A O
drug O
is O
available O
for O
monkeypox O
patients O
who O
have O
or O
who O
are O
at O
risk O
of O
severe O
disease O
, O
but O
doctors O
say O
they O
continue O
to O
face O
challenges O
getting O
access O
to O
it O
. O
The O
US B-LOC
Food B-ORG
and I-ORG
Drug I-ORG
Administration I-ORG
hasn’t O
approved O
tecovirimat O
– O
sold O
under O
the O
brand O
name O
Tpoxx B-ORG
– O
specifically O
for O
use O
against O
monkeypox O
, O
but O
the O
US B-LOC
Centers B-ORG
for I-ORG
Disease I-ORG
Control I-ORG
and I-ORG
Prevention I-ORG
has O
made O
the O
drug O
available O
from O
the O
Strategic B-ORG
National I-ORG
Stockpile I-ORG
through O
expanded O
access O
during O
the O
global O
outbreak O
that O
has O
caused O
about O
5,800 O
probable O
or O
confirmed O
cases O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
. O
Tpoxx B-ORG
was O
FDA-approved O
in O
2018 O
as O
the O
first O
drug O
to O
treat O
smallpox O
, O
a O
virus O
in O
the O
same O
family O
as O
monkeypox O
. O
The O
World B-ORG
Health I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
declared O
smallpox O
eradicated O
in O
1980 O
, O
but O
concerns O
that O
the O
virus O
could O
be O
weaponized O
drove O
the O
US B-LOC
government O
to O
stockpile O
more O
than O
1.7 O
million O
courses O
of O
the O
drug O
in O
case O
of O
a O
bioterrorism O
event O
. O
Tpoxx B-ORG
is O
approved O
in O
the O
European B-LOC
Union I-LOC
to O
treat O
monkeypox O
as O
well O
as O
smallpox O
. O
It O
can O
be O
taken O
intravenously O
or O
more O
commonly O
as O
an O
oral O
pill O
. O
Tpoxx B-ORG
is O
considered O
experimental O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
monkeypox O
treatment O
because O
there’s O
no O
data O
to O
prove O
its O
effectiveness O
against O
the O
disease O
in O
humans O
. O
Its O
safety O
was O
assessed O
in O
healthy O
humans O
before O
its O
FDA B-ORG
approval O
for O
smallpox O
, O
and O
its O
effectiveness O
has O
been O
tested O
in O
animals O
infected O
with O
viruses O
related O
to O
smallpox O
, O
including O
monkeypox O
. O
As O
the O
ongoing O
outbreak O
increases O
demand O
for O
the O
drug O
, O
the O
FDA B-ORG
and O
CDC B-ORG
recently O
eased O
some O
of O
the O
administrative O
requirements O
that O
health O
care O
providers O
face O
when O
requesting O
access O
. O

However O
, O
doctors O
across O
the O
country O
suggest O
that O
significant O
barriers O
remain O
, O
causing O
some O
patients O
to O
wait O
days O
for O
shipments O
or O
travel O
to O
find O
medical O
centers O
that O
can O
provide O
the O
product O
at O
all O
. O
“ O
Patients O
are O
trying O
hard O
to O
get O
this O
medication O
, O
even O
going O
out O
of O
city O
or O
out O
of O
state O
in O
some O
cases O
, O
said O
Dr. O
Peter B-PER
Chin-Hong I-PER
, O
an O
infectious O
disease O
physician O
at O
UCSF B-ORG
Health I-ORG
. O

His O
hospital O
has O
fielded O
calls O
from O
patients O
throughout O
California B-LOC
as O
well O
as O
from O
Colorado B-LOC
and O
even O
Canada B-LOC
and O
the O
UK B-LOC
, O
all O
hoping O
to O
get O
treatment O
. O
Health O
agencies O
cut O
red O
tape O
, O
but O
challenges O
persist O
The O
CDC B-ORG
says O
doctors O
may O
want O
to O
use O
Tpoxx O
for O
people O
who O
have O
monkeypox O
symptoms O
in O
particularly O
hazardous O
areas O
like O
the O
eyes O
, O
mouth O
, O
genitals O
or O
anus O
. O
It O
may O
also O
be O
used O
in O
people O
with O
severe O
symptoms O
like O
sepsis O
or O
brain O
inflammation O
, O
or O
in O
people O
at O
high O
risk O
of O
severe O
illness O
, O
including O
those O
with O
weakened O
immune O
systems O
because O
of O
conditions O
like O
HIV/AIDS O
, O
those O
with O
skin O
conditions O
like O
eczema O
, O
children O
, O
pregnant O
women O
and O
people O
with O
other O
complications O
like O
a O
bacterial O
skin O
infection O
. O

Many O
people O
who O
have O
gotten O
sick O
during O
the O
outbreak O
have O
had O
mild O
symptoms O
and O
have O
recovered O
without O
treatment O
, O
but O
some O
doctors O
say O
they’ve O
seen O
more O
patients O
with O
severe O
disease O
than O
they O
expected O
. O

Dr. O
Mary B-PER
Foote, I-PER
medical O
director O
of O
the O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
City I-LOC
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Health I-ORG
and O
Mental O
Hygiene, O
said O
in O
late O
July O
that O
about O
20% O
to O
25% O
of O
patients O
there O
have O
met O
the O
criteria O
for O
Tpoxx. O
As O
of O
July O
23, O
the O
treatment O
had O
been O
prescribed O
for O
about O
215 O
out O
of O
839 O
confirmed O
cases. O

Anecdotally O
, O
of O
the O
providers O
that O
we’ve O
spoken O
to O
, O
we’ve O
seen O
, O
very O
commonly O
, O
significant O
improvements O
within O
just O
a O
few O
days O
of O
starting O
and O
improvements O
in O
pain O
. O
And O
very O
significantly O
, O
we O
have O
not O
seen O
any O
significant O
adverse O
events O
reported O
and O
very O
few O
even O
mild O
adverse O
events O
. O

Some O
headaches O
, O
nausea O
. O

But O
that’s O
pretty O
much O
it,” O
Foote B-PER
said. O
However, O
it’s O
unclear O
what O
proportion O
of O
the O
more O
than O
5,000 O
probable O
or O
confirmed O
cases O
nationwide O
have O
been O
treated O
with O
Tpoxx. O
CDC B-ORG
officials O
said O
in O
a O
webinar O
that O
more O
than O
223 O
people O
had O
been O
treated O
as O
of O
July O
22, O
but O
the O
agency O
did O
not O
respond O
to O
requests O
for O
a O
more O
specific O
number. O

Experts O
say O
the O
number O
who’ve O
been O
treated O
is O
probably O
a O
fraction O
of O
those O
eligible O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
a O
majority O
of O
patients O
don’t O
have O
access O
,” O
Chin-Hong B-PER
said O
. O
He’s O
seen O
firsthand O
how O
hard O
it O
can O
be O
to O
get O
the O
drug O
. O
Chin-Hong B-PER
treated O
Kevin B-PER
Kwong I-PER
, O
34 O
, O
after O
he O
developed O
painful O
lesions O
all O
over O
his O
hands O
, O
feet O
and O
face O
that O
spread O
to O
his O
back O
, O
thighs O
and O
scalp O
. O
“ O
There O
were O
moments O
I O
could O
barely O
swallow O
food O
because O
of O
the O
sores O
in O
the O
back O
of O
my O
throat O
, O
” O
Kwong B-PER
said O
. O

Lesions O
near O
his O
eye O
threatened O
to O
have O
long-term O
effects O
on O
his O
vision O
. O
But O
after O
his O
symptoms O
began O
, O
it O
took O
about O
five O
days O
for O
Kwong B-PER
to O
get O
to O
a O
facility O
where O
he O
could O
get O
Tpoxx O
. O
He O
spent O
four O
days O
doing O
telehealth O
visits O
and O
going O
to O
urgent O
cares O
and O
emergency O
rooms O
as O
his O
rash O
worsened O
before O
doctors O
finally O
suspected O
monkeypox O
– O
and O
even O
then O
, O
he O
says O
, O
they O
didn’t O
know O
how O
to O
treat O
him O
and O
sent O
him O
home O
. O
But O
his O
symptoms O
only O
got O
worse O
, O
and O
he O
went O
back O
to O
the O
ER O
before O
being O
advised O
to O
go O
to O
the O
UCSF B-ORG
Medical I-ORG
Center I-ORG
because O
it O
was O
treating O
monkeypox O
patients O
. O
Exhausted O
and O
frustrated O
, O
he O
agreed O
out O
of O
desperation O
. O
He O
got O
there O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
night O
; O
several O
hours O
later O
, O
he O
met O
Chin-Hong B-PER
and O
took O
his O
first O
dose O
of O
Tpoxx O
. O
“ O
He O
had O
to O
push O
through O
and O
get O
to O
a O
county O
that O
has O
Tpoxx O
and O
go O
to O
the O
emergency O
room O
in O
the O
hospital O
he O
knew O
might O
offer O
him O
therapy O
because O
the O
place O
where O
he O
comes O
from O
doesn’t O
have O
therapy O
, O
Chin-Hong B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
If O
he O
didn’t O
advocate O
for O
himself O
, O
he O
would O
have O
never O
gotten O
Tpoxx O
.” O
To O
get O
Tpoxx O
, O
a O
patient O
must O
sign O
a O
consent O
form O
from O
the O
CDC B-ORG
, O
and O
doctors O
must O
request O
access O
from O
the O
CDC B-ORG
or O
their O
local O
health O
department O
, O
which O
involves O
submitting O
things O
like O
lab O
tests O
and O
consent O
forms O
. O
The O
CDC B-ORG
and O
the O
FDA B-ORG
recently O
reduced O
the O
amount O
of O
paperwork O
needed O
, O
made O
certain O
tests O
and O
photo O
requirements O
optional O
, O
and O
allowed O
health-care O
workers O
to O
start O
treatment O
before O
paperwork O
is O
submitted O
. O
“ O
They O
have O
made O
it O
easier O
, O
but O
it O
still O
requires O
additional O
time O
, O
efforts O
and O
resources O
to O
be O
able O
to O
prescribe O
it O
, O
” O
Dr. O

Jason B-PER
Zucker I-PER
, O
an O
infectious O
disease O
specialist O
at O
Columbia B-ORG
University I-ORG
Irving I-ORG
Medical I-ORG
Center I-ORG
Chin-Hong B-PER
says O
that O
aside O
from O
the O
paperwork O
, O
there’s O
a O
high O
“activation O
energy” O
that O
clinics O
and O
hospitals O
face O
because O
the O
drug O
is O
considered O
experimental O
for O
monkeypox O
and O
some O
hospitals O
and O
institutions O
require O
additional O
reviews O
for O
such O
treatments O
. O
As O
a O
result O
, O
Tpoxx O
has O
been O
disproportionately O
used O
in O
larger O
academic O
medical O
centers O
that O
have O
better O
infrastructure O
for O
working O
through O
such O
processes O
. O
“We O
have O
this O
interesting O
situation O
– O
and O
it O
was O
like O
that O
in O
Covid O
too O
– O
where O
a O
county O
that O
doesn’t O
have O
Tpoxx O
will O
negotiate O
with O
another O
county O
and O
the O
hospital O
to O
take O
the O
patient O
if O
they O
are O
still O
ill O
and O
would O
need O
Tpoxx O
. O
So O
we O
may O
get O
another O
patient O
like O
that O
from O
another O
county O
in O
the O
East B-LOC
Bay I-LOC
today O
.” O
Chin-Hong B-PER
said O
of O
the O
UCSF B-ORG
Medical I-ORG
Center I-ORG
. O
A O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
man O
named O
Adam B-PER
says O
it O
also O
took O
him O
several O
days O
to O
get O
access O
to O
Tpoxx O
. O
Adam B-PER
had O
a O
fever O
, O
swollen O
lymph O
nodes O
and O
body O
aches O
, O
he O
told O
CNN B-ORG
Chief O
Medical O
Correspondent O
Dr. O

Sanjay B-PER
Gupta I-PER
. O
The O
rashes O
that O
characterize O
monkeypox O
appeared O
around O
his O
groin O
, O
arms O
, O
throat O
and O
face O
. O
“ O
I O
would O
kind O
of O
liken O
it O
to O
a O
crossbreed O
of O
Covid O
, O
strep O
throat O
, O
mono O
, O
kind O
of O
all O
those O
things O
together O
is O
how O
monkeypox O
felt O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
the O
pox O
, O
which O
, O
that O
was O
an O
experience O
for O
sure O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
His O
doctors O
were O
concerned O
that O
one O
lesion O
under O
an O
eyelash O
could O
affect O
his O
vision O
. O

He O
had O
a O
lesion O
on O
the O
inside O
of O
his O
lid O
, O
but O
if O
that O
would O
rupture O
, O
he O
would O
auto-inoculate O
his O
eye O
and O
could O
get O
a O
keratitis O
, O
” O
said O
Dr. O
Stacy B-PER
Lane I-PER
of O
the O
Central B-ORG
Outreach I-ORG
Wellness I-ORG
Center I-ORG
in O
Pittsburgh B-LOC
, O
who O
treated O
Adam B-PER
. O
She O
worried O
that O
it O
could O
put O
him O
at O
risk O
of O
blindness O
. O
“ O
By O
the O
time O
I O
was O
initially O
seen O
and O
talked O
about O
the O
eyeball O
, O
I O
wasn’t O
put O
on O
the O
antiviral O
until O
almost O
a O
week O
later O
, O
” O
Adam B-PER
said O
. O
In O
Adam’s B-PER
case O
, O
his O
doctor’s O
office O
didn’t O
have O
Tpoxx O
on O
hand O
, O
and O
after O
putting O
in O
the O
request O
, O
it O
took O
four O
days O
for O
it O
to O
get O
there O
from O
a O
distribution O
center O
. O
The O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Health I-ORG
said O
in O
an O
email O
that O
it O
typically O
takes O
a O
couple O
days O
after O
a O
doctor O
orders O
Tpoxx O
for O
it O
to O
get O
to O
a O
health-care O
provider O
, O
since O
the O
CDC B-ORG
must O
first O
get O
the O
product O
to O
local O
public O
health O
sites O
. O
“ O
There O
are O
different O
processes O
in O
different O
states O
and O
in O
different O
hospitals O
. O

Every O
region O
or O
every O
area O
will O
have O
its O
own O
problem O
,” O
said O
Dr. O

Aaron B-PER
Glatt I-PER
, O
chief O
of O
infectious O
diseases O
at O
Mount B-LOC
Sinai I-LOC
South I-LOC
Nassau I-LOC
in O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
. O
“ O
If O
you’re O
a O
private O
physician O
or O
your O
clinic O
doesn’t O
have O
access O
to O
Tpoxx O
immediately O
, O
you O
might O
have O
it O
shipped O
from O
the O
national O
stockpile O
, O
and O
you O
have O
to O
have O
a O
full O
process O
– O
you O
know O
, O
guidelines O
, O
shipping O
itself O
takes O
time O
, O
filling O
out O
the O
paperwork O
– O
so O
that O
can O
take O
a O
couple O
of O
days O
. O
“ O
In O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
City I-LOC
, O
you’re O
able O
to O
e-prescribe O
with O
certain O
pharmacies O
that O
would O
be O
able O
to O
make O
sure O
the O
appropriate O
paperwork O
is O
filled O
out O
to O
go O
and O
have O
that O
delivered O
in O
a O
much O
faster O
time O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
How O
clinical O
trials O
could O
help O
Irving B-ORG
Medical I-ORG
Center’s I-ORG
Zucker B-PER
says O
the O
process O
of O
prescribing O
Tpoxx O
involves O
weighing O
the O
risks O
and O
benefits O
for O
each O
person O
. O
Although O
some O
doctors O
have O
reported O
cases O
in O
which O
they O
think O
the O
drug O
may O
have O
been O
beneficial O
, O
the O
CDC B-ORG
says O
that O
evidence O
of O
how O
well O
it O
works O
in O
humans O
has O
been O
limited O
to O
“ O
drug O
levels O
in O
blood O
” O
and O
“ O
a O
few O
case O
studies O
.” O
Tpoxx’s O
safety O
was O
assessed O
through O
a O
study O
of O
359 O
healthy O
people O
before O
it O
got O
FDA B-ORG
approval O
. O
Because O
smallpox O
has O
been O
eradicated O
since O
1980 O
, O
the O
drug’s O
benefits O
were O
evaluated O
through O
trials O
on O
animals O
that O
were O
infected O
with O
related O
viruses O
including O
monkeypox O
virus O
. O
There O
is O
no O
human O
trial O
data O
to O
prove O
that O
it’s O
effective O
in O
treating O
monkeypox O
. O
“ O
Any O
time O
that O
we’re O
using O
a O
new O
medication O
, O
it’s O
important O
that O
we O
do O
randomized O
controlled O
trials O
because O
it’s O
really O
the O
only O
way O
to O
know O
whether O
it O
works O
, O
” O
Zucker B-PER
said O
. O
Randomized O
controlled O
trials O
are O
studies O
that O
evaluate O
how O
well O
a O
drug O
works O
in O
a O
group O
of O
people O
who O
get O
the O
drug O
compared O
with O
a O
group O
of O
people O
who O
don’t O
. O
Zucker B-PER
said O
he’s O
unsure O
whether O
such O
trials O
would O
be O
ethical O
in O
people O
who O
qualify O
for O
Tpoxx O
, O
since O
some O
of O
the O
participants O
would O
get O
a O
useless O
placebo O
instead O
. O
Dr. O
Jay B-PER
Varma I-PER
, O
a O
professor O
of O
population O
health O
sciences O
at O
Weill B-ORG
Cornell I-ORG
Medical I-ORG
College I-ORG
, O
believes O
that O
such O
trials O
are O
ethical O
in O
mild O
cases O
, O
people O
who O
have O
been O
exposed O
or O
are O
at O
risk O
of O
exposure O
, O
and O
children O
and O
pregnant O
women O
. O
“ O
There O
is O
a O
need O
to O
get O
high-quality O
data O
about O
the O
risks O
and O
benefits O
of O
Tpoxx O
, O
” O
Varma B-PER
said O
. O
Zucker B-PER
said O
trials O
would O
not O
only O
help O
generate O
much-needed O
data O
on O
how O
to O
use O
Tpoxx O
, O
they O
would O
help O
expand O
access O
in O
two O
ways O
. O
First O
, O
clinical O
data O
could O
help O
the O
drug O
qualify O
for O
a O
different O
type O
of O
regulatory O
approval O
that O
allows O
broader O
access O
with O
fewer O
hurdles O
. O
Second O
, O
trials O
could O
help O
ease O
access O

for O
people O
who O
don’t O
qualify O
under O
the O
current O
Expanded O
Access O
protocol O
, O
such O
as O
those O
with O
milder O
disease O
. O
“Historically O
, O
antivirals O
are O
better O
earlier O
than O
later O
, O
but O
we O
have O
to O
prove O
it O
, O
Zucker B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
that O
there O
are O
plans O
underway O
for O
a O
US B-LOC
monkeypox O
trial O
for O
Tpoxx O
. O
Varma B-PER
compared O
the O
challenges O
of O
limited O
access O
and O
clinical O
data O
to O
the O
early O
days O
of O
the O
Covid-19 O
pandemic O
. O

The O
unfortunate O
parallel O
is O
that O
the O
US B-LOC
is O
behind O
the O
UK B-LOC
and O
Europe B-LOC
in O
running O
these O
trials O
,” O
he O
said O
. O
Lane B-PER
said O
she’s O
hopeful O
that O
the O
CDC B-ORG
and O
public O
health O
departments O
will O
continue O
to O
work O
toward O
better O
access O
to O
the O
medication O
. O

But O
her O
expectations O
are O
measured O
. O
“ O
Until O
the O
FDA B-ORG
approves O
this O
for O
monkeypox O
or O
the O
National B-ORG
Stockpile I-ORG
releases O
the O
stockpile O
for O
more O
normal O
distribution O
, O
this O
is O
where O
we’re O
at O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O

Wyoming B-LOC
Rep. O
Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
said O
if O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
does O
not O
prosecute O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
for O
his O
role O
in O
the O
insurrection O
at O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
and O
“the O
facts O
and O
the O
evidence O
are O
there,” O
the O
decision O
could O
call O
into O
question O
whether O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
can O
“call O
ourselves O
a O
nation O
of O
laws.” O
In O
an O
interview O
with O
CNN’s B-ORG
Kasie B-PER
Hunt, I-PER
Cheney B-PER
– O
the O
GOP B-ORG
vice O
chair O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
investigating O
the O
events O
surrounding O
the O
January O
6, O
2021, O
insurrection O
– O
said O
Trump B-PER
is O
“guilty O
of O
the O
most O
serious O
dereliction O
of O
duty O
of O
any O
president O
in O
our O
nation’s O
history” O
and O
pointed O
to O
a O
judge O
who’s O
said O
he O
likely O
committed O
crimes. O
She O
said O
the O
House B-ORG
committee O
is O
“going O
to O
continue O
to O
follow O
the O
facts. O

I O
think O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Justice I-ORG
will O
do O
that O

But O
they O
have O
to O
make O
decisions O
about O
prosecution O
.” O
Understanding O
what O
it O
means O
if O
the O
facts O
and O
the O
evidence O
are O
there O
, O
and O
they O
decide O
not O
to O
prosecute O
– O
how O
do O
we O
then O
call O
ourselves O
a O
nation O
of O
laws O
? O
I O
think O
that’s O
a O
very O
serious O
, O
serious O
balancing O
, O
Cheney B-PER
said O
. O

The O
question O
for O
us O
is O
, O
are O
we O
a O
nation O
of O
laws O
? O
Are O
we O
a O
country O
where O
no O
one O
is O
above O
the O
law O
? O
And O
what O
do O
the O
facts O
and O
the O
evidence O
show O
? O
Cheney B-PER
said O
. O
She O
sidestepped O
questions O
about O
whether O
Trump B-PER
being O
prosecuted O
by O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
would O
only O
add O
to O
his O
strength O
with O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
’s O
base O
ahead O
of O
the O
2024 O
presidential O
bid O
that O
Trump B-PER
has O
repeatedly O
teased O
. O
“ O
I O
don’t O
think O
that O
it O
’s O
appropriate O
to O
think O
about O
it O
that O
way O
,” O
said O
Cheney B-PER
, O
who O
’s O
facing O
a O
Trump B-PER
- O
backed O
challenger O
in O
a O
primary O
later O
this O
month O
. O
She O
alluded O
to O
Judge O
David B-PER
Carter I-PER
, O
a O
federal O
judge O
in O
California B-LOC
who O
ordered O
right O
- O
wing O
attorney O
John B-PER
Eastman I-PER
to O
turn O
over O
101 O
emails O
from O
around O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
writing O
in O
March O
that O
he O
“ O
finds O
it O
more O
likely O
than O
not O
that O
President O
Trump B-PER
corruptly O
attempted O
to O
obstruct O
the O
Joint O
Session O
of O
Congress B-ORG
on O
January O
6 O
2021 O
.” O
“ O
I O
think O
he O
’s O
guilty O
of O
the O
most O
serious O
dereliction O
of O
duty O
of O
any O
president O
in O
our O
nation O
’s O
history O
, O
Cheney B-PER
said O
of O
Trump B-PER
. O
“ O
You O
’ve O
had O
a O
federal O
judge O
in O
California B-LOC
say O
that O
it O
’s O
more O
likely O
than O
not O
that O
he O
and O
John B-PER
Eastman I-PER
committed O
two O
crimes O
.” O
Cheney B-PER
’s O
comments O
come O
as O
the O
House B-ORG
panel O
prepares O
for O
a O
busy O
August O
. O
A O
committee O
spokesperson O
also O
said O
last O
week O
that O
the O
committee O
intended O
to O
share O
20 O
transcripts O
with O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
, O
a O
move O
that O
comes O
as O
the O
department O
’s O
criminal O
investigation O
into O
January O
6 O
is O
heating O
up O
. O
The O
House B-ORG
committee O
is O
preparing O
to O
release O
its O
final O
report O
ahead O
of O
November O
’s O
midterm O
elections O
. O
Cheney B-PER
faces O
a O
series O
of O
Trump B-PER
- O
aligned O
challengers O
in O
her O
August O
16 O
primary O
, O
including O
the O
Trump B-PER
- O
endorsed O
Harriet B-PER
Hageman I-PER
, O
a O
former O
Wyoming B-LOC
national O
Republican B-ORG
committeewoman O
who O
has O
advanced O
conspiracy O
theories O
about O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O
Cheney B-PER
is O
the O
daughter O
of O
former O
Vice O
President O
Dick B-PER
Cheney I-PER
. O
Her O
reelection O
campaign O
unveiled O
an O
ad O
on O
Thursday O
in O
which O
the O
former O
vice O
president O
lays O
into O
Trump B-PER
over O
his O
lies O
about O
widespread O
fraud O
in O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O

He O
tried O
to O
steal O
the O
last O
election O
using O
lies O
and O
violence O
to O
keep O
himself O
in O
power O
after O
the O
voters O
had O
rejected O
him O
, O
the O
former O
vice O
president O
says O
in O
the O
spot O
. O
“ O
He O
is O
a O
coward O
.” O

A O
real O
man O
wouldn’t O
lie O
to O
his O
supporters O
. O

He O
lost O
his O
election O
and O
he O
lost O
big O
. O
I O
know O
it O
, O
he O
knows O
it O
and O
, O
deep O
down O
, O
I O
think O
most O
Republicans O
know O
it O
,” O
Dick B-PER
Cheney I-PER
adds O
. O
Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
wouldn’t O
say O
whether O
her O
father O
has O
urged O
her O
to O
run O
for O
president O
in O
2024 O
. O
“ O
Look O
, O
Dick B-PER
Cheney I-PER
is O
a O
big O
Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
supporter O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O
She O
said O
the O
former O
vice O
president O
shares O
“ O
this O
real O
sadness O
, O
frankly O
, O
about O
what’s O
happening O
to O
our O
party O
, O
and O
a O
real O
despair O
about O
how O
it O
could O
be O
that O
so O
many O
Republicans O
would O
refuse O
to O
stand O
up O
and O
tell O
the O
truth O
. O
“ O
And O
it O
is O
a O
scary O
moment O
for O
the O
nation O
, O
” O
she O
added O
. O
Cheney B-PER
says O
more O
to O
come O
from O
the O
committee O
this O
fall O
 O
Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
, O
who O
has O
courted O
Democratic O
voters O
in O
Wyoming’s B-LOC
primary O
, O
said O
she O
doesn’t O
see O
the O
House B-ORG
committee’s O
work O
through O
the O
lens O
of O
political O
outcomes O
. O
Cheney B-PER
said O
the O
House B-ORG
panel O
will O
continue O
to O
lay O
out O
evidence O
in O
the O
coming O
months O
and O
that O
she O
expects O
the O
committee O
to O
“ O
have O
an O
opinion O
” O
about O
making O
criminal O
referrals O
to O
the B-ORG
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
. O
“ O
There’s O
much O
more O
that O
we O
have O
not O
yet O
shared O
in O
hearings O
and O
that O
we O
anticipate O
we O
will O
share O
in O
the O
fall O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O
“ O
And O
we O
will O
also O
make O
decisions O
about O
criminal O
referrals O
. O

And O
ultimately O
, O
the O
decision O
about O
prosecution’s O
up O
to O
the B-ORG
Justice I-ORG
Department I-ORG
. O
But O
I O
would O
anticipate O
that O
the O
committee O
will O
have O
an O
opinion O
on O
it O
.” O
Cheney B-PER
said O
that O
during O
the O
committee’s O
probe O
, O
she O
has O
learned O
that B-PER
Trump’s I-PER
effort O
to O
block O
the O
2020 O
election O
results O
were O
“ O
a O
more O
sophisticated O
and O
broader-reaching O
effort O
than O
I O
understood O
coming O
into O
it O
.” O
“ O
I O
think O
all O
of O
us O
on O
the O
committee O
have O
had O
that O
same O
reaction O
, O
which O
is O
that O
there’s O
so O
much O
, O
there O
was O
so O
much O
more O
that O
was O
happening O
in O
multiple O
different O
areas O
, O
whether O
it O
was O
the O
pressure O
on O
state O
officials O
or O
the O
pressure O
on O
the B-ORG
Justice I-ORG
Department I-ORG
” O
or O
efforts O
to O
push O
former O
Vice O
President O
Mike B-PER
Pence I-PER
to O
reject O
some O
states’ O
electoral O
votes O
. O
“ O
The O
volume O
of O
information O
has O
been O
more O
than O
I O
expected O
, O
she O
said O
. O

Cheney B-PER
praised O
Pence B-PER
for O
rejecting O
the O
pressure O
from O
Trump B-PER
. O
She O
said O
Pence B-PER
, O
who O
, O
as O
vice O
president O
oversaw O
the O
session O
of O
Congress B-ORG
in O
which O
electoral O
votes O
were O
officially O
counted O
, O
“ O
was O
a O
hero O
on O
January O
6 O
.” O
“ O
It’s O
very O
clear O
that O
there O
was O
tremendous O
pressure O
from O
a O
number O
of O
different O
places O
on O
him O
. O
And O
he O
did O
his O
duty O
and O
he O
didn’t O
succumb O
to O
that O
pressure O
and O
if O
he O
had O
succumbed O
to O
that O
pressure O
, O
things O
would O
have O
been O
very O
different O
, O
she O
said O
. O
“ O
And O
so O
I O
think O
that O
that O
we O
owe O
him O
gratitude O
for O
how O
he O
conducted O
himself O
and O
for O
his O
refusal O
to O
do O
what O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
wanted O
him O
to O
do O
, O
which O
would O
have O
been O
illegal O
.” O
Cheney B-PER
faces O
voters O
on O
August O
16 O
Cheney B-PER
said O
she O
expects O
to O
win O
her O
primary O
in O
less O
than O
two O
weeks O
, O
despite O
her O
opponents O
attacking O
her O
role O
on O
the O
committee O
. O
“ O
I O
don’t O
expect O
to O
lose O
.” O

I’m O
working O
hard O
to O
earn O
every O
single O
vote O
and O
, O
ultimately O
, O
I O
really O
believe O
that O
the O
people O
of O
Wyoming B-LOC
fundamentally O
understand O
how O
important O
fidelity O
to O
the O
Constitution O
is O
; O
understand O
how O
important O
it O
is O
that O
we O
fight O
for O
those O
fundamental O
principles O
on O
which O
everything O
else O
is O
based O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O
However O
, O
the O
congresswoman O
also O
made O
clear O
that O
she O
is O
not O
tempering O
her O
criticism O
of O
Trump B-PER
at O
all O
– O
even O
if O
it O
costs O
her O
the O
House O
seat O
that O
her O
father O
held O
and O
that O
she O
has O
held O
since O
2017 O
. O
“ O
We’re O
in O
a O
situation O
where O
former O
President O
Trump B-PER
has O
betrayed O
the O
patriotism O
of O
millions O
and O
millions O
of O
people O
across O
our O
country O
, O
and O
many O
people O
here O
in O
Wyoming B-LOC
, O
and O
he’s O
lied O
to O
them O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O
“ O
And O
what O
I O
know O
to O
do O
is O
to O
tell O
the O
truth O
, O
and O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
people O
understand O
the O
truth O
about O
what O
happened O
and O
why O
it O
matters O
so O
much O
. O
” O
Asked O
why O
she O
thinks O
voters O
believe O
Trump B-PER
, O
Cheney B-PER
added O
: O
“ O
It’s O
just O
consistent O
lying O
about O
what O
happened O
about O
the O
election O
, O
playing O
on O
people’s O
patriotism O
. O
And O
he’s O
so O
dangerous O
that O
, O
you O
, O
know O
, O
my O
view O
is O
that O
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
day O
, O
if O
defending O
the O
Constitution O
against O
the O
threat O
that O
he O
poses O
means O
losing O
a O
House O
seat O
, O
then O
that’s O
a O
sacrifice O
that O
I’m O
willing O
to O
make O
. O

I O
don’t O
intend O
to O
lose O

But O
some O
things O
are O
more O
important O
than O
any O
individual O
office O
or O
political O
campaign O
.” O
Cheney B-PER
would O
not O
discuss O
her O
political O
plans O
after O
this O
month’s O
primary O
. O
But O
she O
said O
she O
will O
do O
“ O
whatever O
is O
necessary O
” O
to O
keep O
Trump B-PER
from O
becoming O
the O
GOP B-ORG
presidential O
nominee O
for O
a O
third O
consecutive O
election O
in O
2024 O
. O
She O
said O
she O
intends O
to O
be O
“ O
a O
big O
part O
of O
making O
sure O
that O
we O
protect O
the O
nation O
” O
from O
Trump B-PER
, O
whether O
she O
wins O
reelection O
or O
not O
. O
Cheney B-PER
also O
urged O
members O
of O
both O
parties O
to O
band O
against O
GOP B-ORG
candidates O
who O
have O
advanced O
Trump’s B-PER
lies O
about O
election O
fraud O
and O
are O
seeking O
to O
take O
over O
the O
election O
machinery O
of O
key O
states O
this O
fall O
. O
Republicans B-ORG
in O
recent O
months O
have O
nominated O
candidates O
who O
have O
embraced O
Trump’s B-PER
lies O
about O
election O
fraud O
for O
offices O
that O
control O
the O
election O
machinery O
in O
a O
series O
of O
states O
, O
including O
some O
of O
the O
nation’s O
most O
competitive O
presidential O
battlegrounds O
: O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
Nevada B-LOC
and O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
. O
The O
party O
has O
also O
endorsed O
an O
election O
denier O
for O
the O
top O
elections O
post O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
. O

I O
don’t O
think O
anybody O
should O
vote O
for O
any O
election O
denier O
, O
Cheney B-PER
said O
. O
She O
cast O
defeating O
those O
candidates O
as O
critical O
to O
stopping O
Trump B-PER
from O
circumventing O
the O
will O
of O
American B-LOC
voters O
if O
he O
is O
nominated O
for O
president O
in O
2024 O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
we O
have O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
we O
come O
together O
and O
form O
alliances O
across O
party O
lines O
, O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
the O
people O
that O
we O
are O
electing O
are O
not O
going O
to O
unravel O
the O
republic O
, O
she O
said O
. O
Cheney B-PER
lambasted O
Democrats B-ORG
for O
meddling O
in O
GOP B-ORG
primaries O
to O
boost O
election O
deniers O
that O
they O
think O
will O
be O
less O
viable O
general O
election O
candidates O
, O
as O
was O
the O
case O
in O
the O
primary O
defeat O
this O
week O
of O
Republican B-ORG
Rep. O
Peter B-PER
Meijer I-PER
of O
Michigan B-LOC
, O
one O
of O
the O
10 O
Republicans B-ORG
in O
the O
House B-ORG
who O
voted O
to O
impeach O
Trump B-PER
following O
the O
insurrection O
. O
The O
Democratic B-ORG
Congressional I-ORG
Campaign I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
pumped O
more O
than O
$300,000 O
into O
television O
ads O
to O
boost O
Trump-endorsed O
John B-PER
Gibbs I-PER
against O
him O
. O
Cheney B-PER
said O
Democrats’ O
involvement O
in O
the O
race O
was O
“ O
terrible O
.” O
“ O
All O
of O
us O
, O
again O
, O
across O
party O
lines O
, O
have O
got O
to O
make O
sure O
that O
we O
are O
supporting O
people O
who O
believe O
fundamentally O
in O
our O
democratic O
system O
, O
she O
said O
. O
“ O
And O
so O
I O
think O
that O
it’s O
inexplicable O
and O
wrong O
for O
the O
Democrats B-ORG
to O
be O
funding O
election O
deniers O
, O
particularly O
against O
one O
of O
the O
10 O
Republicans B-ORG
who O
so O
bravely O
stood O
up O
and O
did O
the O
right O
thing O
. O
CLARIFICATION O
: O
This O
headline O
and O
story O
have O
been O
updated O
to O
clarify O
the O
conditions O
that O
Cheney B-PER
thinks O
would O
call O
into O
question O
the O
US B-LOC
as O
a O
“ O
nation O
of O
laws O
” O
and O
to O
include O
additional O
information O
from O
the O
interview O
. O

Republicans O
will O
officially O
head O
to O
Milwaukee B-LOC
to O
select O
their O
next O
presidential O
nominee O
, O
Republican B-ORG
National I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
chairwoman O
Ronna B-PER
McDaniel I-PER
announced O
Friday O
, O
describing O
the O
host O
of O
the O
party’s O
2024 O
convention O
as O
“ O
a O
great O
city O
.” O
The O
convention O
site O
was O
unanimously O
approved O
by O
RNC B-ORG
members O
during O
a O
closed-door O
vote O
Friday O
morning O
at O
the O
party’s O
annual O
summer O
meeting O
here O
. O
McDaniel B-PER
was O
joined O
by O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
chief O
of O
staff O
and O
onetime O
RNC B-ORG
chairman O
Reince B-PER
Priebus I-PER
, O
along O
with O
members O
of O
the O
party’s O
Wisconsin B-LOC
delegation O
for O
the O
announcement O
. O

In O
the O
next O
two O
years O
, O
we O
look O
forward O
to O
working O
with O
the O
mayor O
and O
everyone O
in O
the O
community O
to O
make O
this O
an O
event O
that O
highlights O
not O
just O
our O
nominee O
… O
but O
the O
great O
city O
that O
Milwaukee B-LOC
is O
, O
McDaniel B-PER
said O
. O
Milwaukee B-LOC
Mayor O
Cavalier B-PER
Johnson I-PER
, O
a O
Democrat O
, O
defended O
the O
decision O
to O
host O
the O
convention O
in O
his O
city O
, O
telling O
CNN B-ORG
the O
move O
“ O
does O
not O
mean O
” O
Milwaukee B-LOC
is O
“ O
signing O
up O
for O
the O
platform O
of O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
.” O
“ O
My O
stance O
, O
and O
I O
think O
that O
most O
Democrats O
understand O
this O
, O
is O
that O
this O
is O
not O
a O
political O
decision O
, O
it O
is O
a O
business O
decision O
, O
” O
Johnson B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
It O
will O
present O
an O
opportunity O
for O
us O
to O
have O
millions O
of O
dollars O
of O
economic O
impact O
… O
for O
us O
to O
fill O
our O
restaurants O
, O
our O
bars O
, O
our O
hotels O
, O
and O
to O
support O
our O
hospitality O
industry O
that’s O
been O
battered O
by O
Covid O
, O
of O
course O
, O
over O
the O
last O
couple O
of O
years O
. O
Johnson B-PER
joined O
McDaniel B-PER
Friday O
to O
officially O
unveil O
Milwaukee B-LOC
as O
the O
convention O
site O
choice O
, O
just O
days O
after O
Nashville B-LOC
fell O
out O
of O
contention O
as O
a O
potential O
alternative O
. O
Milwaukee B-LOC
began O
its O
bid O
to O
be O
a O
convention O
host O
nearly O
a O
year O
ago O
, O
and O
city O
representatives O
met O
with O
RNC B-ORG
officials O
in O
February O
as O
they O
toured O
finalist O
cities O
, O
which O
included O
Salt B-LOC
Lake I-LOC
City I-LOC
and O
Pittsburgh B-LOC
at O
the O
time O
. O

Both O
cities O
were O
later O
removed O
from O
the O
running O
. O
Later O
Friday O
, O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
is O
scheduled O
to O
host O
a O
rally O
in O
the O
Milwaukee B-LOC
suburb O
of O
Waukesha B-LOC
to O
campaign O
for O
Tim B-PER
Michels I-PER
, O
the O
GOP B-ORG
candidate O
for O
governor O
, O
ahead O
of O
the O
state’s O
primary O
next O
week O
. O
Trump’s O
sustained O
popularity O
with O
the O
GOP B-ORG
base O
would O
likely O
position O
him O
as O
a O
front-runner O
in O
a O
crowded O
2024 O
GOP B-ORG
primary O
should O
he O
launch O
another O
presidential O
campaign O
, O
as O
is O
widely O
expected O
. O
Johnson B-PER
, O
who O
said O
he O
will O
actively O
campaign O
for O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
reelection O
in O
2024 O
, O
dismissed O
security O
concerns O
about O
protests O
around O
the O
convention O
in O
Milwaukee B-LOC
, O
including O
if O
Trump B-PER
– O
one O
of O
the O
most O
polarizing O
figures O
in O
American B-LOC
politics O
– O
is O
the O
Republican B-ORG
nominee O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
that O
any O
time O
you O
host O
a O
large-scale O
event O
, O
there O
is O
potential O
for O
that O
sort O
of O
activity O
. O
Our O
police O
department O
is O
well-versed O
, O
and O
I O
think O
they O
are O
prepared O
for O
the O
convention O
, O
” O
Johnson B-PER
said O
, O
noting O
that O
Milwaukee B-LOC
was O
originally O
supposed O
to O
host O
the O
2020 O
Democratic B-ORG
National I-ORG
Convention I-ORG
before O
it O
switched O
to O
a O
virtual O
format O
amid O
the O
coronavirus O
pandemic O
. O
“ O
The O
police O
in O
Milwaukee B-LOC
are O
already O
well O
prepared O
for O
this O
and O
will O
really O
be O
in O
a O
prime O
position O
to O
execute O
what O
we O
were O
about O
to O
execute O
the O
last O
go-round O
, O
” O
Johnson B-PER
said O
. O

This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
reporting O
on O
the O
selection O

Lawrence B-PER
and O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
shared O
a O
passion O
for O
big O
game O
hunting O
. O
In O
late O
September O
2016 O
, O
the O
couple O
traveled O
from O
their O
Phoenix B-LOC
home O
to O
the O
southern O
African B-LOC
nation O
of O
Zambia B-LOC
, O
where O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
was O
determined O
to O
add O
a O
leopard O
to O
her O
collection O
of O
animal O
trophies O
. O
They O
carried O
two O
guns O
for O
the O
hunt O
: O
a O
Remington B-ORG
.375 O
rifle O
and O
a O
Browning B-ORG
12-gauge O
shotgun O
. O
After O
killing O
other O
animals O
during O
the O
two-week O
trip O
– O
but O
not O
a O
leopard O
– O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
never O
made O
it O
home O
. O
She O
suffered O
a O
fatal O
shotgun O
blast O
in O
their O
hunting O
cabin O
at O
dawn O
as O
she O
was O
packing O
to O
return O
to O
Phoenix B-LOC
, O
federal O
prosecutors O
allege O
in O
court O
documents O
. O
Now O
Lawrence B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
, O
67 O
, O
is O
charged O
with O
foreign O
murder O
and O
mail O
fraud O
in O
the O
death O
of O
his O
wife O
of O
30 O
years O
. O
He O
has O
pleaded O
not O
guilty O
, O
and O
took O
the O
stand O
in O
his O
own O
defense O
this O
week O
at O
his O
trial O
in O
Denver B-LOC
, O
CNN B-ORG
affiliate O
KMGH B-ORG
reported O
. O

I O
did O
not O
kill O
my O
wife O

I O
could O
not O
murder O
my O
wife O

I O
would O
not O
murder O
my O
wife O
,” O
he O
told O
jurors O
. O
Rudolph B-PER
told O
investigators O
he O
heard O
the O
shot O
while O
he O
was O
in O
the O
bathroom O
and O
believed O
the O
shotgun O
accidentally O
went O
off O
as O
she O
was O
putting O
it O
in O
its O
case O
, O
court O
documents O
say O
. O
He O
found O
her O
bleeding O
on O
the O
floor O
of O
their O
cabin O
at O
Kafue B-LOC
National I-LOC
Park I-LOC
, O
he O
says O
. O
But O
federal O
prosecutors O
allege O
Rudolph B-PER
killed O
his O
wife O
for O
insurance O
money O
and O
to O
be O
with O
his O
girlfriend O
. O
CNN B-ORG
has O
reached O
out O
to O
Rudolph’s B-PER
attorney O
, O
David B-PER
Markus I-PER
, O
but O
has O
not O
heard O
back O
. O

In O
a O
motion O
Markus B-PER
filed O
in O
January O
listing O
his O
client’s O
assets O
, O
he O
said O
Rudolph B-PER
had O
no O
financial O
motive O
to O
kill O
his O
wife O
. O
In O
the O
court O
document O
, O
he O
noted O
that O
Rudolph B-PER
is O
worth O
millions O
, O
including O
a O
dental O
practice O
near O
Pittsburgh B-LOC
valued O
at O
$10 O
million O
. O
Life O
insurance O
companies O
based O
in O
Colorado B-LOC
paid O
Rudolph B-PER
over O
$4.8 O
million O
after O
his O
wife’s O
death O
, O
according O
to O
court O
documents O
. O
The O
rush O
to O
cremate O
his O
wife O
sparked O
suspicion O
, O
investigators O
say O
In O
court O
documents O
, O
investigators O
allege O
Rudolph B-PER
quickly O
sought O
to O
cremate O
his O
wife’s O
body O
in O
Zambia B-LOC
after O
the O
shooting O
. O

Rudolph B-PER
scheduled O
a O
cremation O
three O
days O
after O
her O
death O
, O
according O
to O
court O
documents O
. O
After O
he O
reported O
her O
death O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Embassy I-ORG
in O
the O
Zambian B-LOC
capital O
of O
Lusaka B-LOC
, O
the O
consular O
chief O
“told O
the O
FBI B-ORG
he O
had O
a O
bad O
feeling O
about O
the O
situation O
, O
which O
he O
thought O
was O
moving O
too O
quickly O
, O
” O
FBI B-ORG
special O
agent O
Donald B-PER
Peterson I-PER
wrote O
in O
the O
criminal O
affidavit O
. O
As O
a O
result O
, O
the O
consular O
chief O
and O
two O
other O
embassy O
officials O
went O
to O
the O
funeral O
home O
where O
the O
body O
was O
being O
held O
to O
take O
photographs O
and O
preserve O
any O
potential O
evidence O
. O
When O
Rudolph B-PER
found O
out O
the O
embassy O
officials O
had O
taken O
photos O
of O
his O
wife’s O
body O
, O
he O
was O
“livid O
, O
” O
Peterson B-PER
wrote O
. O
Rudolph B-PER
initially O
told O
the O
consular O
chief O
that O
his O
wife O
may O
have O
died O
by O
suicide O
, O
but O
an O
investigation O
by O
Zambian B-LOC
law O
enforcement O
ruled O
it O
an O
accidental O
discharge O
, O
Peterson B-PER
wrote O
. O
Zambian B-LOC
investigators O
concluded O
that O
the O
firearm O
was O
loaded O
from O
the O
previous O
hunting O
activities O
and O
normal O
safety O
precautions O
were O
not O
taken O
, O
causing O
it O
to O
accidentally O
fire O
in O
the O
fatal O
incident O
, O
according O
to O
court O
documents O
. O
Investigators O
for O
the O
insurers O
reached O
a O
similar O
conclusion O
and O
paid O
on O
the O
policies O
. O

Zambian B-LOC
authorities O
and O
five O
insurers O
determined O
that O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
died O
accidentally O
. O
Witnesses O
told O
the O
FBI B-ORG
that O
Dr. O

Rudolph B-PER
did O
nothing O
to O
interfere O
in O
the O
investigation O
. O
No O
physical O
evidence O
supports O
the O
government’s O
murder O
theory O
, O
Markus B-PER
wrote O
in O
the O
January O
motion O
. O
The O
suspect O
wanted O
to O
be O
with O
his O
girlfriend O
, O
prosecutors O
allege O
But O
federal O
investigators O
say O
there’s O
more O
to O
the O
story O
. O
Rudolph B-PER
orchestrated O
his O
wife’s O
death O
as O
part O
of O
a O
scheme O
to O
defraud O
life O
insurance O
companies O
and O
to O
allow O
him O
to O
live O
openly O
with O
his O
girlfriend O
, O
the O
FBI B-ORG
alleges O
. O
Federal O
authorities O
got O
involved O
after O
a O
friend O
of O
the O
victim O
reached O
out O
to O
the O
FBI B-ORG
and O
asked O
the O
agency O
to O
investigate O
the O
death O
because O
she O
suspected O
foul O
play O
. O

The O
friend O
said O
Rudolph B-PER
had O
been O
involved O
in O
extramarital O
affairs O
in O
the O
past O
and O
had O
a O
girlfriend O
at O
the O
time O
of O
his O
wife’s O
death O
. O
Rudolph’s B-PER
then-girlfriend O
, O
who O
was O
not O
named O
in O
the O
court O
documents O
, O
worked O
as O
a O
manager O
at O
his O
dental O
practice O
near O
Pittsburgh B-LOC
, O
and O
told O
a O
former O
employee O
that O
she’d O
been O
dating O
him O
for O
15 O
to O
20 O
years O
, O
Peterson B-PER
wrote O
. O
The O
former O
employee O
told O
the O
FBI B-ORG
that O
the O
girlfriend O
told O
her O
she O
gave O
Rudolph B-PER
an O
ultimatum O
of O
one O
year O
to O
sell O
his O
dental O
offices O
and O
leave O
his O
wife O
, O
court O
documents O
allege O
. O
Three O
months O
after O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph’s I-PER
death O
, O
the O
girlfriend O
moved O
in O
with O
him O
, O
Peterson B-PER
wrote O
in O
court O
documents O
. O

An O
executive O
director O
of O
their O
subdivision’s O
community O
association O
told O
investigators O
that O
Rudolph B-PER
and O
his O
girlfriend O
tried O
to O
buy O
another O
home O
in O
the O
same O
subdivision O
for O
$3.5 O
million O
. O
Her O
wounds O
didn’t O
reflect O
an O
accidental O
discharge O
, O
FBI B-ORG
says O
Court O
documents O
also O
allege O
that O
evidence O
shows O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph’s I-PER
wounds O
came O
from O
a O
shot O
fired O
from O
at O
least O
two O
feet O
away O
. O
“An O
FBI B-ORG
special O
agent O
conducted O
testing O
to O
determine O
, O
by O
comparison O
to O
photographs O
from O
the O
scene O
of O
the O
death O
, O
the O
approximate O
position O
of O
the O
shotgun O
muzzle O
within O
the O
soft O
case O
at O
the O
time O
of O
discharge O
, O
as O
well O
as O
the O
resulting O
shot O
patterns O
created O
by O
firing O
the O
shotgun O
with O
the O
case O
over O
the O
barrel O
at O
various O
distances O
, O
the O
criminal O
complaint O
states O
. O
A O
forensic O
medical O
examiner O
determined O
the O
patterns O
matching O
the O
wound O
observed O
in O
photographs O
of O
the O
body O
were O
created O
by O
a O
shot O
from O
a O
distance O
of O
between O
two O
and O
three-and-a-half O
feet O
. O
“At O
that O
distance O
, O
there O
is O
reason O
to O
believe O
that O
Bianca B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
was O
not O
killed O
by O
an O
accidental O
discharge O
as O
stated O
, O
the O
complaint O
states O
. O
Bianca B-PER
and O
Lawrence B-PER
Rudolph I-PER
moved O
from O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
to O
Arizona B-LOC
about O
four O
years O
before O
her O
death O
. O
Rudolph’s B-PER
dental O
practice O
remained O
in O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
, O
and O
he O
commuted O
back O
and O
forth O
from O
his O
Phoenix B-LOC
home O
. O
Federal O
authorities O
allege O
his O
wife’s O
murder O
was O
premeditated O
so O
“he O
could O
falsely O
claim O
the O
death O
was O
the O
result O
of O
an O
accident O
.” O
But O
Markus B-PER
has O
accused O
federal O
officials O
of O
relying O
on O
“shaky O
evidence O
.” O
Rudolph’s B-PER
two O
children O
are O
confident O
their O
father O
did O
not O
kill O
their O
mother O
, O
Markus B-PER
said O
, O
and O
they’ve O
signed O
affidavits O
in O
his O
support O
. O
If O
convicted O
of O
murder O
, O
Rudolph B-PER
faces O
a O
maximum O
of O
life O
in O
prison O
or O
the O
death O
penalty O
. O

The O
Atlanta B-LOC
music O
festival O
Music B-ORG
Midtown I-ORG
, O
which O
draws O
tens O
of O
thousands O
of O
concertgoers O
and O
blockbuster O
musicians O
each O
year O
, O
“ O
will O
no O
longer O
be O
taking O
place O
this O
year O
, O
organizers O
announced O
in O
a O
tweet O
Monday O
. O
Though O
the O
organizers O
did O
not O
cite O
a O
reason O
for O
calling O
off O
the O
festival O
, O
various O
media O
reports O
citing O
industry O
and O
festival O
sources O
said O
the O
cancellation O
was O
due O
to O
a O
recent O
interpretation O
of O
Georgia’s B-LOC
gun O
law O
, O
which O
permits O
firearms O
in O
public O
spaces O
, O
including O
parks O
. O
Weapons O
and O
explosives O
of O
any O
kind O
are O
prohibited O
at O
the O
festival O
, O
according O
to O
its O
website O
. O
Gun O
rights O
advocates O
had O
mounted O
a O
pressure O
campaign O
against O
that O
position O
, O
calling O
into O
question O
the O
festival’s O
ability O
to O
restrict O
firearms O
since O
Georgia B-LOC
allows O
guns O
to O
be O
carried O
in O
parks O
. O
Sources O
with O
knowledge O
of O
the O
cancellation O
decision O
by O
operator O
Live B-ORG
Nation I-ORG
who O
spoke O
to O
Rolling B-ORG
Stone I-ORG
cited O
Georgia B-LOC
gun O
laws O
as O
the O
reason O
. O
Georgia B-LOC
gun O
advocate O
Phil B-PER
Evans I-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
he O
emailed O
festival O
organizers O
in O
May O
, O
apprising O
them O
of O
Georgia B-LOC
gun O
laws O
and O
a O
Georgia B-LOC
Supreme O
Court O
case O
dealing O
with O
guns O
in O
which O
he O
was O
a O
party O
. O
Evans B-PER
said O
he O
also O
asked O
the O
City B-LOC
of I-LOC
Atlanta I-LOC
to O
deny O
a O
permit O
to O
Live B-ORG
Nation I-ORG
for O
Music B-ORG
Midtown I-ORG
, O
given O
the O
festival’s O
ban O
on O
firearms O
. O
In O
the O
email O
dated O
May O
13 O
, O
Evans B-PER
asked O
the O
city O
to O
deny O
the O
permit O
for O
“ O
as O
they O
have O
publicly O
stated O
an O
intent O
to O
violate O
settled O
state O
law O
.” O
“ O
The O
City B-LOC
of I-LOC
Atlanta I-LOC
should O
respect O
state O
law O
and O
uphold O
it O
when O
dealing O
with O
entities O
that O
make O
use O
of O
tax-payer O
owned O
properties O
that O
wish O
to O
make O
money O
from O
such O
usage O
, O
or O
even O
otherwise O
, O
the O
email O
said O
. O
The O
event O
slated O
for O
September O
17 O
and O
18 O
in O
Piedmont B-LOC
Park I-LOC
was O
canceled O
“ O
due O
to O
circumstances O
beyond O
our O
control O
, O
” O
said O
the O
organizer’s O
tweet O
. O

The O
music O
festival O
was O
set O
to O
feature O
a O
“diverse O
lineup O
of O
over O
30 O
artists O
across O
4 O
stages,” O
including O
My B-ORG
Chemical I-ORG
Romance, I-ORG
Future, O
Jack B-PER
White I-PER
and O
Fall B-ORG
Out I-ORG
Boy I-ORG
among O
others, O
according O
to O
the O
festival O
website. O
“We O
were O
looking O
forward O
to O
reuniting O
in O
September O
and O
hope O
we O
can O
all O
get O
back O
to O
enjoying O
the O
festival O
together O
again O
soon,” O
the O
organizers O
said. O

Last O
year’s O
festival O
attracted O
some O
50,000 O
people O
and O
featured O
performances O
by O
Miley B-PER
Cyrus I-PER
, O
the O
Jonas B-PER
Brothers I-PER
, O
and O
Maroon B-ORG
5 I-ORG
, O
according O
to O
the O
Atlanta B-LOC
Journal B-ORG
Constitution I-ORG
. O
Atlanta B-LOC
City B-LOC
Council I-LOC
President O
Doug B-PER
Shipman I-PER
said O
it O
was O
a O
“sad O
day” O
after O
the O
cancellation O
was O
announced O
. O

Public O
policy O
has O
real O
impacts O
and O
in O
this O
case- O
economic O
and O
social O
implications O
on O
a O
great O
tradition,” O
Shipman B-PER
tweeted. O
Ticket O
refunds O
will O
be O
processed O
automatically O
within O
the O
next O
24 O
hours, O
organizers O
said. O

A O
version O
of O
this O
story O
appears O
in O
CNN’s B-ORG
What O
Matters O
newsletter O
. O
To O
get O
it O
in O
your O
inbox O
, O
sign O
up O
for O
free O
here O
. O

It’s O
a O
make-or-break O
week O
for O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden’s I-PER
agenda O
. O
The O
deal O
on O
energy O
and O
health O
care O
that O
Senate O
Majority O
Leader O
Chuck B-PER
Schumer I-PER
and O
Sen. O
Joe B-PER
Manchin I-PER
announced O
last O
week O
has O
a O
narrow O
window O
to O
navigate O
both O
chambers O
of O
Congress O
and O
land O
on O
the O
President’s O
desk O
before O
August O
recess O
. O
And O
with O
the O
shock O
of O
the O
deal’s O
announcement O
wearing O
off O
, O
GOP B-ORG
opposition O
, O
public O
scrutiny O
, O
and O
Democrats’ O
slim O
majorities O
will O
all O
have O
a O
say O
in O
whether O
the O
legislation O
is O
a O
breakthrough O
or O
a O
bust O
. O
Here’s O
what O
you O
need O
to O
know O
. O

What’s O
in O
the O
bill? O
The O
agreement O
contains O
a O
number O
of O
Democrats’ O
goals, O
including O
some O
provisions O
that O
party O
leaders O
have O
worked O
toward O
for O
years: O
What’s O
not O
in O
the O
bill? O
To O
be O
clear, O
this O
isn’t O
Build O
Back O
Better O
2.0. O
The O
package O
is O
less O
than O
half O
the O
size O
of O
Biden’s B-PER
original O
social O
safety O
net O
plan, O
and O
a O
number O
of O
key O
Democratic O
priorities O
are O
likely O
to O
be O
left O
out, O
including: O
What O
are O
Republicans O
saying? O
The O
package, O
as O
it O
stands, O
is O
facing O
furious O
GOP O
opposition. O
Republican O
lawmakers O
on O
the O
Senate B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
released O
data O
from O
the O
nonpartisan O
Joint B-ORG
Committee I-ORG
on I-ORG
Taxation I-ORG
that O
showed O
that O
Americans O
of O
all O
incomes O
would O
see O
their O
federal O
taxes O
rise O
under O
the O
climate O
and O
health O
care O
package. O
That O
analysis, O
however, O
looked O
at O
the O
indirect O
effect O
of O
the O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
provision O
on O
corporations. O
Economists O
assume O
companies O
would O
then O
pass O
along O
part O
of O
their O
tax O
increase O
to O
employees O
by O
reducing O
their O
after-tax O
wages O
and O
job O
opportunities. O
Also, O
shareholders O
would O
take O
a O
hit O
since O
the O
value O
of O
their O
stock O
holdings, O
including O
those O
held O
in O
pensions O
and O
mutual O
funds, O
would O
likely O
decline. O

What’s O
Biden B-PER
saying? O
The O
President O
has O
urged O
congressional O
Democrats O
to O
quickly O
pass O
the O
surprise O
agreement O
“for O
America.” B-LOC
“This O
bill O
is O
far O
from O
perfect. O
It’s O
a O
compromise. O

But O
it’s O
often O
how O
progress O
is O
made O
, O
by O
compromises O
. O
The O
fact O
is O
that O
my O
message O
to O
Congress O
is O
this: O
This O
is O
the O
strongest O
bill O
you O
can O
pass O
to O
lower O
inflation O
, O
cut O
the O
deficit O
, O
reduce O
health O
care O
costs O
, O
tackle O
the O
climate O
crises O
and O
promote O
energy O
security O
– O
all O
the O
time O
while O
reducing O
the O
burdens O
facing O
working-class O
and O
middle-class O
families O
, O
” O
Biden B-PER
said O
during O
a O
speech O
at O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
the O
day O
after O
the O
deal O
was O
announced O
. O
What’s O
the O
timeline? O
The O
health O
and O
climate O
bill O
stands O
a O
serious O
chance O
of O
becoming O
law O
as O
soon O
as O
August O
, O
assuming O
it O
passes O
muster O
with O
the O
Senate B-ORG
parliamentarian O
to O
allow O
it O
to O
be O
approved O
along O
straight O
party O
lines O
in O
the O
budget O
process O
– O
and O
all O
Democrats B-ORG
vote O
for O
it O
( O
more O
on O
that O
below O
) O
– O
and O
that O
the O
House B-ORG
passes O
it O
. O
Democrats B-ORG
need O
all O
50 O
of O
their O
senators O
to O
be O
present O
and O
vote O
in O
favor O
of O
the O
bill O
with O
Vice O
President O
Kamala B-PER
Harris I-PER
casting O
the O
tie-breaking O
vote O
, O
as O
all O
Republicans B-ORG
are O
expected O
to O
vote O
against O
the O
deal O
. O
Manchin B-PER
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Jake B-PER
Tapper I-PER
on O
“State O
of O
the O
Union” O
Sunday O
he O
hopes O
the O
legislation O
passes O
before O
the O
August O
recess O
. O
“I O
think O
it’s O
a O
great O
piece O
of O
legislation O
and O
on O
normal O
times O
, O
my O
Republican O
colleagues O
would O
be O
for O
something O
such O
as O
this. O

We’ve O
basically O
paid O
down O
debt O
, O
(which) O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

We’ve O
accelerated O
permitting O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O
And O
we’ve O
increased O
production O
of O
energy O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O
We’ve O
done O
things O
that O
we O
should O
be O
doing O
together O
, O
” O
Manchin B-PER
said O
. O

Will O
Democrats O
be O
united O
? O
All O
eyes O
in O
Washington B-LOC
are O
on O
Arizona B-LOC
Democratic O
Sen. O
Kyrsten B-PER
Sinema I-PER
, O
a O
key O
moderate O
, O
who O
has O
not O
yet O
weighed O
in O
on O
the O
bill O
. O
She O
has O
previously O
raised O
concerns O
about O
taxes O
on O
carried O
interest O
, O
which O
would O
raise O
$14 O
billion O
under O
the O
deal O
. O
Sinema B-PER
was O
not O
part O
of O
negotiations O
for O
the O
current O
package O
. O
Asked O
about O
getting O
the O
support O
of O
his O
Arizona B-LOC
colleague O
, O
Manchin B-PER
said O
on O
Sunday O
, O
“ O
We O
work O
very O
close O
together O
on O
so O
many O
things O
, O
and O
she O
has O
so O
much O
in O
this O
piece O
of O
legislation O
. O
She’s O
formed O
quite O
a O
bit O
of O
and O
worked O
on O
it O
very O
hard O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
that O
basically O
when O
she O
looks O
at O
the O
bill O
and O
sees O
the O
whole O
spectrum O
of O
what O
we’re O
doing O
… O
hopefully O
she O
will O
be O
positive O
about O
it O
, O
but O
she’ll O
make O
her O
decision O
and O
I O
respect O
that O
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O
How O
did O
this O
come O
together O
? O

Read O
this O
report O
from O
CNN’s B-ORG
Capitol B-LOC
Hill I-LOC
team O
. O
The O
climate O
and O
tax O
deal O
came O
together O
in O
almost O
complete O
secret O
, O
catching O
many O
by O
surprise O
when O
it O
was O
announced O
. O
Schumer B-PER
and O
Manchin B-PER
have O
been O
in O
revived O
talks O
since O
July O
18 O
and O
locked O
down O
a O
deal O
last O
Wednesday O
, O
according O
to O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
. O
Manchin B-PER
had O
thrown O
cold O
water O
on O
doing O
tax O
and O
energy O
provisions O
as O
part O
of O
the O
deal O
, O
but O
ultimately O
agreed O
to O
it O
. O
CNN’s B-ORG
Devan B-PER
Cole I-PER
, O
Daniella B-PER
Diaz I-PER
, O
Tami B-PER
Luhby I-PER
and O
Katie B-PER
Lobosco I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Editor’s O
Note: O
Dean B-PER
Obeidallah, I-PER
a O
former O
attorney, O
is O
the O
host O
of O
SiriusXM B-ORG
radio’s O
daily O
program O
“The O
Dean B-PER
Obeidallah I-PER
Show” O
and O
a O
columnist O
for O
The O
Daily B-ORG
Beast. I-ORG
Follow O
him O
@DeanObeidallah. O

Read O
more O
opinion O
on O
CNN B-ORG
. O
The O
Conservative B-ORG
Political I-ORG
Action I-ORG
Conference I-ORG
made O
it O
clear O
over O
the O
weekend O
in O
Texas B-LOC
whose O
side O
it’s O
on O
in O
the O
fight O
against O
domestic O
terrorism O
. O
First O
, O
it O
featured O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
as O
its O
star O
speaker O
. O

Here O
is O
a O
man O
who O
not O
only O
was O
allegedly O
involved O
in O
waging O
an O
attempted O
coup O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
but O
who O
also O
summoned O
his O
supporters O
to O
Washington B-LOC
on O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
for O
a O
“wild” O
protest O
. O
Then O
on O
that O
fateful O
day O
, O
he O
inflamed O
them O
with O
his O
words O
and O
directed O
them O
to O
head O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Capitol B-LOC
to O
“Stop O
the O
Steal.” O
And O
as O
some O
of O
his O
supporters O
brutally O
beat O
police O
officers O
, O
built O
gallows O
while O
chanting O
to O
hang O
his O
vice O
president O
and O
broke O
into O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
to O
try O
to O
stop O
Congress O
from O
certifying O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden’s I-PER
win O
, O
Trump B-PER
did O
nothing O
for O
more O
than O
three O
hours O
to O
stop O
the O
attack O
. O
(Trump B-PER
has O
denied O
responsibility O
for O
the O
insurrection. O
CPAC B-ORG
also O
welcomed O
as O
a O
speaker O
Viktor B-PER
Orban I-PER
, O
Hungary’s B-LOC
autocratic O
Prime O
Minister O
, O
who O
a O
week O
earlier O
had O
given O
a O
speech O
in O
which O
he O
declared O
that O
in O
Europe B-LOC
“we O
do O
not O
want O
to O
become O
peoples O
of O
mixed O
race.” O
Those O
words O
prompted O
a O
longtime O
Orban B-PER
aide O
to O
resign O
, O
slamming O
his O
remarks O
as O
“pure O
Nazi O
text.” O
But O
the O
cherry O
on O
the O
sundae O
was O
a O
CPAC B-ORG
panel O
showcasing O
Brandon B-PER
Straka I-PER
, O
who O
pleaded O
guilty O
to O
disorderly O
conduct O
in O
the O
January O
6 O
attack O
, O
as O
part O
of O
a O
larger O
exhibit O
designed O
to O
elicit O
sympathy O
for O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
attackers O
still O
in O
prison O
. O
As O
part O
of O
his O
guilty O
plea O
to O
a O
misdemeanor O
, O
Straka B-PER
admitted O
to O
urging O
the O
violent O
mob O
to O
rip O
a O
riot O
shield O
from O
a O
police O
officer O
, O
shouting O
, O
“Take O
it! O

Take O
it!,” O
The O
Washington B-LOC
Post I-LOC
reported O
. O
Straka B-PER
ultimately O
received O
90 O
days’ O
home O
confinement O
and O
three O
years’ O
probation O
after O
agreeing O
to O
cooperate O
with O
law O
enforcement O
. O
But O
just O
last O
week O
, O
a O
federal O
judge O
slammed O
Straka B-PER
for O
making O
public O
comments O
inconsistent O
with O
his O
statements O
to O
investigators O
, O
raising O
the O
possibility O
that O
he O
could O
be O
charged O
with O
lying O
to O
federal O
authorities O
, O
NPR B-ORG
reported O
. O
Nevertheless O
, O
Straka B-PER
appeared O
on O
a O
CPAC B-ORG
panel O
with O
Republican O
Rep. O
Andy B-PER
Biggs I-PER
of O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
criticizing O
the O
House O
member O
for O
not O
doing O
more O
to O
help O
protesters O
who O
have O
been O
arrested O
in O
connection O
with O
the O
January O
6 O
riot O
and O
eliciting O
jeers O
from O
the O
audience O
for O
the O
lawmaker O
, O
according O
to O
Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
. O
In O
an O
apparent O
effort O
to O
get O
into O
the O
crowd’s O
good O
graces O
, O
according O
to O
Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
and O
video O
of O
the O
event O
, O
Biggs B-PER
then O
vowed O
to O
“start O
defunding O
some O
of O
these O
bad O
agencies O
, O
the O
FBI B-ORG
, O
the O
DOJ B-ORG
. O
Yes O
, O
a O
GOP B-ORG
member O
of O
Congress O
reportedly O
told O
the O
crowd O
that O
he O
would O
begin O
to O
defund O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
and O
FBI B-ORG
for O
having O
the O
audacity O
to O
prosecute O
January O
6 O
attackers O
. O
Then O
came O
the O
pièce O
de O
résistance O
: O
a O
headline-grabbing O
, O
jaw-dropping O
exhibit O
that O
featured O
a O
prison O
cell O
that O
housed O
a O
person O
dressed O
in O
an O
orange O
jumpsuit O
, O
wearing O
a O
red O
“Make O
America O
Great O
Again” O
cap O
. O
CPAC B-ORG
attendees O
were O
invited O
to O
put O
on O
headsets O
to O
listen O
to O
actual O
messages O
from O
the O
January O
6 O
attackers O
. O
A O
CPAC B-ORG
representative O
told O
BuzzFeed B-ORG
News I-ORG
that O
the O
#Walk O
Away O
group O
founded O
by O
Straka B-PER
ran O
the O
booth O
. O
In O
the O
past O
, O
CPAC B-ORG
has O
reportedly O
banned O
a O
booth O
from O
an O
atheist O
organization O
and O
the O
Log B-ORG
Cabin I-ORG
Republicans I-ORG
, O
an O
LGBT O
group O
, O
as O
an O
event O
sponsor O
. O
On O
Thursday O
, O
an O
actor O
played O
the O
prisoner O
, O
complete O
with O
tears O
as O
he O
stood O
in O
front O
of O
a O
chalkboard O
that O
read O
, O
“Where O
is O
Everyone?” O
But O
on O
Friday O
– O
in O
a O
surreal O
case O
of O
life O
imitating O
art O
– O
Straka B-PER
portrayed O
the O
prisoner O
in O
the O
cell O
. O
Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
reported O
that O
the O
line O
to O
see O
Straka B-PER
stretched O
clear O
to O
the O
back O
of O
the O
exhibit O
hall O
. O

It O
wasn’t O
long O
before O
right-wing O
firebrand O
Rep. O
Marjorie B-PER
Taylor I-PER
Greene I-PER
– O
who O
has O
long O
called O
the O
jailed O
January O
6 O
attackers O
“political O
prisoners” O
– O
entered O
the O
fake O
jail O
cell O
and O
led O
a O
prayer O
for O
those O
still O
imprisoned O
for O
their O
role O
in O
the O
January O
6 O
attack. O
Let’s O
put O
politics O
aside O
and O
look O
at O
the O
facts. O

January O
6 O
was O
an O
act O
of O
“ O
domestic O
terrorism O
,” O
as O
FBI B-ORG
Director O
Christopher B-PER
Wray I-PER
testified O
before O
Congress B-ORG
. O
Just O
as O
we O
would O
call O
anyone O
involved O
in O
the O
far O
deadlier O
September B-LOC
11 O
2001 O
, O
attacks O
“ O
terrorists O
” O
– O
we O
would O
do O
the O
same O
for O
anyone O
who O
played O
a O
role O
on O
January O
6 O
. O

For O
some O
people O
, O
the O
idea O
of O
calling O
a O
white O
American B-LOC
a O
terrorist O
is O
uncomfortable O
, O
but O
there’s O
no O
place O
for O
timidity O
when O
the O
stakes O
are O
this O
high O
. O
Those O
behind O
the O
mock O
jail O
cell O
at O
CPAC B-ORG
want O
you O
to O
have O
sympathy O
for O
the O
worst O
of O
the O
January O
6 O
attackers O
. O
The O
overwhelmingly O
majority O
of O
people O
arrested O
in O
connection O
with O
the O
January O
6 O
attack O
have O
been O
granted O
bail O
, O
according O
to O
PolitiFact B-ORG
. O
Those O
defendants O
still O
in O
jail O
deserve O
to O
be O
there O
because O
of O
the O
severity O
of O
crimes O
with O
which O
they O
have O
been O
charged O
. O
Among O
them O
are O
members O
of O
the O
Oath B-ORG
Keepers I-ORG
militia O
and O
the O
Proud B-ORG
Boys I-ORG
– O
some O
of O
whom O
were O
charged O
with O
“seditious O
conspiracy” O
– O
and O
others O
who O
are O
accused O
of O
brutally O
beating O
police O
officers O
and O
other O
heinous O
acts O
. O
Judges O
hearing O
the O
charges O
against O
these O
suspects O
have O
deemed O
that O
they O
pose O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
community O
were O
they O
to O
be O
released O
on O
bail O
. O
Imagine O
if O
, O
about O
18 O
months O
after O
a O
terrorist O
attack O
, O
a O
booth O
at O
a O
Democratic B-ORG
event O
attempted O
to O
elicit O
sympathy O
for O
those O
arrested O
for O
their O
role O
in O
a O
deadly O
strike O
on O
our O
nation O
! O
Critics O
would O
lash O
out O
at O
Democrats B-ORG
as O
unpatriotic O
Americans B-LOC
who O
support O
terrorism O
. O

And O
they O
would O
be O
right O
to O
do O
so O
. O
That’s O
the O
same O
revulsion O
the O
vile O
display O
at O
CPAC B-ORG
deserves O
from O
all O
of O
us O
. O

الإمارات B-LOC
تدعم O
مبدأ O
"الصين O
الواحدة" O
وتؤكد: O
قلقون O
من O
"الزيارات O
الاستفزازية" O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

Vulnerabilities O
in O
software O
that O
TV O
and O
radio O
networks O
around O
the O
country O
use O
to O
transmit O
emergency O
alerts O
could O
allow O
a O
hacker O
to O
broadcast O
fake O
messages O
over O
the O
alert O
system O
, O
a O
Federal B-ORG
Emergency I-ORG
Management I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
official O
tells O
CNN B-ORG
. O
A O
cybersecurity O
researcher O
provided O
FEMA B-ORG
with O
“compelling O
evidence O
to O
suggest O
certain O
unpatched O
and O
unsecured O
EAS O
[Emergency O
Alert O
System] O
devices O
are O
indeed O
vulnerable O
, O
said O
Mark B-PER
Lucero I-PER
, O
the O
chief O
engineer O
for O
Integrated B-ORG
Public I-ORG
Alert I-ORG
& I-ORG
Warning I-ORG
System I-ORG
, O
the O
national O
system O
that O
state O
and O
local O
officials O
use O
to O
send O
urgent O
alerts O
about O
natural O
disasters O
or O
child O
abductions O
. O
The O
agency O
this O
week O
urged O
operators O
of O
the O
devices O
to O
update O
their O
software O
to O
address O
the O
issue O
, O
saying O
that O
the O
false O
alerts O
could O
in O
theory O
be O
issued O
over O
TV O
, O
radio O
and O
cable O
networks O
. O

The O
advisory O
did O
not O
say O
that O
alerts O
sent O
over O
text O
messages O
were O
affected O
. O
There O
is O
no O
evidence O
that O
malicious O
hackers O
have O
exploited O
the O
vulnerabilities O
, O
Lucero B-PER
said O
. O
It’s O
unclear O
how O
many O
emergency O
alert O
system O
devices O
are O
running O
the O
vulnerable O
software O
. O
FEMA B-ORG
referred O
a O
request O
for O
an O
estimate O
of O
that O
figure O
to O
the O
FCC B-ORG
, O
which O
did O
not O
immediately O
respond O
to O
a O
request O
for O
comment O
. O
Ken B-PER
Pyle I-PER
, O
the O
cybersecurity O
researcher O
who O
discovered O
the O
issue O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
he O
acquired O
several O
of O
the O
EAS O
devices O
independently O
and O
found O
poor O
security O
controls O
. O
He O
shared O
an O
example O
of O
a O
fake O
alert O
he O
crafted O
, O
but O
did O
not O
send O
, O
that O
declared O
a O
“civil O
emergency” O
for O
certain O
counties O
and O
areas O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
. O

TV O
and O
radio O
networks O
own O
and O
operate O
the O
equipment O
and O
transmit O
the O
emergency O
alerts O
but O
they O
are O
drafted O
by O
local O
authorities O
. O
Digital B-ORG
Alert I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
, I-ORG
Inc. I-ORG
, O
the O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
-based O
firm O
that O
makes O
the O
emergency-alert O
software O
, O
said O
that O
Pyle B-PER
first O
reported O
the O
vulnerabilities O
to O
the O
firm O
in O
2019 O
, O
at O
which O
time O
the O
firm O
issued O
updated O
software O
to O
address O
the O
issue O
. O
However O
, O
Pyle B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
subsequent O
versions O
of O
the O
Digital B-ORG
Alert I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
software O
were O
still O
susceptible O
to O
some O
of O
the O
security O
issues O
he O
discovered O
. O
“ O
We O
take O
all O
security O
reports O
very O
seriously O
, O
Ed B-PER
Czarnecki I-PER
, O
Digital B-ORG
Alert I-ORG
Systems’ I-ORG
vice O
president O
of O
global O
and O
government O
affairs O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
He O
added O
that O
the O
firm O
will O
examine O
future O
software O
releases O
for O
any O
issues O
reported O
by O
Pyle B-PER
. O
“ O
The O
vast O
majority O
of O
our O
users O
have O
been O
very O
good O
at O
keeping O
up O
with O
software O
updates O
, O
Czarnecki B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
that O
users O
can O
further O
mitigate O
the O
issue O
by O
ensuring O
the O
device O
is O
protected O
by O
a O
firewall O
. O
Seeing O
the O
breakdown O
of O
law O
enforcement O
communications O
in O
the O
days O
before O
the O
January O
6 O
2019 O
, O
attack O
on O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
motivated O
Pyle B-PER
to O
dig O
further O
into O
the O
security O
of O
those O
types O
of O
communications O
, O
he O
said O
. O
“ O
It’s O
a O
big O
critical O
infrastructure O
problem O
everyone O
needs O
to O
own O
, O
said O
Pyle B-PER
, O
who O
is O
a O
partner O
at O
security O
firm O
CYBIR B-ORG
. O

He O
will O
demonstrate O
his O
research O
next O
week O
in O
Las B-LOC
Vegas I-LOC
at O
DEF B-ORG
CON I-ORG
, O
one O
of O
the O
world’s O
biggest O
hacking O
conferences O
. O

The O
misuse O
of O
emergency O
alerts O
can O
create O
panic O
. O
In O
2018 O
, O
an O
employee O
of O
a O
Hawaii B-LOC
Emergency B-ORG
Management I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
was O
supposed O
to O
test O
the O
alert O
system O
but O
instead O
sent O
actual O
text O
messages O
to O
the O
cellphones O
of O
Hawaiian O
residents O
and O
tourists O
about O
a O
supposed O
incoming O
ballistic O
missile O
that O
told O
them O
to O
“SEEK O
IMMEDIATE O
SHELTER O
.” O

Editor’s O
Note: O
A O
version O
of O
this O
story O
first O
appeared O
in O
CNN’s B-ORG
Meanwhile O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
newsletter, O
a O
three-times-a-week O
look O
inside O
the O
region’s O
biggest O
stories. O

Sign O
up O
here O
. O
One O
of O
the O
most O
important O
aspects O
of O
the O
weekend’s O
short O
but O
violent O
conflict O
between O
Israel B-LOC
and O
the O
Palestinian O
Islamic O
Jihad O
( O
PIJ B-ORG
) O
was O
what O
didn’t O
happen O
: O
Hamas’ O
involvement O
. O
A O
ceasefire O
between O
Israel B-LOC
and O
the O
PIJ B-ORG
over O
Gaza B-LOC
that O
went O
into O
effect O
at O
11:30 O
p.m. O
local O
time O
( O
4:30 O
p.m. O
) O

ET) O
Sunday O
appeared O
to O
be O
holding O
almost O
24 O
hours O
later. O
The O
conflict O
led O
to O
the O
death O
of O
at O
least O
44 O
militants O
and O
civilians O
in O
Gaza, B-LOC
according O
to O
information O
from O
the O
Palestinian B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
Of I-ORG
Health. I-ORG

Fifteen O
of O
the O
dead O
were O
children O
. O
Israel B-LOC
insists O
most O
of O
those O
killed O
were O
militants O
, O
and O
that O
several O
civilians O
were O
killed O
by O
failed O
militant O
rocket O
launches O
. O
Hamas B-ORG
, O
the O
militant O
group O
that O
runs O
Gaza B-LOC
, O
expressed O
support O
for O
the O
PIJ’s O
actions O
. O
But O
it O
kept O
its O
much O
larger O
and O
more O
powerful O
arsenal O
of O
rockets O
out O
of O
the O
equation O
, O
while O
Israel’s B-LOC
military O
made O
it O
clear O
from O
the O
outset O
they O
were O
focusing O
solely O
on O
PIJ O
targets O
. O
That O
kept O
the O
conflict O
from O
spiraling O
into O
a O
larger O
, O
more O
dangerous O
confrontation O
, O
and O
closer O
to O
what O
happened O
during O
the O
11-day O
war O
in O
May O
2021 O
. O
So O
why O
not O
get O
involved O
? O
According O
to O
analysts O
and O
Israeli B-LOC
officials O
, O
one O
reason O
is O
the O
fact O
it O
is O
still O
only O
15 O
months O
since O
the O
2021 O
conflict O
that O
led O
to O
considerable O
damage O
and O
death O
in O
Gaza B-LOC
. O
Palestinians O
there O
are O
still O
rebuilding O
their O
homes O
, O
and O
Hamas B-ORG
is O
rebuilding O
its O
arsenal O
. O
The O
Israeli B-LOC
government O
also O
believes O
its O
campaign O
of O
economic O
incentives O
– O
boosting O
the O
number O
of O
permits O
given O
to O
Gazans O
to O
cross O
into O
Israel B-LOC
for O
work O
– O
is O
succeeding O
. O
Israel B-LOC
and O
Egypt B-LOC
have O
imposed O
a O
closure O
on O
Gaza B-LOC
since O
2007 O
, O
limiting O
access O
to O
the O
territory O
via O
land O
, O
air O
and O
sea O
, O
including O
tight O
restrictions O
on O
the O
movement O
of O
residents O
and O
the O
flow O
of O
goods O
. O
If O
rockets O
are O
fired O
, O
Israel B-LOC
closes O
the O
border O
and O
the O
thousands O
of O
Gazans O
with O
permits O
can’t O
work O
in O
Israel B-LOC
or O
get O
paid O
. O
On O
Monday O
, O
a O
senior O
Israeli B-LOC
diplomatic O
official O
said O
Hamas B-ORG
was O
“ O
an O
enemy O
not O
a O
partner O
… O
but O
there O
is O
cooperation O
we O
can O
do O
, O
predominantly O
through O
Egypt B-LOC
, O
to O
improve O
the O
situation O
in O
Gaza B-LOC
. O
For O
showing O
restraint O
, O
Hamas B-ORG
will O
expect O
to O
be O
rewarded O
. O
Lapid’s O
first O
big O
security O
test O
The O
weekend’s O
conflict O
was O
also O
the O
first O
major O
military O
test O
for O
interim O
Prime O
Minister O
Yair B-PER
Lapid I-PER
. O

Unlike O
his O
predecessor O
Naftali B-PER
Bennett I-PER
, O
Lapid B-PER
is O
not O
known O
for O
his O
military O
combat O
experience O
. O
But O
like O
US B-ORG
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
visit O
last O
month O
, O
it O
was O
another O
moment O
for O
Lapid B-PER
to O
look O
like O
a O
real O
prime O
minister O
— O
images O
Lapid B-PER
likely O
hopes O
Israelis B-LOC
remember O
as O
they O
had O
to O
the O
polls O
in O
November O
. O
The O
conflict O
also O
brought O
about O
another O
breakthrough O
, O
albeit O
on O
a O
somewhat O
smaller O
scale O
: O
former O
prime O
minister O
, O
now O
opposition O
leader O
Benjamin B-PER
Netanyahu I-PER
met O
with O
Lapid B-PER
on O
Sunday O
to O
receive O
a O
security O
briefing O
on O
the O
operation O
. O
It O
was O
his O
first O
security O
briefing O
since O
leaving O
power O
– O
even O
though O
by O
law O
it O
is O
supposed O
to O
be O
standard O
practice O
. O

Until O
this O
weekend O
, O
Netanyahu B-PER
had O
boycotted O
the O
meetings O
. O

After O
the O
meeting O
, O
Netanyahu B-PER
said O
he O
supported O
the O
operation O
and O
gave O
his O
“ O
full O
backing O
to O
the O
government O
, O
the O
IDF O
, O
and O
the O
security O
forces O
.” O
Parts O
of O
Gaza B-LOC
once O
again O
lie O
in O
rubble O
and O
the O
mourning O
continues O
for O
lost O
lives O
, O
but O
for O
everyday O
Israelis B-LOC
and O
Gazans B-LOC
, O
the O
conflict O
hasn’t O
led O
to O
a O
substantial O
change O
in O
the O
political O
situation O
on O
the O
ground O
. O
The O
digest O
Russia B-LOC
envoy O
to O
Iran B-LOC
nuclear O
talks O
says O
they O
are O
“ O
moving O
in O
right O
direction O
” O
Ambassador O
Mikhail B-PER
Ulyanov I-PER
, O
Russia’s B-LOC
chief O
negotiator O
in O
Vienna B-LOC
for O
talks O
aimed O
at O
reviving O
the O
Iran B-LOC
nuclear O
deal O
, O
on O
Sunday O
told O
media O
, O
“ O
I O
cannot O
guarantee O
[ O
anything O
] O
, O
but O
the O
impression O
is O
that O
we O
are O
moving O
in O
the O
right O
direction O
.” O
He O
said O
there O
were O
“ O
minimal O
” O
unresolved O
issues O
, O
“ O
just O
3 O
[ O
or O
4 O
] O
.” O
Putin B-PER
, O
Erdogan B-PER
agree O
to O
begin O
partial O
payment O
in O
rubles O
for O
Russian B-LOC
gas O
Bilateral O
talks O
in O
Sochi B-LOC
between O
Russian B-LOC
President O
Vladimir B-PER
Putin I-PER
and O
Turkish B-LOC
President O
Recep B-PER
Tayyip I-PER
Erdogan I-PER
included O
an O
agreement O
to O
pay O
Russia B-LOC
in O
rubles O
for O
partial O
gas O
supplies O
. O
Russian B-LOC
Deputy O
Prime O
Minister O
Alexander B-PER
Novak I-PER
said O
the O
two O
presidents O
reached O
agreements O
on O
establishing O
a O
financial O
banking O
bloc O
“ O
to O
enable O
commercial O
companies O
, O
Russian B-LOC
citizens O
, O
to O
pay O
during O
tourist O
trips O
and O
exchange O
money O
.” O
Iran B-LOC
city O
reaches O
53 O
degrees O
Celsius O
, O
hottest O
temperature O
in O
the O
world O
this O
year O
Abadan B-LOC
, O
Iran B-LOC
had O
a O
high O
temperature O
of O
53.0° O
C O
(127.4° O
F) O
Friday O
– O
the O
highest O
temperature O
recorded O
anywhere O
in O
the O
world O
in O
2022 O
, O
according O
to O
weather O
historian O
Maximiliano B-PER
Herrera I-PER
. O
What’s O
trending O
Kuwait B-LOC
: O
#Wage_rise_is_a_public_demand O
The O
citizens O
of O
one O
of O
the O
richest O
Arab O
countries O
are O
demanding O
a O
rise O
in O
wages O

Kuwaitis O
took O
to O
Twitter B-ORG
to O
express O
their O
frustration O
at O
the O
country’s O
economic O
situation O
, O
blaming O
official O
corruption O
and O
greed O
for O
alleged O
inequality O
in O
pay O
. O
Kuwaiti O
citizens O
are O
a O
minority O
in O
the O
country O
of O
4.2 O
million O
, O
making O
up O
just O
30% O
of O
the O
population O
, O
according O
to O
World B-ORG
Population I-ORG
Review I-ORG
. O
Most O
rely O
on O
government O
jobs O
to O
make O
a O
living O
. O
“ O
It’s O
inconceivable O
that O
a O
rich O
country O
like O
Kuwait B-LOC
that O
has O
a O
small O
number O
of O
people O
and O
the O
strongest O
currency O
in O
the O
world O
[ O
wouldn’t O
raise O
wages O
], O
” O
tweeted O
Mohammed B-PER
Al I-PER
Huwaishel I-PER
. O
“ O
The O
demands O
of O
the O
people O
must O
be O
met O
without O
conditions O
. O
Many O
Kuwaitis O
take O
government O
jobs O
– O
where O
pay O
can O
be O
up O
to O
28% O
higher O
than O
the O
private O
sector O
– O
because O
they O
either O
lack O
the O
necessary O
skills O
to O
work O
in O
the O
private O
sector O
or O
because O
some O
of O
those O
jobs O
are O
seen O
as O
menial O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Middle B-ORG
East I-ORG
Institute I-ORG
. O
Due O
to O
the O
benefits O
offered O
in O
government O
jobs O
, O
the O
private O
sector O
finds O
it O
difficult O
to O
lure O
Kuwaitis O
. O
According O
to O
the O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
public O
wages O
and O
benefits O
account O
for O
one-third O
of O
the O
government’s O
budget O
. O

The O
government O
set O
aside O
$72 O
billion O
in O
spending O
for O
its O
latest O
budget O
. O
The O
World B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
warned O
in O
December O
that O
the O
government’s O
wage O
bill O
is O
unsustainable O
, O
saying O
that O
if O
the O
situation O
continues O
, O
the O
country’s O
financial O
reserves O
will O
be O
depleted O
. O
The O
nation O
has O
made O
the O
least O
progress O
among O
oil-rich O
Gulf B-LOC
Arab I-LOC
countries O
to O
reform O
its O
wage O
bill O
and O
has O
even O
increased O
hiring O
, O
it O
said O
. O
Another O
hashtag O
on B-ORG
Twitter I-ORG
called O
on O
the O
government O
to O
write O
off O
citizens’ O
debt O
, O
which O
is O
not O
without O
precedent O
. O
After O
the O
end O
of O
the O
1991 O
Gulf B-LOC
War I-LOC
, O
the O
government O
wrote O
off O
almost O
all O
consumer O
debt O
. O
By O
Mohammed B-PER
Abdelbary I-PER
Photo O
of O
the O
day O

Dry O
lightning O
has O
ignited O
some O
of O
the O
most O
destructive O
and O
costly O
wildfires O
in O
California B-LOC
history O
, O
a O
new O
study O
shows O
. O
Researchers O
found O
that O
over O
the O
past O
few O
decades O
, O
nearly O
half O
of O
the O
lightning O
strikes O
that O
hit O
the O
ground O
during O
spring O
and O
summer O
had O
been O
dry O
— O
there O
was O
no O
rain O
falling O
nearby O
. O
Dry O
lightning O
tends O
to O
happen O
in O
storms O
over O
areas O
of O
extreme O
drought O
, O
like O
the O
one O
California B-LOC
has O
been O
in O
for O
the O
past O
several O
years O
. O
The O
air O
is O
so O
dry O
that O
the O
rain O
evaporates O
before O
it O
hits O
the O
ground O
. O
And O
the O
conditions O
that O
favor O
dry O
lightning O
are O
becoming O
more O
widespread O
and O
more O
frequent O
as O
the O
climate O
crisis O
fuel’s O
the O
West’s O
megadrought O
. O
Dmitri B-PER
Kalashnikov I-PER
, O
lead O
author O
of O
the O
paper O
and O
a O
doctoral O
student O
at O
Washington B-ORG
State I-ORG
University I-ORG
, O
pointed O
to O
the O
wildfires O
that O
scorched O
California B-LOC
in O
2020 O
— O
particularly O
the O
August O
Complex O
Fire O
, O
the O
largest O
wildfire O
in O
the O
state’s O
history O
— O
as O
the O
motivation O
for O
the O
research O
. O

The O
August O
Complex O
Fire O
was O
originally O
more O
than O
three O
dozen O
fires O
that O
were O
sparked O
by O
dry O
lightning O
. O

Those O
fires O
merged O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
in O
state O
history O
, O
burning O
more O
than O
a O
million O
acres O
in O
seven O
counties O
. O

California B-LOC
firefighters O
were O
exhausted O
that O
summer O
, O
CNN B-ORG
reported O
at O
the O
time O
, O
and O
they O
were O
particularly O
concerned O
about O
the O
potential O
for O
more O
and O
more O
fires O
sparked O
by O
dry O
lightning O
. O
All O
of O
the O
seven O
largest O
fires O
in O
California B-LOC
history O
have O
occurred O
in O
the O
past O
five O
years O
, O
and O
four O
of O
those O
were O
caused O
by O
lightning O
, O
according O
to O
data O
from O
Cal B-ORG
Fire I-ORG
. O
“ O
With O
warming O
and O
drying O
and O
drier O
vegetation O
, O
it O
doesn’t O
take O
a O
whole O
lot O
of O
lightning O
to O
start O
wildfires O
, O
Kalashnikov B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
“ O
So O
even O
if O
, O
on O
the O
off O
chance O
, O
dry O
lightning O
decreases O
in O
the O
future O
, O
it O
just O
takes O
one O
outbreak O
one O
day O
in O
a O
year O
to O
cause O
a O
lot O
of O
fire O
and O
a O
lot O
of O
damage O
, O
if O
that O
were O
to O
happen O
. O
The O
study O
, O
funded O
by O
NASA B-ORG
and O
published O
Monday O
in O
the O
journal O
Environmental B-ORG
Research I-ORG
: I-ORG
Climate I-ORG
, O
is O
the O
first O
to O
develop O
long-term O
climatology O
of O
dry O
lightning O
in O
California B-LOC
, O
specifically O
focusing O
on O
Central B-LOC
and O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
, O
an O
area O
where O
lightning O
is O
a O
significant O
cause O
of O
wildfire O
. O
Dry O
lightning O
was O
found O
to O
occur O
most O
frequently O
in O
July B-LOC
and O
August B-LOC
, O
the O
researchers O
found O
, O
though O
lower O
elevation O
regions O
tended O
to O
see O
activity O
peak O
later O
in O
September B-LOC
and O
October B-LOC
, O
when O
vegetation O
is O
even O
drier O
. O
Researchers O
found O
that O
around O
Sacramento B-LOC
, O
San B-LOC
Francisco I-LOC
, O
Redwood B-LOC
, O
Sequoia B-LOC
and O
Yosemite B-LOC
, O
lightning O
sparked O
nearly O
30% O
, O
of O
fires O
which O
accounted O
for O
nearly O
50% O
of O
the O
total O
burned O
area O
. O
“ O
That O
is O
a O
lot O
of O
fires O
started O
by O
lightning O
, O
which O
are O
usually O
more O
difficult O
to O
attack O
because O
they O
tend O
to O
be O
more O
remote O
than O
human O
caused O
fires O
, O
Chris B-PER
Vagasky I-PER
, O
a O
meteorologist O
and O
lightning O
applications O
manager O
at O
Vaisala B-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

Vagasky B-PER
, O
who O
is O
not O
involved O
with O
the O
study O
, O
said O
the O
findings O
provide O
“ O
excellent O
background O
” O
for O
weather O
forecasting O
and O
wildland O
management O
communities O
to O
better O
determine O
the O
conditions O
that O
are O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
to O
occur O
in O
advance O
. O

This O
really O
highlights O
the O
importance O
of O
understanding O
when O
dry O
lightning O
can O
be O
expected O
so O
that O
crews O
can O
be O
at O
the O
ready O
in O
the O
event O
of O
fire O
starting O
,” O
he O
said O
. O
“ O
So O
it’s O
good O
to O
see O
that O
there O
is O
now O
a O
study O
for O
this O
region O
of O
the B-LOC
US I-LOC
that O
shows O
not O
just O
the O
time O
of O
year O
, O
but O
the O
type O
of O
meteorological O
conditions O
that O
appear O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
.” O
  O
The O
research O
is O
just O
the O
first O
step O
, O
Vagasky B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
When O
thunderstorms O
do O
develop O
, O
first O
responders O
need O
to O
be O
aware O
that O
dry O
lightning O
conditions O
may O
be O
possible O
, O
but O
they O
will O
also O
have O
to O
be O
able O
to O
quickly O
respond O
to O
areas O
that O
are O
impacted O
, O
he O
added O
. O
Kalashnikov B-PER
said O
there O
are O
still O
uncertainties O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
lightning O
research O
, O
whether O
dry O
lightning O
will O
occur O
more O
often O
as O
the O
climate O
changes O
. O
But O
one O
thing O
is O
certain O
, O
he O
said O
, O
as O
the O
Western B-LOC
drought O
persists O
, O
conditions O
are O
much O
more O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
to O
take O
shape O
. O
In O
just O
the O
last O
year O
alone O
, O
dry O
lightning O
has O
sparked O
deadly O
and O
destructive O
wildfires O
such O
as O
the O
Bootleg O
Fire O
in O
Oregon B-LOC
that O
burned O
more O
than O
400,000 O
acres O
. O
“ O
We O
know O
it’s O
getting O
hotter O
and O
drier O
— O
California B-LOC
is O
becoming O
hotter O
and O
drier O
, O
Kalashnikov B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
So O
we O
can O
say O
that O
no O
matter O
what O
the O
trend O
in O
lightning O
is O
doing O
, O
when O
lightning O
happens O
with O
a O
hotter O
, O
drier O
atmosphere O
and O
vegetation O
, O
it’s O
just O
going O
to O
lead O
to O
more O
of O
a O
risk O
of O
these O
kinds O
of O
wildfire O
outbreaks O
like O
we O
saw O
in O
2020 O
. O

As O
firefighters O
battle O
the O
raging O
wildfire O
scorching O
a O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
forest O
and O
swallowing O
homes O
in O
its O
path O
, O
some O
residents O
forced O
to O
flee O
are O
left O
to O
grapple O
with O
the O
losses O
and O
an O
uncertain O
future O
. O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
resident O
Kayla B-PER
Dailey I-PER
, O
pregnant O
with O
her O
third O
child O
, O
spent O
her O
due O
date O
not O
prepping O
for O
the O
imminent O
delivery O
of O
her O
daughter O
, O
but O
fleeing O
the O
McKinney B-ORG
Fire I-ORG
, O
which O
she O
says O
ultimately O
engulfed O
her O
home O
. O
Dailey B-PER
, O
her O
husband O
Levi B-PER
, O
their O
two O
young O
sons O
, O
and O
the O
family’s O
roommate O
Dalton B-PER
Shute I-PER
relocated O
to O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
from O
Indiana B-LOC
just O
4 O
months O
ago O
. O

Wildfires O
were O
not O
something O
the O
family O
had O
encountered O
before O
. O
The O
blaze O
, O
the O
largest O
wildfire O
in O
California B-LOC
so O
far O
this O
year O
, O
broke O
out O
Friday O
afternoon O
in O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
National I-LOC
Forest I-LOC
near O
the O
California-Oregon B-LOC
border O
and O
grew O
rapidly O
over O
the O
weekend O
, O
fueled O
by O
explosive O
fire O
weather O
. O
The O
fire O
sprinted O
through O
dry O
brush O
and O
grass O
, O
scorching O
more O
than O
56,000 O
acres O
and O
forcing O
thousands O
to O
evacuate O
as O
the O
flames O
advanced O
on O
rural O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
communities O
. O
The O
fire O
had O
zero O
containment O
as O
of O
Tuesday O
. O

However O
, O
in O
a O
hopeful O
sign O
, O
US B-ORG
Forest I-ORG
Service I-ORG
officials O
said O
lower O
temperatures O
and O
higher O
humidity O
levels O
– O
as O
well O
as O
rain O
over O
some O
areas O
of O
the O
fire O
– O
slowed O
down O
the O
fire’s O
spread O
and O
helped O
firefighters O
to O
make O
good O
progress O
Tuesday O
. O
“ O
I O
was O
really O
confused O
at O
first O
. O
” O

I O
had O
never O
seen O
a O
forest O
fire,” O
explained O
Dailey. B-PER
“Things O
just O
looked O
weird O
– O
there O
was O
this O
orange O
cast O
over O
the O
forest O
– O
and O
once O
I O
saw O
smoke O
rising O
from O
fire O
over O
top O
of O
the O
mountains, O
I O
just O
panicked.” O
The O
couple O
and O
their O
roommate O
immediately O
packed O
all O
into O
their O
small O
car, O
leaving O
room O
for O
little O
else. O
“I O
could O
see O
nothing O
but O
smoke O
and O
the O
fire O
coming O
down O
the O
mountain,” O
said O
Dailey, B-PER
who O
later O
learned O
the O
wildfire O
started O
just O
3 O
miles O
away O
before O
it O
raced O
for O
their O
home, O
the O
flames O
feasting O
on O
their O
belongings, O
including O
everything O
set O
aside O
for O
the O
new O
baby. O
Now, O
4 O
days O
past O
her O
due O
date, O
Dailey B-PER
has O
yet O
another O
new O
worry: O
The O
nearest O
hospital O
has O
been O
evacuated O
and O
she’s O
been O
warned O
that O
she O
will O
likely O
need O
to O
make O
a O
2-hour O
trek O
through O
the O
mountains O
to O
give O
birth O
at O
a O
hospital O
in O
Medford, B-LOC
Oregon. B-LOC
It O
remains O
unclear O
how O
many O
homes O
were O
lost, O
but O
forest O
officials O
said O
“numerous” O
structures O
were O
destroyed O
around O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
community. O
Four O
people O
have O
been O
found O
dead O
in O
the O
fire’s O
burn O
area, O
including O
two O
who O
were O
in O
a O
burned O
vehicle O
in O
a O
home’s O
driveway O
and O
another O
two O
found O
at O
different O
homes O
along O
the O
same O
road, O
State O
Route O
96, O
according O
to O
the O
Siskiyou B-LOC
County I-LOC
Sheriff’s O
Office. O
More O
than O
5,800 O
people O
have O
been O
evacuated O
due O
to O
the O
fire, O
Joel B-PER
Brumm, I-PER
a O
spokesperson O
for O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
National I-ORG
Forest, I-ORG
told O
CNN. B-ORG
‘We O
don’t O
even O
have O
an O
address O
anymore’ O
Valerie B-PER
Linfoot I-PER
and O
her O
husband, O
both O
retired O
forest O
firefighters, O
lost O
their O
home O
of O
more O
than O
three O
decades. O
“We’ve O
fought O
fires O
and O
seen O
homes O
burn O
up O
and O
been O
in O
a O
place O
of O
being O
the O
firefighters O
there O
doing O
that O
work, O
but O
to O
have O
it O
happen O
to O
yourself, O
it’s O
just O
unimaginable,” O
Linfoot B-PER
told O
CNN. B-ORG
“I’m O
still O
overwhelmed O
that O
we’re O
the O
victims O
of O
this O
horrible, O
horrible O
convergence O
of O
weather O
and O
fire, O
which O
so O
many O
times O
we’ve O
seen O
other O
people O
suffer.” O
Linfoot B-PER
was O
out O
of O
town O
when O
the O
fire O
quickly O
advanced O
on O
her O
home. O
Her O
husband, O
Chuck, B-PER
saw O
the O
flames O
approach O
and O
packed O
up O
and O
left. O

He O
drove O
to O
the O
community O
hall O
and O
looked O
back O
, O
seeing O
flames O
flanking O
their O
home O
on O
both O
sides O
. O
“ O
There’s O
nothing O
left O
. O
” O

It’s O
completely O
burned O
down O
to O
the O
dirt O
. O
It’s O
just O
completely O
gone O
, O
Linfoot B-PER
said O
. O
For O
Linfoot B-PER
, O
the O
hardest O
part O
is O
thinking O
about O
the O
irreplaceable O
items O
that O
were O
left O
behind O
when O
her O
home O
burned O
down O
. O
“ O
It’s O
a O
lot O
to O
take O
on O
in O
your O
mind O
thinking O
about O
those O
things O
that O
you’re O
never O
gonna O
get O
back O
, O
she O
said O
. O

I O
left O
my O
wedding O
rings O
on O
my O
dresser O
and O
I’m O
never O
gonna O
get O
those O
back O
. O
I O
have O
been O
married O
31 O
years O
and O
those O
are O
the O
rings O
that O
were O
put O
on O
my O
finger O
the O
day O
I O
said O
yes O
. O
And O
they’re O
gone O
forever O
. O
Also O
lost O
in O
the O
fire O
were O
the O
ashes O
of O
Linfoot’s B-PER
mother O
and O
grandmother O
, O
as O
well O
as O
her O
children’s O
baby O
photographs O
. O
“ O
We O
lost O
one O
of O
our O
sons O
about O
10 O
years O
ago O
in O
a O
motorcycle O
accident O
. O
So O
the O
idea O
of O
not O
having O
any O
pictures O
… O
” O
she O
said O
. O
Linfoot B-PER
has O
found O
comfort O
in O
the O
sense O
of O
community O
in O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
, O
and O
staying O
close O
with O
friends O
who O
are O
also O
dealing O
with O
the O
same O
losses O
. O
But O
she O
worries O
for O
her O
tightly O
knit O
community O
. O
“ O
It’s O
a O
small O
community O
and O
this O
is O
absolutely O
devastating O
to O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O
“ O
I O
don’t O
know O
how O
they’re O
gonna O
recover O
. O

None O
of O
us O
are O
rich O
people O
. O
We’re O
all O
hardworking O
and O
resilient O
people O
, O
but O
most O
people O
that O
were O
down O
there O
are O
middle O
class O
, O
regular O
working O
folks O
or O
retirees O
. O
” O
She O
said O
her O
family O
is O
exploring O
their O
options O
, O
but O
don’t O
think O
they O
will O
be O
able O
to O
rebuild O
. O
The O
Linfoots B-PER
set O
up O
a O
GoFundMe B-ORG
page O
to O
help O
them O
with O
recovery O
and O
rebuilding O
. O
“ O
It’s O
hard O
to O
convey O
to O
somebody O
what O
it’s O
like O
to O
know O
that O
you O
have O
nothing O
. O

One O
of O
the O
first O
things O
my O
husband O
said O
to O
me O
is O
, O
‘ O
we O
don’t O
even O
have O
an O
address O
anymore O
,’” O
Linfoot B-PER
said O
. O
Shute B-PER
, O
the O
Dailey’s B-PER
friend O
and O
roommate O
, O
is O
still O
struggling O
to O
process O
the O
situation O
. O
“ O
It O
still O
doesn’t O
feel O
real O
, O
said O
Shute B-PER
, O
who O
lost O
his O
mom O
to O
a O
house O
fire O
when O
he O
was O
6 O
years O
old O
. O
“ O
I O
feel O
that O
sort O
of O
emptiness O
I O
felt O
when O
I O
was O
a O
child O
.” O
Despite O
the O
challenges O
they’ve O
faced O
, O
Shute B-PER
and O
his O
roommates O
are O
confident O
that O
they O
will O
rebound O
, O
and O
are O
grateful O
for O
the O
help O
being O
offered O
by O
the O
community O
. O
A O
GoFundMe B-ORG
page O
has O
been O
set O
up O
to O
help O
him O
find O
a O
new O
home O
. O
“ O
We’re O
definitely O
not O
going O
to O
let O
this O
set O
us O
back O
, O
” O
Shute B-PER
said O
. O

Right O
now O
we’re O
learning O
to O
take O
it O
one O
day O
at O
a O
time O
and O
we’ll O
eventually O
be O
in O
a O
good O
place O
again O

Two O
men O
serving O
life O
sentences O
for O
murder O
in O
a O
Florida B-LOC
prison O
have O
been O
linked O
to O
two O
other O
murders O
with O
the O
help O
of O
newly O
discovered O
DNA O
samples O
, O
which O
led O
to O
the O
exoneration O
of O
another O
man O
who O
wrongfully O
served O
37 O
years O
in O
prison O
for O
the O
rape O
and O
murder O
of O
Barbara B-PER
Grams I-PER
in O
1983 O
. O
Amos B-PER
Robinson I-PER
and O
Abron B-PER
Scott I-PER
allegedly O
raped O
and O
murdered O
19 O
-year-old O
Grams B-PER
, O
whose O
beaten O
body O
was O
found O
behind O
a O
dental O
office O
in O
Tampa B-LOC
Heights I-LOC
on O
August O
18 O
, O
1983 O
, O
Hillsborough B-LOC
County I-LOC
State O
Attorney O
Andrew B-PER
Warren I-PER
said O
during O
a O
news O
conference O
Thursday O
after O
he O
was O
suspended O
as O
the O
state O
attorney O
by O
Florida B-LOC
Gov O
. O
Ron B-PER
DeSantis I-PER
for O
his O
stance O
against O
criminalizing O
abortion O
providers O
. O

A O
grand O
jury O
indicted O
Robinson B-PER
and O
Scott B-PER
Thursday O
for O
the O
rape O
and O
murder O
of O
Linda B-PER
Lansen I-PER
, O
whose O
beaten O
body O
was O
found O
in O
Town B-LOC
and I-LOC
Country I-LOC
in O
July O
1983 O
in O
bushes O
with O
a O
gunshot O
wound O
to O
the O
head O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
These O
two O
men O
not O
only O
robbed O
me O
, O
but O
they O
robbed O
a O
7-year-old O
little O
girl O
of O
her O
mother O
, O
said O
Linda B-PER
Sheffield I-PER
, O
Lansen’s O
niece O
, O
during O
Thursday’s O
news O
conference O
. O
“ O
When O
they’re O
initially O
murdered O
, O
the O
shock O
is O
there O
, O
but O
39 O
years O
later O
the O
shock O
is O
no O
longer O
there O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O

But O
the O
void O
stays O
, O
and O
the O
pain O
stays O
and O
the O
crying O
stays O
. O
It O
doesn’t O
go O
away O
. O
Robinson B-PER
and O
Scott B-PER
are O
also O
subjects O
of O
other O
cold O
case O
investigations O
from O
the O
same O
time O
period O
in O
the O
Tampa B-LOC
Bay I-LOC
area O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
We O
now O
know O
that O
these O
two O
men O
carried O
out O
a O
sinister O
spree O
of O
rape O
and O
murder O
in O
Tampa B-LOC
Bay I-LOC
in O
the O
summer O
and O
fall O
of O
1983 O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O
It O
is O
unclear O
if O
Robinson B-PER
and O
Scott B-PER
have O
attorneys O
at O
this O
time O
. O
DNA O
evidence O
leads O
to O
exoneration O
and O
new O
conviction O
In O
2018 O
, O
Warren’s B-PER
office O
created O
a O
Conviction B-ORG
Review I-ORG
Unit I-ORG
to O
help O
overturn O
and O
prevent O
wrongful O
convictions O
. O
Two O
years O
later O
, O
Robert B-PER
DuBoise I-PER
, O
who O
spent O
37 O
years O
in O
prison O
for O
Grams’ B-PER
rape O
and O
murder O
, O
was O
exonerated O
. O
“ O
Our O
investigation O
found O
DNA O
evidence O
that O
established O
Robert B-PER
did O
not O
murder O
Barbara B-PER
Grams I-PER
; O
however O
, O
that O
DNA O
evidence O
did O
provide O
new O
leads O
and O
launched O
a O
fresh O
investigation O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O
The O
DNA O
sample O
that O
did O
not O
contain O
material O
from O
DuBoise B-PER
was O
run O
through O
a O
national O
database O
containing O
DNA O
samples O
of O
convicted O
felons O
and O
led O
investigators O
to O
Scott B-PER
and O
Robinson B-PER
, O
who O
were O
already O
serving O
life O
sentences O
in O
a O
Florida B-LOC
prison O
for O
a O
murder O
they O
committed O
in O
Pinellas B-LOC
County I-LOC
in O
October O
of O
1983 O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O
With O
that O
information O
, O
investigators O
were O
able O
to O
build O
a O
case O
for O
Grams’ B-PER
murder O
and O
open O
a O
cold O
case O
investigation O
into O
Lansen’s B-PER
murder O
. O
At O
the O
time O
of O
DuBoise’s B-PER
trial O
, O
there O
wasn’t O
any O
physical O
or O
circumstantial O
evidence O
connecting O
DuBoise B-PER
to O
the O
attack O
, O
according O
to O
The B-ORG
Florida I-ORG
Innocence I-ORG
Project I-ORG
. O

Before O
his O
conviction O
, O
he O
was O
transported O
to O
Hillsborough B-LOC
County I-LOC
Jail O
. O
A O
jailhouse O
informant O
who O
spoke O
with O
DuBoise B-PER
later O
testified O
falsely O
that O
DuBoise B-PER
had O
confessed O
to O
the O
crime O
during O
his O
jail O
stay O
, O
The O
Florida B-LOC
Innocence B-ORG
Project I-ORG
said O
. O
“ O
I O
am O
sad O
for O
the O
families O
who O
have O
waited O
so O
long O
to O
get O
true O
closure O
, O
DuBoise B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
Friday O
. O
“ O
I O
spent O
37 O
years O
imprisoned O
for O
a O
crime O
I O
was O
totally O
innocent O
. O

This O
is O
what O
happens O
when O
the O
police O
focus O
on O
the O
wrong O
person O
, O
make O
up O
evidence O
to O
fit O
their O
theory O
and O
don’t O
investigate O
to O
find O
the O
truth O
. O
Lives O
are O
ruined O
and O
communities O
are O
less O
safe O
. O

Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
has O
posed O
the O
question O
with O
which O
America B-LOC
may O
have O
to O
wrestle O
for O
months O
to O
come O
: O
if O
there O
is O
evidence O
that O
ex-President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
committed O
crimes O
in O
seeking O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
, O
what O
message O
will O
it O
send O
if O
he’s O
not O
charged O
? O
The O
Wyoming B-LOC
representative O
, O
who O
serves O
as O
the O
vice O
chair O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
investigating O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
issued O
what O
was O
effectively O
a O
challenge O
to O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
as O
CNN B-ORG
exclusively O
reported O
on O
Thursday O
that O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
are O
in O
talks O
with O
its O
prosecutors O
– O
in O
the O
most O
concrete O
step O
yet O
toward O
the O
former O
commander-in-chief O
. O
The O
news O
was O
the O
latest O
sign O
that O
the O
department O
, O
criticized O
for O
months O
for O
moving O
too O
slowly O
to O
investigate O
Trump’s B-PER
election O
stealing O
effort O
and O
his O
incitement O
of O
the O
mob O
that O
invaded O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
, O
is O
moving O
with O
speed O
and O
broadening O
its O
scope O
– O
though O
there O
remains O
no O
indication O
when O
or O
even O
if O
the O
former O
President O
will O
be O
charged O
in O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department’s I-ORG
probe O
. O
Cheney B-PER
argued O
in O
an O
interview O
with O
CNN’s B-ORG
Kasie B-PER
Hunt I-PER
taped O
Wednesday O
that O
if O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
failed O
to O
act O
in O
the O
face O
of O
evidence O
of O
criminal O
wrongdoing O
, O
it O
would O
be O
disastrous O
to O
the O
idea O
of O
America B-LOC
itself O
. O
“ O
Understanding O
what O
it O
means O
if O
the O
facts O
and O
the O
evidence O
are O
there O
, O
and O
they O
decide O
not O
to O
prosecute O
– O
how O
do O
we O
then O
call O
ourselves O
a O
nation O
of O
laws O
? O
,” O
said O
Cheney B-PER
, O
one O
of O
two O
Republicans O
on O
the O
panel O
. O
CNN B-ORG
senior O
legal O
analyst O
Preet B-PER
Bharara I-PER
said O
that O
the O
fact O
that O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
are O
already O
in O
communication O
with O
the O
investigation O
suggests O
they O
believe O
he O
may O
have O
some O
significant O
exposure O
down O
the O
line O
. O
“ O
Actively O
engaging O
suggests O
to O
me O
that O
the O
lawyers O
think O
that O
there O
is O
some O
jeopardy O
here O
and O
they O
should O
engage O
sooner O
rather O
than O
later O
, O
” O
Bharara B-PER
, O
a O
former O
US B-ORG
attorney O
for O
the O
Southern O
District O
of O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
, O
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Wolf B-PER
Blitzer I-PER
. O
Bharara B-PER
cautioned O
that O
the O
investigation O
could O
last O
a O
long O
time O
and O
that O
a O
decision O
“ O
about O
whether O
or O
not O
to O
charge O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
” O
could O
occur O
many O
months O
from O
now O
. O
Learning O
what O
Trump B-PER
was O
saying O
and O
thinking O
as O
his O
mob O
smashed O
its O
way O
into O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
and O
during O
his O
prior O
schemes O
designed O
to O
overturn O
his O
election O
loss O
could O
help O
establish O
whether O
the O
ex-President O
acted O
with O
corrupt O
intent O
and O
could O
be O
at O
risk O
of O
being O
criminally O
charged O
. O
More O
immediately O
, O
the O
dialogue O
with O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
could O
also O
be O
the O
curtain O
raiser O
to O
what O
may O
well O
be O
a O
critical O
legal O
fight O
over O
the O
extent O
to O
which O
Trump B-PER
– O
as O
an O
ex-President O
– O
can O
assert O
executive O
privilege O
over O
conversations O
and O
advice O
he O
received O
while O
in O
office O
. O
