Democrats O
need O
all O
50 O
of O
their O
senators O
to O
be O
present O
and O
vote O
in O
favor O
of O
the O
bill O
with O
Vice O
President O
Kamala B-PER
Harris I-PER
casting O
the O
tie-breaking O
vote O
, O
as O
all O
Republicans O
are O
expected O
to O
vote O
against O
the O
deal O
. O

Manchin O
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Jake O
Tapper B-PER
on O
“State O
of O
the O
Union” O
Sunday O
he O
hopes O
the O
legislation O
passes O
before O
the O
August O
recess. O

I O
think O
it’s O
a O
great O
piece O
of O
legislation O
and O
on O
normal O
times O
, O
my O
Republican B-ORG
colleagues O
would O
be O
for O
something O
such O
as O
this O
. O

We’ve O
basically O
paid O
down O
debt O
, O
(which) O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

We’ve O
accelerated O
permitting O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

And O
we’ve O
increased O
production O
of O
energy O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

We’ve O
done O
things O
that O
we O
should O
be O
doing O
together O
, O
Manchin B-PER
said O
. O

Will O
Democrats O
be O
united O
. O

All O
eyes O
in O
Washington B-LOC
are O
on O
Arizona B-LOC
Democratic O
Sen. O
Kyrsten B-PER
Sinema I-PER
, O
a O
key O
moderate O
, O
who O
has O
not O
yet O
weighed O
in O
on O
the O
bill O
. O

She O
has O
previously O
raised O
concerns O
about O
taxes O
on O
carried O
interest O
, O
which O
would O
raise O
$14 O
billion O
under O
the O
deal O
. O

Sinema O
was O
not O
part O
of O
negotiations O
for O
the O
current O
package O

Asked O
about O
getting O
the O
support O
of O
his O
Arizona B-LOC
colleague O
, O
Manchin B-PER
said O
on O
Sunday O
, O
“ O
We O
work O
very O
close O
together O
on O
so O
many O
things O
, O
and O
she O
has O
so O
much O
in O
this O
piece O
of O
legislation O
. O
” O

She’s O
formed O
quite O
a O
bit O
of O
and O
worked O
on O
it O
very O
hard O
.” O
“ O

I O
think O
that O
basically O
when O
she O
looks O
at O
the O
bill O
and O
sees O
the O
whole O
spectrum O
of O
what O
we’re O
doing O
… O
hopefully O
she O
will O
be O
positive O
about O
it O
, O
but O
she’ll O
make O
her O
decision O
and O
I O
respect O
that O
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O

How O
did O
this O
come O
together O
? O

Read O
this O
report O
from O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Capitol B-LOC
Hill I-LOC
team O
. O

The O
climate O
and O
tax O
deal O
came O
together O
in O
almost O
complete O
secret O
, O
catching O
many O
by O
surprise O
when O
it O
was O
announced O
. O

Schumer B-PER
and O
Manchin B-PER
have O
been O
in O
revived O
talks O
since O
July O
18 O
and O
locked O
down O
a O
deal O
last O
Wednesday O
, O
according O
to O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
. O

Manchin B-PER
had O
thrown O
cold O
water O
on O
doing O
tax O
and O
energy O
provisions O
as O
part O
of O
the O
deal O
, O
but O
ultimately O
agreed O
to O
it O
. O

CNN’s B-ORG
Devan B-PER
Cole, I-PER
Daniella B-PER
Diaz, I-PER
Tami B-PER
Luhby I-PER
and O
Katie B-PER
Lobosco I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report. O

Editor’s O
Note: O
Dean B-PER
Obeidallah, I-PER
a O
former O
attorney, O
is O
the O
host O
of O
SiriusXM B-ORG
radio’s O
daily O
program O
“The O
Dean B-PER
Obeidallah I-PER
Show” O
and O
a O
columnist O
for O
The O
Daily B-ORG
Beast. I-ORG

Follow O
him O
@DeanObeidallah B-PER

Read O
more O
opinion O
on O
CNN B-ORG

The O
Conservative B-ORG
Political I-ORG
Action I-ORG
Conference I-ORG
made O
it O
clear O
over O
the O
weekend O
in O
Texas B-LOC
whose O
side O
it’s O
on O
in O
the O
fight O
against O
domestic O
terrorism O

First, O
it O
featured O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
as O
its O
star O
speaker. O

Here O
is O
a O
man O
who O
not O
only O
was O
allegedly O
involved O
in O
waging O
an O
attempted O
coup O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
but O
who O
also O
summoned O
his O
supporters O
to O
Washington B-LOC
on O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
for O
a O
“wild” O
protest O
. O

Then O
on O
that O
fateful O
day O
, O
he O
inflamed O
them O
with O
his O
words O
and O
directed O
them O
to O
head O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Capitol I-ORG
to O
“Stop O
the O
Steal.” O

And O
as O
some O
of O
his O
supporters O
brutally O
beat O
police O
officers O
, O
built O
gallows O
while O
chanting O
to O
hang O
his O
vice O
president O
and O
broke O
into O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
to O
try O
to O
stop O
Congress B-ORG
from O
certifying O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
win O
, O
Trump B-PER
did O
nothing O
for O
more O
than O
three O
hours O
to O
stop O
the O
attack O
. O

Trump B-PER
has O
denied O
responsibility O
for O
the O
insurrection O
. O

CPAC B-ORG
also O
welcomed O
as O
a O
speaker O
Viktor B-PER
Orban I-PER
, O
Hungary’s B-LOC
autocratic O
Prime O
Minister O
, O
who O
a O
week O
earlier O
had O
given O
a O
speech O
in O
which O
he O
declared O
that O
in O
Europe B-LOC
“ O
we O
do O
not O
want O
to O
become O
peoples O
of O
mixed O
race O
. O
” O

Those O
words O
prompted O
a O
longtime O
Orban B-PER
aide O
to O
resign O
, O
slamming O
his O
remarks O
as O
“pure O
Nazi O
text O
.” O

But O
the O
cherry O
on O
the O
sundae O
was O
a O
CPAC B-ORG
panel O
showcasing O
Brandon B-PER
Straka I-PER
, O
who O
pleaded O
guilty O
to O
disorderly O
conduct O
in O
the O
January O
6 O
attack O
, O
as O
part O
of O
a O
larger O
exhibit O
designed O
to O
elicit O
sympathy O
for O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
attackers O
still O
in O
prison O
. O

As O
part O
of O
his O
guilty O
plea O
to O
a O
misdemeanor O
, O
Straka B-PER
admitted O
to O
urging O
the O
violent O
mob O
to O
rip O
a O
riot O
shield O
from O
a O
police O
officer O
, O
shouting O
, O
“Take O
it O
: O
! O

Take O
it!,” O

The O
Washington B-ORG
Post I-ORG
reported O

Straka B-PER
ultimately O
received O
90 O
days’ O
home O
confinement O
and O
three O
years’ O
probation O
after O
agreeing O
to O
cooperate O
with O
law O
enforcement O

But O
just O
last O
week O
, O
a O
federal O
judge O
slammed O
Straka B-PER
for O
making O
public O
comments O
inconsistent O
with O
his O
statements O
to O
investigators O
, O
raising O
the O
possibility O
that O
he O
could O
be O
charged O
with O
lying O
to O
federal O
authorities O
, O
NPR B-ORG
reported O
. O

Nevertheless O
, O
Straka O
appeared O
on O
a O
CPAC B-ORG
panel O
with O
Republican O
Rep. O
Andy B-PER
Biggs I-PER
of O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
criticizing O
the O
House O
member O
for O
not O
doing O
more O
to O
help O
protesters O
who O
have O
been O
arrested O
in O
connection O
with O
the O
January O
6 O
riot O
and O
eliciting O
jeers O
from O
the O
audience O
for O
the O
lawmaker O
, O
according O
to O
Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
. O

In O
an O
apparent O
effort O
to O
get O
into O
the O
crowd’s O
good O
graces O
, O
according O
to O
Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
and O
video O
of O
the O
event O
, O
Biggs B-PER
then O
vowed O
to O
“ O
start O
defunding O
some O
of O
these O
bad O
agencies O
, O
the O
FBI B-ORG
, O
the O
DOJ B-ORG
.” O

Yes O
, O
a O
GOP O
member O
of O
Congress B-ORG
reportedly O
told O
the O
crowd O
that O
he O
would O
begin O
to O
defund O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
and O
FBI B-ORG
for O
having O
the O
audacity O
to O
prosecute O
January O
6 O
attackers O
. O

Then O
came O
the O
pièce O
de O
résistance O
: O
a O
headline-grabbing O
, O
jaw-dropping O
exhibit O
that O
featured O
a O
prison O
cell O
that O
housed O
a O
person O
dressed O
in O
an O
orange O
jumpsuit O
, O
wearing O
a O
red O
“Make O
America B-LOC
Great O
Again” O
cap O
. O

CPAC B-ORG
attendees O
were O
invited O
to O
put O
on O
headsets O
to O
listen O
to O
actual O
messages O
from O
the O
January O
6 O
attackers O

A O
CPAC B-ORG
representative O
told O
BuzzFeed B-ORG
News I-ORG
that O
the O
#Walk O
Away O
group O
founded O
by O
Straka B-PER
ran O
the O
booth O

In O
the O
past O
, O
CPAC B-ORG
has O
reportedly O
banned O
a O
booth O
from O
an O
atheist O
organization O
and O
the O
Log B-ORG
Cabin I-ORG
Republicans I-ORG
, O
an O
LGBT O
group O
, O
as O
an O
event O
sponsor O
. O

On O
Thursday O
, O
an O
actor O
played O
the O
prisoner O
, O
complete O
with O
tears O
as O
he O
stood O
in O
front O
of O
a O
chalkboard O
that O
read O
, O
“ O
Where O
is O
Everyone O
?” O

But O
on O
Friday O
– O
in O
a O
surreal O
case O
of O
life O
imitating O
art O
– O
Straka O
portrayed O
the O
prisoner O
in O
the O
cell O

Vice B-ORG
News I-ORG
reported O
that O
the O
line O
to O
see O
Straka O
stretched O
clear O
to O
the O
back O
of O
the O
exhibit O
hall O

It O
wasn’t O
long O
before O
right-wing O
firebrand O
Rep. O
Marjorie B-PER
Taylor I-PER
Greene I-PER
– O
who O
has O
long O
called O
the O
jailed O
January O
6 O
attackers O
“political O
prisoners” O
– O
entered O
the O
fake O
jail O
cell O
and O
led O
a O
prayer O
for O
those O
still O
imprisoned O
for O
their O
role O
in O
the O
January O
6 O
attack O
. O

Let’s O
put O
politics O
aside O
and O
look O
at O
the O
facts O

January O
6 O
was O
an O
act O
of O
“ O
domestic O
terrorism O
,” O
as O
FBI B-ORG
Director O
Christopher B-PER
Wray I-PER
testified O
before O
Congress B-ORG
. O

Just O
as O
we O
would O
call O
anyone O
involved O
in O
the O
far O
deadlier O
September B-LOC
11 O
, O
2001 O
, O
attacks O
“ O
terrorists O
” O
– O
we O
would O
do O
the O
same O
for O
anyone O
who O
played O
a O
role O
on O
January B-LOC
6 O
. O

For O
some O
people O
, O
the O
idea O
of O
calling O
a O
white O
American O
a O
terrorist O
is O
uncomfortable O
, O
but O
there’s O
no O
place O
for O
timidity O
when O
the O
stakes O
are O
this O
high O
. O

Those O
behind O
the O
mock O
jail O
cell O
at O
CPAC B-ORG
want O
you O
to O
have O
sympathy O
for O
the O
worst O
of O
the O
January B-LOC
6 O
attackers O

The O
overwhelmingly O
majority O
of O
people O
arrested O
in O
connection O
with O
the O
January B-LOC
6 O
attack O
have O
been O
granted O
bail O
, O
according O
to O
PolitiFact B-ORG
. O

Those O
defendants O
still O
in O
jail O
deserve O
to O
be O
there O
because O
of O
the O
severity O
of O
crimes O
with O
which O
they O
have O
been O
charged O

Among O
them O
are O
members O
of O
the O
Oath B-ORG
Keepers I-ORG
militia O
and O
the O
Proud B-ORG
Boys I-ORG
– O
some O
of O
whom O
were O
charged O
with O
“seditious O
conspiracy” O
– O
and O
others O
who O
are O
accused O
of O
brutally O
beating O
police O
officers O
and O
other O
heinous O
acts O
. O

Judges O
hearing O
the O
charges O
against O
these O
suspects O
have O
deemed O
that O
they O
pose O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
community O
were O
they O
to O
be O
released O
on O
bail O

Imagine O
if O
about O
18 O
months O
after O
a O
terrorist O
attack O
, O
a O
booth O
at O
a O
Democratic B-ORG
event O
attempted O
to O
elicit O
sympathy O
for O
those O
arrested O
for O
their O
role O
in O
a O
deadly O
strike O
on O
our O
nation O
! O

Critics O
would O
lash O
out O
at O
Democrats B-ORG
as O
unpatriotic O
Americans O
who O
support O
terrorism O
. O

And O
they O
would O
be O
right O
to O
do O
so O

That’s O
the O
same O
revulsion O
the O
vile O
display O
at O
CPAC B-ORG
deserves O
from O
all O
of O
us O

الإمارات B-LOC
تدعم O
مبدأ O
"الصين B-LOC
الواحدة" I-LOC
وتؤكد: O
قلقون O
من O
"الزيارات O
الاستفزازية" O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

Vulnerabilities O
in O
software O
that O
TV O
and O
radio O
networks O
around O
the O
country O
use O
to O
transmit O
emergency O
alerts O
could O
allow O
a O
hacker O
to O
broadcast O
fake O
messages O
over O
the O
alert O
system O
, O
a O
Federal B-ORG
Emergency I-ORG
Management I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
official O
tells O
CNN B-ORG
. O

A O
cybersecurity O
researcher O
provided O
FEMA B-ORG
with O
“compelling O
evidence O
to O
suggest O
certain O
unpatched O
and O
unsecured O
EAS O
[Emergency O
Alert O
System] O
devices O
are O
indeed O
vulnerable,” O
said O
Mark B-PER
Lucero, I-PER
the O
chief O
engineer O
for O
Integrated B-ORG
Public I-ORG
Alert I-ORG
& I-ORG
Warning I-ORG
System, I-ORG
the O
national O
system O
that O
state O
and O
local O
officials O
use O
to O
send O
urgent O
alerts O
about O
natural O
disasters O
or O
child O
abductions. O

The O
agency O
this O
week O
urged O
operators O
of O
the O
devices O
to O
update O
their O
software O
to O
address O
the O
issue O
, O
saying O
that O
the O
false O
alerts O
could O
in O
theory O
be O
issued O
over O
TV O
, O
radio O
and O
cable O
networks O
. O

The O
advisory O
did O
not O
say O
that O
alerts O
sent O
over O
text O
messages O
were O
affected O

There O
is O
no O
evidence O
that O
malicious O
hackers O
have O
exploited O
the O
vulnerabilities O
, O
Lucero B-PER
said O

It’s O
unclear O
how O
many O
emergency O
alert O
system O
devices O
are O
running O
the O
vulnerable O
software O

Ken B-PER
Pyle I-PER
, O
the O
cybersecurity O
researcher O
who O
discovered O
the O
issue O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
he O
acquired O
several O
of O
the O
EAS O
devices O
independently O
and O
found O
poor O
security O
controls O
. O

He O
shared O
an O
example O
of O
a O
fake O
alert O
he O
crafted O
, O
but O
did O
not O
send O
, O
that O
declared O
a O
“civil O
emergency” O
for O
certain O
counties O
and O
areas O
in O
the O
US B-LOC

TV O
and O
radio O
networks O
own O
and O
operate O
the O
equipment O
and O
transmit O
the O
emergency O
alerts O
but O
they O
are O
drafted O
by O
local O
authorities O

Digital B-ORG
Alert I-ORG
Systems I-ORG
, O
Inc. O
, O
the O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
-based O
firm O
that O
makes O
the O
emergency-alert O
software O
, O
said O
that O
Pyle B-PER
first O
reported O
the O
vulnerabilities O
to O
the O
firm O
in O
2019 O
, O
at O
which O
time O
the O
firm O
issued O
updated O
software O
to O
address O
the O
issue O
. O

However O
, O
Pyle B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
subsequent O
versions O
of O
the O
Digital O
Alert O
Systems O
software O
were O
still O
susceptible O
to O
some O
of O
the O
security O
issues O
he O
discovered O
. O

We O
take O
all O
security O
reports O
very O
seriously O
, O
Ed B-PER
Czarnecki I-PER
, O
Digital B-ORG
Alert I-ORG
Systems’ I-ORG
vice O
president O
of O
global O
and O
government O
affairs O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

He O
added O
that O
the O
firm O
will O
examine O
future O
software O
releases O
for O
any O
issues O
reported O
by O
Pyle O

The O
vast O
majority O
of O
our O
users O
have O
been O
very O
good O
at O
keeping O
up O
with O
software O
updates O
, O
” O
Czarnecki B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
that O
users O
can O
further O
mitigate O
the O
issue O
by O
ensuring O
the O
device O
is O
protected O
by O
a O
firewall O
. O

Seeing O
the O
breakdown O
of O
law O
enforcement O
communications O
in O
the O
days O
before O
the O
January O
6 O
2021 O
, O
attack O
on O
the O
US B-ORG
Capitol I-ORG
motivated O
Pyle B-PER
to O
dig O
further O
into O
the O
security O
of O
those O
types O
of O
communications O
, O
he O
said O
. O

It’s O
a O
big O
critical O
infrastructure O
problem O
everyone O
needs O
to O
own O
,” O
said O
Pyle O
, O
who O
is O
a O
partner O
at O
security O
firm O
CYBIR B-ORG
. O

He O
will O
demonstrate O
his O
research O
next O
week O
in O
Las B-LOC
Vegas I-LOC
at O
DEF B-ORG
CON I-ORG
, O
one O
of O
the O
world’s O
biggest O
hacking O
conferences O
. O

The O
misuse O
of O
emergency O
alerts O
can O
create O
panic O

In O
2018 O
, O
an O
employee O
of O
a O
Hawaii B-ORG
Emergency I-ORG
Management I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
was O
supposed O
to O
test O
the O
alert O
system O
but O
instead O
sent O
actual O
text O
messages O
to O
the O
cellphones O
of O
Hawaiian B-LOC
residents O
and O
tourists O
about O
a O
supposed O
incoming O
ballistic O
missile O
that O
told O
them O
to O
“SEEK O
IMMEDIATE O
SHELTER.” O

Editor’s O
Note: O
A O
version O
of O
this O
story O
first O
appeared O
in O
CNN’s B-ORG
Meanwhile O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
newsletter, O
a O
three-times-a-week O
look O
inside O
the O
region’s O
biggest O
stories. O

Sign O
up O
here O

One O
of O
the O
most O
important O
aspects O
of O
the O
weekend’s O
short O
but O
violent O
conflict O
between O
Israel B-LOC
and O
the O
Palestinian B-ORG
Islamic I-ORG
Jihad I-ORG
( O
PIJ O
) O
was O
what O
didn’t O
happen O
: O
Hamas’ O
involvement O

A O
ceasefire O
between O
Israel B-LOC
and O
the O
PIJ B-ORG
over O
Gaza B-LOC
that O
went O
into O
effect O
at O
11:30 O
p.m. O
local O
time O
( O
4:30 O
p.m. O
ET O
) O
Sunday O
appeared O
to O
be O
holding O
almost O
24 O
hours O
later O

The O
conflict O
led O
to O
the O
death O
of O
at O
least O
44 O
militants O
and O
civilians O
in O
Gaza B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
information O
from O
the O
Palestinian B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
of I-ORG
Health I-ORG
. O

Fifteen O
of O
the O
dead O
were O
children O

Israel B-LOC
insists O
most O
of O
those O
killed O
were O
militants O
, O
and O
that O
several O
civilians O
were O
killed O
by O
failed O
militant O
rocket O
launches O
. O

Hamas B-ORG
, O
the O
militant O
group O
that O
runs O
Gaza B-LOC
, O
expressed O
support O
for O
the O
PIJ’s O
actions O
. O

But O
it O
kept O
its O
much O
larger O
and O
more O
powerful O
arsenal O
of O
rockets O
out O
of O
the O
equation O
, O
while O
Israel’s B-LOC
military O
made O
it O
clear O
from O
the O
outset O
they O
were O
focusing O
solely O
on O
PIJ O
targets O
. O

That O
kept O
the O
conflict O
from O
spiraling O
into O
a O
larger O
, O
more O
dangerous O
confrontation O
, O
and O
closer O
to O
what O
happened O
during O
the O
11-day O
war O
in O
May B-LOC
2021 O
. O

So O
why O
not O
get O
involved O
? O

According O
to O
analysts O
and O
Israeli B-LOC
officials O
, O
one O
reason O
is O
the O
fact O
it O
is O
still O
only O
15 O
months O
since O
the O
2021 O
conflict O
that O
led O
to O
considerable O
damage O
and O
death O
in O
Gaza B-LOC
. O

Palestinians O
there O
are O
still O
rebuilding O
their O
homes O
, O
and O
Hamas B-ORG
is O
rebuilding O
its O
arsenal O
. O

The O
Israeli B-LOC
government O
also O
believes O
its O
campaign O
of O
economic O
incentives O
– O
boosting O
the O
number O
of O
permits O
given O
to O
Gazans B-LOC
to O
cross O
into O
Israel B-LOC
for O
work O
– O
is O
succeeding O

Israel B-LOC
and O
Egypt B-LOC
have O
imposed O
a O
closure O
on O
Gaza B-LOC
since O
2007 O
, O
limiting O
access O
to O
the O
territory O
via O
land O
, O
air O
and O
sea O
, O
including O
tight O
restrictions O
on O
the O
movement O
of O
residents O
and O
the O
flow O
of O
goods O
. O

If O
rockets O
are O
fired O
, O
Israel B-LOC
closes O
the O
border O
and O
the O
thousands O
of O
Gazans O
with O
permits O
can’t O
work O
in O
Israel B-LOC
or O
get O
paid O
. O

On O
Monday O
, O
a O
senior O
Israeli B-LOC
diplomatic O
official O
said O
Hamas B-ORG
was O
“ O
an O
enemy O
not O
a O
partner O
… O
but O
there O
is O
cooperation O
we O
can O
do O
, O
predominantly O
through O
Egypt B-LOC
, O
to O
improve O
the O
situation O
in O
Gaza B-LOC
. O

For O
showing O
restraint O
, O
Hamas B-ORG
will O
expect O
to O
be O
rewarded O
. O

Lapid’s O
first O
big O
security O
test O
The O
weekend’s O
conflict O
was O
also O
the O
first O
major O
military O
test O
for O
interim O
Prime O
Minister O
Yair B-PER
Lapid I-PER

Unlike O
his O
predecessor O
Naftali B-PER
Bennett I-PER
, O
Lapid O
is O
not O
known O
for O
his O
military O
combat O
experience O
. O

But O
like O
US O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden’s I-PER
visit O
last O
month O
, O
it O
was O
another O
moment O
for O
Lapid B-PER
to O
look O
like O
a O
real O
prime O
minister O
— O
images O
Lapid B-PER
likely O
hopes O
Israelis O
remember O
as O
they O
had O
to O
the O
polls O
in O
November O
. O

The O
conflict O
also O
brought O
about O
another O
breakthrough O
, O
albeit O
on O
a O
somewhat O
smaller O
scale O
: O
former O
prime O
minister O
, O
now O
opposition O
leader O
Benjamin B-PER
Netanyahu I-PER
met O
with O
Lapid B-PER
on O
Sunday O
to O
receive O
a O
security O
briefing O
on O
the O
operation O
. O

It O
was O
his O
first O
security O
briefing O
since O
leaving O
power O
– O
even O
though O
by O
law O
it O
is O
supposed O
to O
be O
standard O
practice O
. O

Until O
this O
weekend O
, O
Netanyahu B-PER
had O
boycotted O
the O
meetings O
. O

After O
the O
meeting O
, O
Netanyahu B-PER
said O
he O
supported O
the O
operation O
and O
gave O
his O
“ O
full O
backing O
to O
the O
government O
, O
the O
IDF B-ORG
, O
and O
the O
security O
forces O
. O
” O

Parts O
of O
Gaza B-LOC
once O
again O
lie O
in O
rubble O
and O
the O
mourning O
continues O
for O
lost O
lives O
, O
but O
for O
everyday O
Israelis B-LOC
and O
Gazans B-LOC
, O
the O
conflict O
hasn’t O
led O
to O
a O
substantial O
change O
in O
the O
political O
situation O
on O
the O
ground O

The O
digest O
Russia B-LOC
envoy O
to O
Iran B-LOC
nuclear O
talks O
says O
they O
are O
“moving O
in O
right O
direction” O
Ambassador O
Mikhail B-PER
Ulyanov I-PER
, O
Russia’s B-LOC
chief O
negotiator O
in O
Vienna B-LOC
for O
talks O
aimed O
at O
reviving O
the O
Iran B-LOC
nuclear O
deal O
, O
on O
Sunday O
told O
media O
, O
“I O
cannot O
guarantee O
[anything] O
, O
but O
the O
impression O
is O
that O
we O
are O
moving O
in O
the O
right O
direction.” O

He O
said O
there O
were O
“minimal” O
unresolved O
issues, O
“just O
3 O
[or] O
4.” O

Putin B-PER
, O
Erdogan B-PER
agree O
to O
begin O
partial O
payment O
in O
rubles O
for O
Russian O
gas O
Bilateral O
talks O
in O
Sochi B-LOC
between O
Russian O
President O
Vladimir B-PER
Putin I-PER
and O
Turkish O
President O
Recep B-PER
Tayyip I-PER
Erdogan I-PER
included O
an O
agreement O
to O
pay O
Russia B-LOC
in O
rubles O
for O
partial O
gas O
supplies O

Russian O
Deputy O
Prime O
Minister O
Alexander B-PER
Novak I-PER
said O
the O
two O
presidents O
reached O
agreements O
on O
establishing O
a O
financial O
banking O
bloc O
“to O
enable O
commercial O
companies O
, O
Russian B-LOC
citizens O
, O
to O
pay O
during O
tourist O
trips O
and O
exchange O
money O
. O
” O

Iran B-LOC
city O
reaches O
53 O
degrees O
Celsius O
, O
hottest O
temperature O
in O
the O
world O
this O
year O
Abadan B-LOC
, O
Iran B-LOC
had O
a O
high O
temperature O
of O
53.0° O
C O
( O
127.4° O
F O
) O
Friday O
– O
the O
highest O
temperature O
recorded O
anywhere O
in O
the O
world O
in O
2022 O
, O
according O
to O
weather O
historian O
Maximiliano B-PER
Herrera I-PER
. O

What’s O
trending O
Kuwait B-LOC
: O
#Wage_rise_is_a_public_demand O
The O
citizens O
of O
one O
of O
the O
richest O
Arab O
countries O
are O
demanding O
a O
rise O
in O
wages O

Kuwaitis B-LOC
took O
to O
Twitter B-ORG
to O
express O
their O
frustration O
at O
the O
country’s O
economic O
situation O
, O
blaming O
official O
corruption O
and O
greed O
for O
alleged O
inequality O
in O
pay O
. O

Kuwaiti B-LOC
citizens O
are O
a O
minority O
in O
the O
country O
of O
4.2 O
million O
, O
making O
up O
just O
30% O
of O
the O
population O
, O
according O
to O
World B-ORG
Population I-ORG
Review I-ORG
. O

Most O
rely O
on O
government O
jobs O
to O
make O
a O
living O
. O

It’s O
inconceivable O
that O
a O
rich O
country O
like O
Kuwait B-LOC
that O
has O
a O
small O
number O
of O
people O
and O
the O
strongest O
currency O
in O
the O
world O
[ O
wouldn’t O
raise O
wages O
],” O
tweeted O
Mohammed B-PER
Al I-PER
Huwaishel I-PER
. O

The O
demands O
of O
the O
people O
must O
be O
met O
without O
conditions O
. O

Many O
Kuwaitis B-LOC
take O
government O
jobs O
– O
where O
pay O
can O
be O
up O
to O
28% O
higher O
than O
the O
private O
sector O
– O
because O
they O
either O
lack O
the O
necessary O
skills O
to O
work O
in O
the O
private O
sector O
or O
because O
some O
of O
those O
jobs O
are O
seen O
as O
menial O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Middle B-ORG
East I-ORG
Institute I-ORG
. O

Due O
to O
the O
benefits O
offered O
in O
government O
jobs O
, O
the O
private O
sector O
finds O
it O
difficult O
to O
lure O
Kuwaitis O
. O

According O
to O
the O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
public O
wages O
and O
benefits O
account O
for O
one-third O
of O
the O
government’s O
budget O
. O

The O
government O
set O
aside O
$72 O
billion O
in O
spending O
for O
its O
latest O
budget O

The O
World B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
warned O
in O
December O
that O
the O
government’s O
wage O
bill O
is O
unsustainable O
, O
saying O
that O
if O
the O
situation O
continues O
, O
the O
country’s O
financial O
reserves O
will O
be O
depleted O
. O

The O
nation O
has O
made O
the O
least O
progress O
among O
oil-rich O
Gulf B-LOC
Arab I-LOC
countries O
to O
reform O
its O
wage O
bill O
and O
has O
even O
increased O
hiring O
, O
it O
said O
. O

Another O
hashtag O
on O
Twitter B-ORG
called O
on O
the O
government O
to O
write O
off O
citizens’ O
debt O
, O
which O
is O
not O
without O
precedent O
. O

After O
the O
end O
of O
the O
1991 O
Gulf B-LOC
War I-LOC
, O
the O
government O
wrote O
off O
almost O
all O
consumer O
debt O
. O

By O
Mohammed B-PER
Abdelbary I-PER
Photo O
of O
the O
day O

Dry O
lightning O
has O
ignited O
some O
of O
the O
most O
destructive O
and O
costly O
wildfires O
in O
California B-LOC
history O
, O
a O
new O
study O
shows O
. O

Researchers O
found O
that O
over O
the O
past O
few O
decades O
, O
nearly O
half O
of O
the O
lightning O
strikes O
that O
hit O
the O
ground O
during O
spring O
and O
summer O
had O
been O
dry O
— O
there O
was O
no O
rain O
falling O
nearby O
. O

Dry O
lightning O
tends O
to O
happen O
in O
storms O
over O
areas O
of O
extreme O
drought O
, O
like O
the O
one O
California B-LOC
has O
been O
in O
for O
the O
past O
several O
years O
. O

The O
air O
is O
so O
dry O
that O
the O
rain O
evaporates O
before O
it O
hits O
the O
ground O

And O
the O
conditions O
that O
favor O
dry O
lightning O
are O
becoming O
more O
widespread O
and O
more O
frequent O
as O
the O
climate O
crisis O
fuel’s O
the O
West’s B-LOC
megadrought O

Dmitri B-PER
Kalashnikov I-PER
, O
lead O
author O
of O
the O
paper O
and O
a O
doctoral O
student O
at O
Washington B-LOC
State I-LOC
University I-LOC
, O
pointed O
to O
the O
wildfires O
that O
scorched O
California B-LOC
in O
2020 O
— O
particularly O
the O
August B-LOC
Complex I-LOC
Fire I-LOC
, O
the O
largest O
wildfire O
in O
the O
state’s O
history O
— O
as O
the O
motivation O
for O
the O
research O
. O

The O
August B-LOC
Complex I-LOC
Fire I-LOC
was O
originally O
more O
than O
three O
dozen O
fires O
that O
were O
sparked O
by O
dry O
lightning O

Those O
fires O
merged O
to O
become O
the O
largest O
in O
state O
history O
, O
burning O
more O
than O
a O
million O
acres O
in O
seven O
counties O
. O

California B-LOC
firefighters O
were O
exhausted O
that O
summer O
, O
CNN B-ORG
reported O
at O
the O
time O
, O
and O
they O
were O
particularly O
concerned O
about O
the O
potential O
for O
more O
and O
more O
fires O
sparked O
by O
dry O
lightning O
. O

All O
of O
the O
seven O
largest O
fires O
in O
California B-LOC
history O
have O
occurred O
in O
the O
past O
five O
years O
, O
and O
four O
of O
those O
were O
caused O
by O
lightning O
, O
according O
to O
data O
from O
Cal B-ORG
Fire I-ORG
. O

With O
warming O
and O
drying O
and O
drier O
vegetation O
, O
it O
doesn’t O
take O
a O
whole O
lot O
of O
lightning O
to O
start O
wildfires O
, O
” O
Kalashnikov B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

So O
even O
if O
, O
on O
the O
off O
chance O
, O
dry O
lightning O
decreases O
in O
the O
future O
, O
it O
just O
takes O
one O
outbreak O
one O
day O
in O
a O
year O
to O
cause O
a O
lot O
of O
fire O
and O
a O
lot O
of O
damage O
, O
if O
that O
were O
to O
happen O
. O

The O
study O
, O
funded O
by O
NASA B-ORG
and O
published O
Monday O
in O
the O
journal O
Environmental B-ORG
Research I-ORG
: O
Climate I-ORG
, O
is O
the O
first O
to O
develop O
long-term O
climatology O
of O
dry O
lightning O
in O
California B-LOC
, O
specifically O
focusing O
on O
Central B-LOC
and O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
, O
an O
area O
where O
lightning O
is O
a O
significant O
cause O
of O
wildfire O
. O

Dry O
lightning O
was O
found O
to O
occur O
most O
frequently O
in O
July B-LOC
and O
August B-LOC
, O
the O
researchers O
found O
, O
though O
lower O
elevation O
regions O
tended O
to O
see O
activity O
peak O
later O
in O
September B-LOC
and O
October B-LOC
, O
when O
vegetation O
is O
even O
drier O
. O

Researchers O
found O
that O
around O
Sacramento B-LOC
, O
San B-LOC
Francisco I-LOC
, O
Redwood B-LOC
, O
Sequoia B-LOC
and O
Yosemite B-LOC
, O
lightning O
sparked O
nearly O
30% O
, O
of O
fires O
which O
accounted O
for O
nearly O
50% O
of O
the O
total O
burned O
area O
. O

That O
is O
a O
lot O
of O
fires O
started O
by O
lightning O
, O
which O
are O
usually O
more O
difficult O
to O
attack O
because O
they O
tend O
to O
be O
more O
remote O
than O
human O
caused O
fires O
, O
Chris B-PER
Vagasky I-PER
, O
a O
meteorologist O
and O
lightning O
applications O
manager O
at O
Vaisala B-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

Vagasky B-PER
, O
who O
is O
not O
involved O
with O
the O
study O
, O
said O
the O
findings O
provide O
“excellent O
background” O
for O
weather O
forecasting O
and O
wildland O
management O
communities O
to O
better O
determine O
the O
conditions O
that O
are O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
to O
occur O
in O
advance O
. O

This O
really O
highlights O
the O
importance O
of O
understanding O
when O
dry O
lightning O
can O
be O
expected O
so O
that O
crews O
can O
be O
at O
the O
ready O
in O
the O
event O
of O
fire O
starting O
,” O
he O
said O
. O

So O
it’s O
good O
to O
see O
that O
there O
is O
now O
a O
study O
for O
this O
region O
of O
the O
US B-LOC
that O
shows O
not O
just O
the O
time O
of O
year O
, O
but O
the O
type O
of O
meteorological O
conditions O
that O
appear O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
. O

The O
research O
is O
just O
the O
first O
step O
, O
Vagasky B-PER
said O
. O

When O
thunderstorms O
do O
develop O
, O
first O
responders O
need O
to O
be O
aware O
that O
dry O
lightning O
conditions O
may O
be O
possible O
, O
but O
they O
will O
also O
have O
to O
be O
able O
to O
quickly O
respond O
to O
areas O
that O
are O
impacted O
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O

Kalashnikov B-PER
said O
there O
are O
still O
uncertainties O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
lightning O
research O
, O
whether O
dry O
lightning O
will O
occur O
more O
often O
as O
the O
climate O
changes O
. O

But O
one O
thing O
is O
certain O
, O
he O
said O
, O
as O
the O
Western B-LOC
drought O
persists O
, O
conditions O
are O
much O
more O
favorable O
for O
dry O
lightning O
to O
take O
shape O
. O

In O
just O
the O
last O
year O
alone O
, O
dry O
lightning O
has O
sparked O
deadly O
and O
destructive O
wildfires O
such O
as O
the O
Bootleg B-LOC
Fire I-LOC
in O
Oregon B-LOC
that O
burned O
more O
than O
400,000 O
acres O
. O

We O
know O
it’s O
getting O
hotter O
and O
drier O
— O
California B-LOC
is O
becoming O
hotter O
and O
drier O
,” O
Kalashnikov B-PER
said O
. O

So O
we O
can O
say O
that O
no O
matter O
what O
the O
trend O
in O
lightning O
is O
doing O
, O
when O
lightning O
happens O
with O
a O
hotter O
, O
drier O
atmosphere O
and O
vegetation O
, O
it’s O
just O
going O
to O
lead O
to O
more O
of O
a O
risk O
of O
these O
kinds O
of O
wildfire O
outbreaks O
like O
we O
saw O
in O
2020 O
. O

As O
firefighters O
battle O
the O
raging O
wildfire O
scorching O
a O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
forest O
and O
swallowing O
homes O
in O
its O
path O
, O
some O
residents O
forced O
to O
flee O
are O
left O
to O
grapple O
with O
the O
losses O
and O
an O
uncertain O
future O
. O

Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
resident O
Kayla B-PER
Dailey I-PER
, O
pregnant O
with O
her O
third O
child O
, O
spent O
her O
due O
date O
not O
prepping O
for O
the O
imminent O
delivery O
of O
her O
daughter O
, O
but O
fleeing O
the O
McKinney B-LOC
Fire I-LOC
, O
which O
she O
says O
ultimately O
engulfed O
her O
home O
. O

Dailey O
, O
her O
husband O
Levi O
, O
their O
two O
young O
sons O
, O
and O
the O
family’s O
roommate O
Dalton B-PER
Shute I-PER
relocated O
to O
Northern B-LOC
California I-LOC
from O
Indiana B-LOC
just O
4 O
months O
ago O
. O

Wildfires O
were O
not O
something O
the O
family O
had O
encountered O
before O

The O
blaze O
, O
the O
largest O
wildfire O
in O
California B-LOC
so O
far O
this O
year O
, O
broke O
out O
Friday O
afternoon O
in O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
National I-LOC
Forest I-LOC
near O
the O
California-Oregon B-LOC
border O
and O
grew O
rapidly O
over O
the O
weekend O
, O
fueled O
by O
explosive O
fire O
weather O
. O

The O
fire O
sprinted O
through O
dry O
brush O
and O
grass O
, O
scorching O
more O
than O
56,000 O
acres O
and O
forcing O
thousands O
to O
evacuate O
as O
the O
flames O
advanced O
on O
rural O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
communities O
. O

The O
fire O
had O
zero O
containment O
as O
of O
Tuesday O

However O
, O
in O
a O
hopeful O
sign O
, O
US B-ORG
Forest I-ORG
Service I-ORG
officials O
said O
lower O
temperatures O
and O
higher O
humidity O
levels O
– O
as O
well O
as O
rain O
over O
some O
areas O
of O
the O
fire O
– O
slowed O
down O
the O
fire’s O
spread O
and O
helped O
firefighters O
to O
make O
good O
progress O
Tuesday O
. O

I O
was O
really O
confused O
at O
first O
. O

I O
had O
never O
seen O
a O
forest O
fire O
,” O
explained O
Dailey B-PER
. O

Things O
just O
looked O
weird O
– O
there O
was O
this O
orange O
cast O
over O
the O
forest O
– O
and O
once O
I O
saw O
smoke O
rising O
from O
fire O
over O
top O
of O
the O
mountains O
, O
I O
just O
panicked O
.” O

The O
couple O
and O
their O
roommate O
immediately O
packed O
all O
into O
their O
small O
car O
, O
leaving O
room O
for O
little O
else O
. O

I O
could O
see O
nothing O
but O
smoke O
and O
the O
fire O
coming O
down O
the O
mountain O
,” O
said O
Dailey B-PER
, O
who O
later O
learned O
the O
wildfire O
started O
just O
3 O
miles O
away O
before O
it O
raced O
for O
their O
home O
, O
the O
flames O
feasting O
on O
their O
belongings O
, O
including O
everything O
set O
aside O
for O
the O
new O
baby O
. O

Now, O
4 O
days O
past O
her O
due O
date, O
Dailey B-PER
has O
yet O
another O
new O
worry: O
The O
nearest O
hospital O
has O
been O
evacuated O
and O
she’s O
been O
warned O
that O
she O
will O
likely O
need O
to O
make O
a O
2-hour O
trek O
through O
the O
mountains O
to O
give O
birth O
at O
a O
hospital O
in O
Medford, B-LOC
Oregon. B-LOC

It O
remains O
unclear O
how O
many O
homes O
were O
lost O
, O
but O
forest O
officials O
said O
“numerous” O
structures O
were O
destroyed O
around O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
community O
. O

Four O
people O
have O
been O
found O
dead O
in O
the O
fire’s O
burn O
area O
, O
including O
two O
who O
were O
in O
a O
burned O
vehicle O
in O
a O
home’s O
driveway O
and O
another O
two O
found O
at O
different O
homes O
along O
the O
same O
road O
, O
State B-LOC
Route I-LOC
96 O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Siskiyou B-LOC
County I-LOC
Sheriff’s B-ORG
Office I-ORG
. O

More O
than O
5,800 O
people O
have O
been O
evacuated O
due O
to O
the O
fire O
, O
Joel B-PER
Brumm I-PER
, O
a O
spokesperson O
for O
the O
Klamath B-LOC
National I-LOC
Forest I-LOC
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

We O
don’t O
even O
have O
an O
address O
anymore O
’ O
Valerie B-PER
Linfoot I-PER
and O
her O
husband O
, O
both O
retired O
forest O
firefighters O
, O
lost O
their O
home O
of O
more O
than O
three O
decades O
. O

We’ve O
fought O
fires O
and O
seen O
homes O
burn O
up O
and O
been O
in O
a O
place O
of O
being O
the O
firefighters O
there O
doing O
that O
work O
, O
but O
to O
have O
it O
happen O
to O
yourself O
, O
it’s O
just O
unimaginable O
, O
” O
Linfoot B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

I’m O
still O
overwhelmed O
that O
we’re O
the O
victims O
of O
this O
horrible O
, O
horrible O
convergence O
of O
weather O
and O
fire O
, O
which O
so O
many O
times O
we’ve O
seen O
other O
people O
suffer O
. O

Linfoot O
was O
out O
of O
town O
when O
the O
fire O
quickly O
advanced O
on O
her O
home O

Her O
husband O
, O
Chuck O
, O
saw O
the O
flames O
approach O
and O
packed O
up O
and O
left O

He O
drove O
to O
the O
community O
hall O
and O
looked O
back O
, O
seeing O
flames O
flanking O
their O
home O
on O
both O
sides O
. O

There’s O
nothing O
left O

It’s O
completely O
burned O
down O
to O
the O
dirt O

It’s O
just O
completely O
gone,” O
Linfoot B-PER
said. O

For O
Linfoot B-PER
, O
the O
hardest O
part O
is O
thinking O
about O
the O
irreplaceable O
items O
that O
were O
left O
behind O
when O
her O
home O
burned O
down O
. O

It’s O
a O
lot O
to O
take O
on O
in O
your O
mind O
thinking O
about O
those O
things O
that O
you’re O
never O
gonna O
get O
back,” O
she O
said. O
“ O

I O
left O
my O
wedding O
rings O
on O
my O
dresser O
and O
I’m O
never O
gonna O
get O
those O
back O

I O
have O
been O
married O
31 O
years O
and O
those O
are O
the O
rings O
that O
were O
put O
on O
my O
finger O
the O
day O
I O
said O
yes O

And O
they’re O
gone O
forever O
. O

Also O
lost O
in O
the O
fire O
were O
the O
ashes O
of O
Linfoot’s O
mother O
and O
grandmother O
, O
as O
well O
as O
her O
children’s O
baby O
photographs O
. O

We O
lost O
one O
of O
our O
sons O
about O
10 O
years O
ago O
in O
a O
motorcycle O
accident O

So O
the O
idea O
of O
not O
having O
any O
pictures… O
she O
said O

Linfoot O
has O
found O
comfort O
in O
the O
sense O
of O
community O
in O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
, O
and O
staying O
close O
with O
friends O
who O
are O
also O
dealing O
with O
the O
same O
losses O
. O

But O
she O
worries O
for O
her O
tightly O
knit O
community O
. O

It’s O
a O
small O
community O
and O
this O
is O
absolutely O
devastating O
to O
Klamath B-LOC
River I-LOC
,” O
she O
said O
. O

I O
don’t O
know O
how O
they’re O
gonna O
recover O

None O
of O
us O
are O
rich O
people O

We’re O
all O
hardworking O
and O
resilient O
people O
, O
but O
most O
people O
that O
were O
down O
there O
are O
middle O
class O
, O
regular O
working O
folks O
or O
retirees O
. O

She O
said O
her O
family O
is O
exploring O
their O
options O
, O
but O
don’t O
think O
they O
will O
be O
able O
to O
rebuild O
. O

The O
Linfoots B-PER
set O
up O
a O
GoFundMe B-ORG
page O
to O
help O
them O
with O
recovery O
and O
rebuilding O
. O

It’s O
hard O
to O
convey O
to O
somebody O
what O
it’s O
like O
to O
know O
that O
you O
have O
nothing O

One O
of O
the O
first O
things O
my O
husband O
said O
to O
me O
is O
, O
‘ O
we O
don’t O
even O
have O
an O
address O
anymore O
, O
’ O
” O
Linfoot B-PER
said O

Shute O
, O
the O
Dailey’s O
friend O
and O
roommate O
, O
is O
still O
struggling O
to O
process O
the O
situation O
. O

It O
still O
doesn’t O
feel O
real O
,” O
said O
Shute B-PER
, O
who O
lost O
his O
mom O
to O
a O
house O
fire O
when O
he O
was O
6 O
years O
old O
. O
“ O

I O
feel O
that O
sort O
of O
emptiness O
I O
felt O
when O
I O
was O
a O
child O
. O

Despite O
the O
challenges O
they’ve O
faced O
, O
Shute B-PER
and O
his O
roommates O
are O
confident O
that O
they O
will O
rebound O
, O
and O
are O
grateful O
for O
the O
help O
being O
offered O
by O
the O
community O
. O

A O
GoFundMe B-ORG
page O
has O
been O
set O
up O
to O
help O
him O
find O
a O
new O
home O
. O

We’re O
definitely O
not O
going O
to O
let O
this O
set O
us O
back,” O
Shute B-PER
said. O
“ O

Right O
now O
we’re O
learning O
to O
take O
it O
one O
day O
at O
a O
time O
and O
we’ll O
eventually O
be O
in O
a O
good O
place O
again O
. O

Two O
men O
serving O
life O
sentences O
for O
murder O
in O
a O
Florida B-LOC
prison O
have O
been O
linked O
to O
two O
other O
murders O
with O
the O
help O
of O
newly O
discovered O
DNA O
samples O
, O
which O
led O
to O
the O
exoneration O
of O
another O
man O
who O
wrongfully O
served O
37 O
years O
in O
prison O
for O
the O
rape O
and O
murder O
of O
Barbara B-PER
Grams I-PER
in O
1983 O
. O

Amos B-PER
Robinson I-PER
and O
Abron B-PER
Scott I-PER
allegedly O
raped O
and O
murdered O
19-year-old O
Grams O
, O
whose O
beaten O
body O
was O
found O
behind O
a O
dental O
office O
in O
Tampa B-LOC
Heights I-LOC
on O
August O
18 O
, O
1983 O
, O
Hillsborough B-LOC
County I-LOC
State O
Attorney O
Andrew B-PER
Warren I-PER
said O
during O
a O
news O
conference O
Thursday O
after O
he O
was O
suspended O
as O
the O
state O
attorney O
by O
Florida B-LOC
Gov O
. O
Ron B-PER
DeSantis I-PER
for O
his O
stance O
against O
criminalizing O
abortion O
providers O
. O

A O
grand O
jury O
indicted O
Robinson B-PER
and O
Scott B-PER
Thursday O
for O
the O
rape O
and O
murder O
of O
Linda B-PER
Lansen I-PER
, O
whose O
beaten O
body O
was O
found O
in O
Town B-LOC
and I-LOC
Country I-LOC
in O
July O
1983 O
in O
bushes O
with O
a O
gunshot O
wound O
to O
the O
head O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O

These O
two O
men O
not O
only O
robbed O
me O
, O
but O
they O
robbed O
a O
7-year-old O
little O
girl O
of O
her O
mother O
, O
said O
Linda B-PER
Sheffield I-PER
, O
Lansen’s O
niece O
, O
during O
Thursday’s O
news O
conference O
. O

When O
they’re O
initially O
murdered O
, O
the O
shock O
is O
there O
, O
but O
39 O
years O
later O
the O
shock O
is O
no O
longer O
there O
, O
she O
said O
. O
“ O

But O
the O
void O
stays O
, O
and O
the O
pain O
stays O
and O
the O
crying O
stays O
. O

It O
doesn’t O
go O
away O
. O

Robinson O
and O
Scott O
are O
also O
subjects O
of O
other O
cold O
case O
investigations O
from O
the O
same O
time O
period O
in O
the O
Tampa B-LOC
Bay I-LOC
area O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O

We O
now O
know O
that O
these O
two O
men O
carried O
out O
a O
sinister O
spree O
of O
rape O
and O
murder O
in O
Tampa B-LOC
Bay I-LOC
in O
the O
summer O
and O
fall O
of O
1983 O
Warren B-PER
said O

It O
is O
unclear O
if O
Robinson O
and O
Scott O
have O
attorneys O
at O
this O
time O
. O

DNA O
evidence O
leads O
to O
exoneration O
and O
new O
conviction O
In O
2018 O
, O
Warren’s B-PER
office O
created O
a O
Conviction O
Review O
Unit O
to O
help O
overturn O
and O
prevent O
wrongful O
convictions O
. O

Two O
years O
later O
, O
Robert B-PER
DuBoise I-PER
, O
who O
spent O
37 O
years O
in O
prison O
for O
Grams’ O
rape O
and O
murder O
, O
was O
exonerated O
. O

Our O
investigation O
found O
DNA O
evidence O
that O
established O
Robert B-PER
did O
not O
murder O
Barbara B-PER
Grams I-PER
; O
however O
, O
that O
DNA O
evidence O
did O
provide O
new O
leads O
and O
launched O
a O
fresh O
investigation O
, O
” O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O

The O
DNA O
sample O
that O
did O
not O
contain O
material O
from O
DuBoise O
was O
run O
through O
a O
national O
database O
containing O
DNA O
samples O
of O
convicted O
felons O
and O
led O
investigators O
to O
Scott B-PER
and O
Robinson B-PER
, O
who O
were O
already O
serving O
life O
sentences O
in O
a O
Florida B-LOC
prison O
for O
a O
murder O
they O
committed O
in O
Pinellas B-LOC
County I-LOC
in O
October O
of O
1983 O
, O
Warren B-PER
said O
. O

With O
that O
information O
, O
investigators O
were O
able O
to O
build O
a O
case O
for O
Grams’ O
murder O
and O
open O
a O
cold O
case O
investigation O
into O
Lansen’s O
murder O
. O

At O
the O
time O
of O
DuBoise’s O
trial O
, O
there O
wasn’t O
any O
physical O
or O
circumstantial O
evidence O
connecting O
DuBoise O
to O
the O
attack O
, O
according O
to O
The B-ORG
Florida I-ORG
Innocence I-ORG
Project I-ORG
. O

Before O
his O
conviction O
, O
he O
was O
transported O
to O
Hillsborough B-LOC
County I-LOC
Jail I-LOC
. O

A O
jailhouse O
informant O
who O
spoke O
with O
DuBoise B-PER
later O
testified O
falsely O
that O
DuBoise B-PER
had O
confessed O
to O
the O
crime O
during O
his O
jail O
stay O
, O
The O
Florida B-ORG
Innocence I-ORG
Project I-ORG
said O
. O

I O
am O
sad O
for O
the O
families O
who O
have O
waited O
so O
long O
to O
get O
true O
closure O
, O
DuBoise B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
Friday O
. O

I O
spent O
37 O
years O
imprisoned O
for O
a O
crime O
I O
was O
totally O
innocent O

This O
is O
what O
happens O
when O
the O
police O
focus O
on O
the O
wrong O
person O
, O
make O
up O
evidence O
to O
fit O
their O
theory O
and O
don’t O
investigate O
to O
find O
the O
truth O
. O

Lives O
are O
ruined O
and O
communities O
are O
less O
safe O
. O

Liz O
Cheney B-PER
has O
posed O
the O
question O
with O
which O
America B-LOC
may O
have O
to O
wrestle O
for O
months O
to O
come O
: O
if O
there O
is O
evidence O
that O
ex-President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
committed O
crimes O
in O
seeking O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
, O
what O
message O
will O
it O
send O
if O
he’s O
not O
charged O
? O

The O
Wyoming B-LOC
representative O
, O
who O
serves O
as O
the O
vice O
chair O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
investigating O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
issued O
what O
was O
effectively O
a O
challenge O
to O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
as O
CNN B-ORG
exclusively O
reported O
on O
Thursday O
that O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
are O
in O
talks O
with O
its O
prosecutors O
– O
in O
the O
most O
concrete O
step O
yet O
toward O
the O
former O
commander-in-chief O
. O

The O
news O
was O
the O
latest O
sign O
that O
the O
department O
, O
criticized O
for O
months O
for O
moving O
too O
slowly O
to O
investigate O
Trump’s B-PER
election O
stealing O
effort O
and O
his O
incitement O
of O
the O
mob O
that O
invaded O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
, O
is O
moving O
with O
speed O
and O
broadening O
its O
scope O
– O
though O
there O
remains O
no O
indication O
when O
or O
even O
if O
the O
former O
President O
will O
be O
charged O
in O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department’s I-ORG
probe O

Cheney O
argued O
in O
an O
interview O
with O
CNN’s B-ORG
Kasie B-PER
Hunt I-PER
taped O
Wednesday O
that O
if O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
failed O
to O
act O
in O
the O
face O
of O
evidence O
of O
criminal O
wrongdoing O
, O
it O
would O
be O
disastrous O
to O
the O
idea O
of O
America B-LOC
itself O
. O

Understanding O
what O
it O
means O
if O
the O
facts O
and O
the O
evidence O
are O
there O
, O
and O
they O
decide O
not O
to O
prosecute O
– O
how O
do O
we O
then O
call O
ourselves O
a O
nation O
of O
laws O
: O

said O
Cheney B-PER
, O
one O
of O
two O
Republicans O
on O
the O
panel O
. O

CNN B-ORG
senior O
legal O
analyst O
Preet B-PER
Bharara I-PER
said O
that O
the O
fact O
that O
Trump’s O
lawyers O
are O
already O
in O
communication O
with O
the O
investigation O
suggests O
they O
believe O
he O
may O
have O
some O
significant O
exposure O
down O
the O
line O
. O

Actively O
engaging O
suggests O
to O
me O
that O
the O
lawyers O
think O
that O
there O
is O
some O
jeopardy O
here O
and O
they O
should O
engage O
sooner O
rather O
than O
later O
, O
Bharara B-PER
, O
a O
former O
US O
attorney O
for O
the O
Southern B-LOC
District I-LOC
of O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
, O
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Wolf B-PER
Blitzer I-PER
. O

Bharara O
cautioned O
that O
the O
investigation O
could O
last O
a O
long O
time O
and O
that O
a O
decision O
“ O
about O
whether O
or O
not O
to O
charge O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
” O
could O
occur O
many O
months O
from O
now O

Learning O
what O
Trump B-PER
was O
saying O
and O
thinking O
as O
his O
mob O
smashed O
its O
way O
into O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
and O
during O
his O
prior O
schemes O
designed O
to O
overturn O
his O
election O
loss O
could O
help O
establish O
whether O
the O
ex-President O
acted O
with O
corrupt O
intent O
and O
could O
be O
at O
risk O
of O
being O
criminally O
charged O

More O
immediately O
, O
the O
dialogue O
with O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
could O
also O
be O
the O
curtain O
raiser O
to O
what O
may O
well O
be O
a O
critical O
legal O
fight O
over O
the O
extent O
to O
which O
Trump B-PER
– O
as O
an O
ex-President O
– O
can O
assert O
executive O
privilege O
over O
conversations O
and O
advice O
he O
received O
while O
in O
office O
. O

Such O
a O
case O
could O
go O
all O
the O
way O
to O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
and O
in O
itself O
break O
new O
legal O
ground O
since O
there O
is O
little O
litigation O
on O
the O
issue O
concerning O
out-of-office O
presidents O

Executive O
privilege O
is O
the O
custom O
under O
which O
private O
conversations O
and O
advice O
given O
to O
a O
president O
can O
remain O
private O
, O
especially O
from O
Congress B-ORG
, O
under O
the O
doctrine O
of O
separation O
of O
powers O
. O

A O
long O
legal O
duel O
The O
potential O
legal O
battle O
that O
Trump’s O
often O
risible O
privilege O
claims O
may O
spark O
could O
push O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
investigation O
into O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
ex-President’s O
likely O
2024 O
campaign O

This O
would O
risk O
yet O
another O
national O
political O
conflagration O
on O
top O
of O
many O
ignited O
by O
the O
45th O
President O

But O
more O
broadly O
, O
the O
latest O
news O
about O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
inquiry O
shows O
that O
there O
is O
an O
aggressive O
criminal O
probe O
that O
is O
narrowing O
in O
on O
a O
former O
President O
of O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
– O
a O
historical O
watershed O
– O
after O
an O
administration O
that O
is O
still O
tearing O
at O
the O
guardrails O
of O
the O
democratic O
system O
even O
out O
of O
office O
. O

This O
does O
not O
necessarily O
mean O
that O
Trump B-PER
will O
be O
charged O

A O
criminal O
investigation O
requires O
a O
far O
higher O
level O
of O
proof O
than O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
, O
which O
has O
painted O
a O
damning O
picture O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
actions O
ahead O
of O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
insurrection O
. O

And O
Trump B-PER
has O
made O
a O
life’s O
work O
of O
escaping O
legal O
scrapes O
and O
attempts O
to O
enforce O
accountability O

In O
his O
presidency O
alone O
, O
he O
wriggled O
free O
from O
the O
Russia B-LOC
investigation O
. O

He O
was O
the O
first O
President O
to O
be O
impeached O
twice O
by O
the O
House B-ORG
, O
although O
he O
wasn’t O
convicted O
in O
Senate B-ORG
trials O
or O
barred O
from O
future O
federal O
office O
. O

Still, O
according O
to O
the O
new O
CNN B-ORG
report, O
Trump’s O
team O
has O
warned O
him O
there O
may O
be O
indictments O
resulting O
from O
the O
grand O
jury O
investigation. O

And O
sources O
say O
the O
former O
President O
has O
asked O
his O
advisers O
whether O
he O
is O
in O
personal O
legal O
jeopardy O

New O
visibility O
into O
aggressive O
DOJ O
investigation O
Kimberly B-PER
Wehle I-PER
, O
a O
professor O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of O
Baltimore B-LOC
School O
of O
Law O
, O
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Erin B-PER
Burnett I-PER
that O
the O
contacts O
between O
Trump’s B-PER
lawyers O
and O
prosecutors O
pointed O
to O
a O
legal O
joust O
over O
the O
scope O
of O
executive O
privilege O
. O

I O
think O
that O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
is O
going O
to O
lose O
that O
battle O
, O
but O
the O
fact O
that O
his O
lawyers O
are O
engaging O
in O
this O
and O
telling O
him O
that O
he O
better O
beware O
, O
indictments O
could O
come O
, O
I O
think O
is O
very O
serious O
news O
for O
the O
former O
President O
but O
very O
good O
news O
for O
democracy O
, O
the O
rule O
of O
law O
and O
the O
Constitution O
, O
” O
Wehle B-PER
said O
. O

The O
latest O
revelations O
about O
the O
grand O
jury O
probe O
reinforce O
signs O
that O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
is O
acting O
with O
speed O
and O
expansive O
scope O
to O
investigate O
the O
insurrection O
following O
months O
of O
complaints O
– O
even O
from O
members O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
– O
that O
it O
did O
not O
appear O
to O
be O
that O
active O

This O
in O
turn O
raises O
the O
possibility O
that O
yet O
another O
significant O
period O
of O
national O
trauma O
caused O
by O
Trump B-PER
could O
lie O
ahead O

The O
former O
President O
has O
already O
claimed O
that O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration O
is O
weaponizing O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
to O
pursue O
its O
political O
enemies O
– O
a O
charge O
many O
critics O
leveled O
against O
him O
while O
he O
was O
still O
president O

Trump B-PER
would O
be O
sure O
to O
react O
to O
any O
signs O
that O
he O
is O
a O
target O
of O
the O
investigation O
or O
the O
possible O
indictments O
of O
those O
around O
him O
by O
claiming O
that O
he O
is O
being O
victimized O
by O
a O
politicized O
investigation O

Given O
his O
hold O
over O
his O
supporters O
, O
and O
a O
record O
of O
inciting O
violence O
, O
political O
tensions O
could O
become O
acute O
. O

All O
of O
this O
will O
sharpen O
the O
dilemma O
that O
Attorney O
General O
Merrick B-PER
Garland I-PER
would O
face O
if O
the O
evidence O
from O
the O
criminal O
probe O
suggests O
a O
prosecution O
is O
merited O

Indicting O
a O
former O
President O
– O
especially O
one O
running O
for O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
again O
– O
would O
incite O
a O
political O
storm O

This O
must O
raise O
the O
question O
of O
whether O
targeting O
Trump B-PER
would O
be O
in O
the O
broader O
national O
interest O
outside O
the O
criminal O
context O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
failing O
to O
pursue O
an O
ex-President O
accused O
of O
helping O
to O
foment O
a O
coup O
attempt O
could O
create O
an O
equally O
dangerous O
precedent O
and O
send O
a O
signal O
to O
future O
aberrant O
Presidents O
. O

Trump O
team O
discussed O
potential O
defense O
strategies O
The O
most O
significant O
news O
yet O
about O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
criminal O
probe O
follows O
unmistakable O
signs O
of O
a O
comprehensive O
and O
quickening O
investigation O

The O
department O
has O
, O
for O
instance O
, O
subpoenaed O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
Counsel O
Pat B-PER
Cipollone I-PER
and O
ex-deputy O
counsel O
Patrick B-PER
Philbin I-PER
. O

Last O
week O
, O
it O
emerged O
that O
two O
of O
former O
Vice O
President O
Mike B-PER
Pence’s I-PER
most O
senior O
aides O
, O
former O
chief O
of O
staff O
Marc B-PER
Short I-PER
and O
former O
counsel O
Greg B-PER
Jacob I-PER
, O
have O
already O
spoken O
to O
the O
grand O
jury O
. O

Investigators O
recently O
obtained O
a O
second O
warrant O
to O
search O
the O
cellphone O
of O
conservative O
lawyer O
John B-PER
Eastman I-PER
, O
one O
of O
the O
key O
figures O
in O
pushing O
Pence O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
by O
rejecting O
electors O
from O
important O
swing O
states O
. O

Federal O
investigators O
in O
June O
carried O
out O
a O
pre-dawn O
search O
of O
the O
home O
of O
former O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
official O
Jeffrey B-PER
Clark I-PER
, O
who O
invoked O
his O
Fifth O
Amendment O
right O
against O
self-incrimination O
more O
than O
100 O
times O
in O
a O
deposition O
to O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
. O

In O
the O
latest O
reporting O
by O
CNN’s B-ORG
Katelyn B-PER
Polantz I-PER
, O
Kara B-PER
Scannell I-PER
, O
Gabby B-PER
Orr I-PER
and O
Kristen B-PER
Holmes I-PER
, O
sources O
revealed O
that O
some O
members O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
legal O
team O
discussed O
possible O
defense O
strategies O
on O
at O
least O
two O
occasions O
in O
recent O
months O
. O

This O
comes O
as O
they O
await O
developments O
not O
solely O
in O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
investigation O
but O
in O
a O
separate O
probe O
by O
officials O
in O
Georgia B-LOC
into O
Trump’s B-PER
efforts O
to O
overturn O
Biden’s B-PER
election O
victory O
in O
the O
crucial O
state O
in O
2020 O

Trump B-PER
has O
grilled O
his O
attorneys O
on O
whether O
they O
actually O
believe O
he O
will O
face O
formal O
charges O
, O
but O
he O
has O
expressed O
skepticism O
that O
he O
will O
be O
indicted O
, O
one O
of O
the O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
said O

The O
CNN B-ORG
team O
also O
reveals O
that O
Trump B-PER
has O
ignored O
advice O
from O
advisers O
to O
avoid O
speaking O
to O
former O
and O
current O
aides O
who O
have O
become O
entangled O
in O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
probe O
and O
could O
be O
drawn O
in O
by O
the O
criminal O
investigation O

When O
it O
comes O
to O
the O
issue O
of O
executive O
privilege O
, O
historical O
precedent O
could O
work O
against O
the O
former O
President O
. O

During O
the O
Watergate O
scandal O
, O
then-President O
Richard B-PER
Nixon I-PER
asserted O
executive O
privilege O
to O
try O
to O
prevent O
the O
handover O
of O
incriminating O
audio O
tapes O
. O

But O
in O
a O
ruling O
that O
could O
be O
significant O
in O
Trump’s B-PER
case O
, O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
said O
that O
executive O
privilege O
could O
not O
be O
used O
to O
thwart O
the O
administration O
of O
criminal O
justice O
. O

The O
House O
January O
6 O
committee O
did O
not O
litigate O
the O
question O
of O
Cipollone’s O
reluctance O
to O
talk O
about O
certain O
conversations O
with O
Trump B-PER
on O
the O
basis O
of O
executive O
privilege O

It O
is O
racing O
against O
a O
ticking O
clock O
since O
it O
is O
likely O
to O
be O
disbanded O
by O
pro-Trump O
Republicans O
in O
the O
House B-ORG
if O
control O
of O
the O
chamber O
changes O
after O
the O
midterm O
elections O
in O
November B-LOC

But O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
has O
the O
luxury O
of O
more O
time O
to O
conduct O
a O
legal O
fight O

And O
the O
possibility O
of O
a O
prolonged O
investigation O
is O
one O
reason O
many O
observers O
believe O
Trump B-PER
is O
leaning O
toward O
an O
early O
announcement O
of O
a O
2024 O
presidential O
campaign O
, O
which O
would O
enable O
him O
to O
rile O
up O
his O
supporters O
by O
arguing O
that O
the O
investigation O
is O
a O
politicized O
attempt O
by O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration O
to O
keep O
him O
from O
reclaiming O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
. O

President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
was O
officially O
cleared O
to O
emerge O
from O
isolation O
Sunday O
after O
a O
second O
negative O
Covid-19 O
test O
, O
his O
physician O
announced O
. O

This O
morning O
, O
the O
president’s O
SARS-CoV-2 O
antigen O
testing O
was O
negative O
for O
a O
second O
consecutive O
day O
, O
presidential O
physician O
Kevin B-PER
O’Connor I-PER
wrote O
in O
a O
letter O
Sunday O
. O

He O
will O
safely O
return O
to O
public O
engagement O
and O
presidential O
travel O
. O

Biden O
tested O
negative O
on O
an O
antigen O
test O
Saturday O
as O
well O
, O
but O
remained O
in O
isolation O
until O
Sunday O
morning O
before O
departing O
for O
Rehoboth B-LOC
Beach I-LOC
, O
Delaware B-LOC
. O

Departing O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
for O
Rehoboth B-LOC
Beach I-LOC
, O
the O
President O
told O
reporters O
he O
was O
“feeling O
good,” O
saying, O
“After O
18 O
days, O
I’m O
clear!” O

Biden B-PER
had O
not O
left O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
since O
initially O
testing O
positive O
for O
Covid-19 O
on O
July O
21 O

After O
taking O
a O
five-day O
course O
of O
Pfizer’s B-ORG
antiviral O
drug O
, O
Paxlovid B-ORG
, O
he O
tested O
positive O
for O
a O
rebound O
case O
of O
Covid-19 O
last O
Saturday O
and O
resumed O
isolation O
. O

There O
are O
currently O
no O
events O
on O
his O
public O
schedule O
for O
the O
weekend O

During O
isolation O
, O
the O
President O
has O
participated O
virtually O
in O
public O
events O
from O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
residence O
. O

On O
two O
occasions O
, O
he O
delivered O
socially O
distanced O
remarks O
to O
a O
restricted O
pool O
from O
the O
Blue B-LOC
Room I-LOC
balcony O
, O
announcing O
a O
successful O
strike O
that O
killed O
al O
Qaeda B-ORG
leader O
Ayman B-PER
al-Zawahiri I-PER
Monday O
and O
signing O
two O
bills O
cracking O
down O
on O
Covid-19 O
relief O
fraud O
Friday O

The O
President O
and O
first O
lady O
Jill B-PER
Biden I-PER
are O
scheduled O
to O
travel O
on O
Monday O
to O
visit O
Kentucky B-LOC
after O
deadly O
floods O
in O
the O
eastern O
part O
of O
the O
state O
killed O
dozens O
of O
people O
and O
devastated O
the O
area O

According O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Centers I-ORG
for I-ORG
Disease I-ORG
Control I-ORG
and I-ORG
Prevention I-ORG
, O
“People O
with O
recurrence O
of O
COVID-19 O
symptoms O
or O
a O
new O
positive O
viral O
test O
after O
having O
tested O
negative O
should O
restart O
isolation O
and O
isolate O
again O
for O
at O
least O
5 O
days O
.” O

During O
Biden’s B-PER
first O
bout O
with O
the O
disease O
, O
he O
experienced O
mild O
symptoms O
, O
including O
runny O
nose O
, O
fatigue O
, O
high O
temperature O
and O
a O
cough O
, O
according O
to O
his O
doctor O
. O

The O
five-day O
course O
of O
Paxlovid O
the O
President O
completed O
requires O
a O
doctor’s O
prescription O
and O
is O
available O
via O
emergency O
use O
authorization O
from O
the O
US B-ORG
Food I-ORG
and I-ORG
Drug I-ORG
Administration I-ORG
for O
treatment O
of O
mild-to-moderate O
Covid-19 O
in O
people O
12 O
and O
older O
who O
are O
at O
high O
risk O
of O
severe O
illness O

The O
CDC B-ORG
issued O
a O
health O
alert O
to O
doctors O
on O
May O
24 O
advising O
that O
Covid-19 O
symptoms O
sometimes O
come O
back O
, O
and O
that O
may O
just O
be O
how O
the O
infection O
plays O
out O
in O
some O
people O
, O
regardless O
of O
whether O
they’re O
vaccinated O
or O
treated O
with O
medications O
such O
as O
Paxlovid O
. O

The O
CDC B-ORG
said O
that O
most O
rebound O
cases O
involve O
mild O
disease O
and O
that O
there O
have O
been O
no O
reports O
of O
serious O
illness O

Biden O
is O
fully O
vaccinated O
and O
received O
two O
booster O
shots O

He O
received O
his O
first O
two O
doses O
of O
the O
Pfizer/BioNTech B-ORG
Covid-19 O
vaccine O
ahead O
of O
his O
inauguration O
in O
January B-LOC
2021 O
, O
his O
first O
booster O
shot O
in O
September B-LOC
and O
his O
second O
booster O
vaccination O
in O
March B-LOC
. O

This O
story O
and O
headline O
have O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
developments O
Sunday O

If O
you O
have O
one O
or O
more O
drawers O
filled O
with O
old O
gadgets O
and O
wires O
, O
you’re O
not O
alone O
. O

Decades O
of O
the O
tech O
sector’s O
pressure O
to O
“innovate O
or O
die” O
have O
led O
to O
a O
long O
list O
of O
useful O
and O
flashy O
household O
tech O
products O
, O
but O
many O
of O
these O
same O
devices O
also O
have O
a O
need O
to O
be O
replaced O
at O
almost O
the O
same O
rapid O
rate O
that O
new O
technology O
emerges O
. O

The O
result O
of O
this O
so-called O
planned O
obsolescence O
, O
combined O
with O
a O
limited O
number O
of O
options O
to O
repair O
older O
devices O
over O
the O
years O
, O
is O
a O
tsunami O
of O
electronic O
waste O
, O
also O
known O
as O
e-waste O
. O

And O
the O
fallout O
from O
it O
extends O
far O
beyond O
the O
headache O
of O
figuring O
out O
what O
to O
do O
with O
the O
clutter O
tucked O
away O
inside O
your O
home O
. O

Planned O
obsolescence O
just O
makes O
it O
worse O

People O
now O
expect O
to O
get O
a O
new O
computer O
every O
three O
or O
four O
years O
, O
a O
new O
phone O
every O
two O
years O
, O
said O
Jim B-PER
Puckett I-PER
, O
executive O
director O
of O
the O
Basel B-ORG
Action I-ORG
Network I-ORG
, O
a O
Seattle-based O
e-waste O
watchdog O
group O
. O

It’s O
a O
mountain O
that O
just O
keeps O
growing O
. O

The O
most O
recent O
United B-ORG
Nation’s I-ORG
data O
indicates O
the O
world O
generated O
a O
staggering O
53.6 O
million O
metric O
tons O
of O
e-waste O
in O
2019 O
, O
and O
only O
17.4% O
of O
that O
was O
recycled O
. O

The O
burden O
and O
harms O
of O
e-waste O
often O
fall O
to O
those O
in O
developing O
countries O
. O

The O
US B-ORG
Environmental I-ORG
Protection I-ORG
Agency I-ORG
estimates O
that O
an O
“undetermined O
amount O
of O
used O
electronics O
is O
shipped O
from O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
and O
other O
developed O
countries O
to O
developing O
countries O
that O
lack O
the O
capacity O
to O
reject O
imports O
or O
to O
handle O
these O
materials O
appropriately O
.” O

The O
World B-ORG
Health I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
WHO O
) O
warned O
last O
year O
that O
the O
disposal O
and O
processing O
of O
soaring O
e-waste O
can O
cause O
a O
range O
of O
“adverse O
child O
health O
impacts,” O
including O
changes O
in O
lung O
function, O
DNA O
damage O
and O
increased O
risk O
of O
some O
chronic O
illnesses O
such O
as O
cancer O
and O
cardiovascular O
disease O
later O
in O
life. O

Moreover O
, O
there O
are O
more O
than O
18 O
million O
children O
and O
adolescents O
“actively O
engaged” O
in O
the O
informal O
e-waste O
processing O
industry O
, O
the O
WHO B-ORG
warned O
. O

Children O
and O
adolescents O
are O
often O
used O
to O
scour O
through O
mountains O
of O
e-waste O
in O
search O
of O
valuable O
materials O
such O
as O
copper O
and O
gold O
“because O
their O
small O
hands O
are O
more O
dexterous O
than O
those O
of O
adults,” O
the O
WHO B-ORG
said. O

The O
issue O
of O
e-waste O
is O
“ O
all O
about O
environmental O
justice O
at O
the O
global O
level O
,” O
Puckett B-PER
said O
.” O

It’s O
about O
keeping O
the O
rich O
countries O
from O
dumping O
their O
waste O
and O
dirty O
technologies O
on O
developing O
countries O
. O

The O
growing O
environmental O
crisis O
is O
now O
catching O
the O
attention O
of O
lawmakers O
from O
Europe B-LOC
to O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
, O
as O
well O
as O
communities O
in O
the O
developing O
nations O
where O
e-waste O
has O
historically O
been O
offshored O
. O

EU B-ORG
officials O
last O
month O
approved O
a O
new O
law O
requiring O
all O
phones O
and O
electronics O
to O
use O
a O
standard O
, O
brand-agnostic O
charger O
, O
with O
the O
potential O
to O
limit O
how O
many O
different O
wires O
the O
average O
consumer O
needs O
to O
own O
. O

Three O
progressive O
American O
lawmakers O
urged O
in O
a O
letter O
for O
the O
US O
to O
follow O
suit O

Sens. O

Ed O
Markey B-PER
, O
Elizabeth O
Warren B-PER
and O
Bernie O
Sanders B-PER
said O
the O
novel O
EU O
policy O
“ O
has O
the O
potential O
to O
significantly O
reduce O
e-waste O
and O
help O
consumers O
who O
are O
tired O
of O
having O
to O
rummage O
through O
junk O
drawers O
full O
of O
tangled O
chargers O
to O
find O
a O
compatible O
one O
, O
or O
buy O
a O
new O
one O
,” O
in O
a O
letter O
addressed O
to O
the O
US O
Commerce B-ORG
secretary O
. O

The O
senators O
alluded O
to O
the O
bipartisan O
hot O
topic O
of O
“taking O
on O
powerful O
technology O
companies” O
in O
the O
interest O
of O
consumers O
and O
the O
environment. O

For O
now O
, O
though O
, O
regulation O
around O
e-waste O
exists O
primarily O
at O
the O
state O
level O
and O
there O
are O
few O
signs O
of O
federal O
policy O
moving O
forward O
in O
the O
near O
future O
. O

In O
its O
absence O
, O
the O
onus O
continues O
to O
be O
on O
consumers O
– O
and O
companies O
– O
to O
take O
initiative O
and O
find O
better O
ways O
to O
deal O
with O
old O
electronics O
. O

What O
consumers O
and O
companies O
can O
do O
about O
it O
When O
Corey B-PER
Dehmey I-PER
worked O
in O
corporate O
IT O
departments O
, O
he O
had O
to O
figure O
out O
what O
to O
do O
with O
hundreds O
of O
company O
computers O
that O
were O
no O
longer O
up O
to O
date O
. O

Now, O
as O
executive O
director O
of O
non-profit O
Sustainable B-ORG
Electronics I-ORG
Recycling I-ORG
International I-ORG
( O
SERI B-ORG
) O
, O
he O
is O
part O
of O
a O
group O
trying O
to O
tackle O
the O
e-waste O
crisis O
by O
bolstering O
cooperation O
between O
the O
government O
, O
private O
sector O
and O
consumers. O

E-waste O
is O
the O
result O
of O
not O
planning O
for O
the O
product O
throughout O
its O
lifecycle O
,” O
Dehmey B-PER
said O
. O

We’re O
just O
reacting O
to O
a O
problem O
we O
created O
years O
ago O

And O
so O
if O
we O
want O
to O
get O
in O
front O
of O
this O
thing O
, O
we O
have O
to O
think O
about O
these O
things O
on O
the O
front O
end O
– O
what O
we’re O
designing O
and O
what O
we O
as O
consumers O
are O
purchasing O
as O
well O
. O

To O
do O
that O
, O
SERI B-ORG
introduced O
and O
oversees O
its O
own O
certification O
standards O
for O
e-waste O
recycling O
that O
makes O
sure O
facilities O
are O
properly O
disposing O
of O
e-waste O
. O

It O
also O
hosts O
events O
for O
businesses O
and O
other O
stakeholders O
and O
engages O
in O
advocacy O
work O
to O
pressure O
companies O
and O
governments O
to O
take O
more O
sustainable O
approaches O
to O
developing O
electronics O

We’ve O
got O
to O
figure O
out O
ways O
to O
use O
[ O
an O
electronic O
device O
] O
longer O
, O
repair O
it O
, O
reuse O
it O
, O
Dehmey B-PER
said O
, O
noting O
this O
will O
require O
mindset O
shifts O
from O
both O
consumers O
and O
companies O
. O

In O
recent O
months O
, O
there O
has O
been O
some O
cause O
for O
optimism O
on O
this O
front O
. O

The O
surge O
in O
e-waste O
has O
led O
to O
increased O
pressure O
on O
manufacturers O
to O
ease O
restrictions O
on O
fixing O
devices O
for O
individuals O
and O
independent O
repair O
shops O
in O
a O
push O
known O
as O
the O
“right O
to O
repair” O
movement O

President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
last O
year O
passed O
an O
executive O
order O
that O
directed O
the O
Federal B-ORG
Trade I-ORG
Commission I-ORG
to O
issue O
rules O
requiring O
companies O
to O
allow O
DIY O
repairs O
, O
and O
the O
FTC B-ORG
vowed O
to O
“root O
out” O
illegal O
repair O
restrictions O
. O

Now O
, O
a O
handful O
of O
tech O
companies O
have O
launched O
initiatives O
to O
help O
with O
repairing O
old O
gadgets O
. O

Earlier O
this O
year O
, O
Apple B-ORG
and O
Samsung B-ORG
launched O
their O
self-service O
repair O
stores O
, O
offering O
parts O
for O
users O
seeking O
do-it-yourself O
fixes O
for O
their O
smartphones O
. O

Google B-ORG
similarly O
promised O
parts O
for O
repairing O
Pixel O
phones O
will O
be O
available O
to O
the O
public O
later O
this O
year O

Various O
coalitions O
have O
also O
emerged O
in O
recent O
years O
to O
give O
consumers O
the O
option O
to O
responsibly O
dispose O
of O
their O
devices O

Puckett O
helped O
launch O
the O
e-waste O
recycling O
initiative O
e-Stewards B-ORG
, O
for O
example O
, O
which O
certifies O
and O
audits O
electronics O
recyclers O
to O
make O
sure O
they O
are O
properly O
disposing O
of O
e-waste O
using O
“very O
rigorous O
standards O
. O

With O
this O
tool O
, O
consumers O
can O
look O
up O
nearby O
recycling O
centers O
. O

SERI B-ORG
also O
offers O
an O
online O
tool O
to O
find O
a O
certified O
recycling O
center O

Jeff B-PER
Seibert I-PER
, O
the O
chief O
provocateur O
( O
yes O
, O
that’s O
his O
real O
title O
) O
at O
SERI B-ORG
, O
also O
recommends O
consumers O
check O
with O
their O
local O
municipality O
to O
see O
if O
they O
have O
a O
designated O
plan O
for O
recycling O
e-waste O
. O

A O
handful O
of O
US O
retailers O
, O
including O
Staples B-ORG
and O
Best B-ORG
Buy I-ORG
, O
also O
have O
programs O
that O
let O
consumers O
bring O
in O
e-waste O
for O
recycling O
in O
the O
absence O
of O
broader O
infrastructure O
. O

Other O
companies O
, O
including O
Apple B-ORG
, O
have O
programs O
to O
offer O
credits O
or O
free O
recycling O
in O
exchange O
for O
trading O
in O
used O
gadgets O
. O

Before O
opting O
to O
donate O
or O
recycle O
used O
electronics O
, O
the O
EPA B-ORG
recommends O
considering O
upgrading O
the O
hardware O
or O
software O
of O
a O
computer O
instead O
of O
buying O
a O
brand O
new O
product O
. O

If O
you O
do O
decide O
to O
recycle O
, O
the O
EPA B-ORG
urges O
consumers O
to O
remove O
any O
batteries O
that O
may O
need O
to O
be O
recycled O
separately O
. O

The O
agency O
says O
that O
recycling O
one O
million O
laptops O
saves O
the O
energy O
equivalent O
of O
the O
electricity O
used O
by O
more O
than O
3,500 O
US B-LOC
homes O
in O
a O
year O

For O
every O
one O
million O
cell O
phones O
that O
are O
recycled O
, O
the O
agency O
says O
35,000 O
pounds O
of O
copper O
, O
772 O
pounds O
of O
silver O
, O
75 O
pounds O
of O
gold O
and O
33 O
pounds O
of O
palladium O
can O
be O
recovered O
. O

Apart O
from O
these O
options O
, O
Seibert B-PER
simply O
urges O
consumers O
to O
start O
thinking O
about O
electronics O
like O
we O
think O
about O
cars O
: O
we O
don’t O
trash O
our O
vehicles O
when O
we O
need O
new O
tires O
or O
if O
the O
windshield O
cracks O
. O

Everybody O
wants O
to O
do O
the O
right O
thing O
,” O
Seibert B-PER
said O
. O

So O
we’ve O
got O
to O
give O
them O
the O
resources O
to O
be O
able O
to O
do O
that O
, O
and O
that’s O
still O
a O
work O
in O
progress O
. O

ردا O
على O
زيارة O
بيلوسي B-PER
.. O
الصين B-LOC
توجه O
"ضربات O
دقيقة" O
لمناطق O
حول O
تايوان B-LOC
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

Airbnb B-ORG
and O
new O
property O
owner O
apologize O
for O
'slave O
cabin' O
listing O
| O
CNN B-ORG
Travel I-ORG
![fwp_0] O
(https://ads.stickyadstv.com/user-matching?id=185&_fw_gdpr=0&_fw_gdpr_consent=) O
![fwp_1] O
(https://ads.stickyadstv.com/auto-user-sync) O

Four O
people O
were O
fatally O
shot O
Friday O
at O
multiple O
sites O
in O
a O
small O
Ohio B-LOC
town O
just O
north O
of O
Dayton B-LOC
, O
and O
police O
are O
searching O
for O
a O
man O
who O
is O
possibly O
connected O
to O
the O
shootings O
. O

Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
, O
a O
“ O
person O
of O
interest O
,” O
is O
likely O
armed O
and O
dangerous O
, O
Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
Police B-ORG
Chief O
John B-PER
Porter I-PER
said O
at O
a O
media O
briefing O
. O

Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
remains O
the O
primary O
suspect O
,” O
Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
Police B-ORG
said O
in O
a O
statement O
Saturday O
via O
Facebook B-ORG
. O

We O
have O
no O
current O
information O
to O
make O
us O
believe O
others O
were O
involved O
in O
these O
horrific O
acts O
.” O

Following O
the O
shootings O
, O
it O
appears O
Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
drove O
to O
Interstate O
70 O
and O
headed O
west O
, O
” O
the O
statement O
added O
. O

At O
this O
time O
, O
we O
believe O
that O
he O
has O
left O
Ohio B-LOC
. O

Law O
enforcement O
agencies O
in O
multiple O
states O
have O
been O
made O
aware O
of O
this O
and O
are O
on O
high O
alert O

Earlier, O
FBI B-ORG
said O
Marlow B-PER
has O
ties O
to O
Lexington, B-LOC
Kentucky, B-LOC
Indianapolis B-LOC
and O
Chicago B-LOC
and O
may O
be O
in O
one O
of O
those O
cities. O

Porter B-PER
said O
Marlow B-PER
is O
5’11” O
and O
about O
160 O
pounds O
, O
with O
brown O
hair O
. O

Authorities O
believe O
Marlow B-PER
, O
39 O
, O
was O
wearing O
shorts O
and O
a O
yellow O
T-shirt O
and O
fled O
in O
a O
white O
2007 O
Ford B-ORG
Edge I-ORG
. O

Authorities O
have O
asked O
anyone O
with O
information O
to O
contact O
the O
FBI B-ORG

They O
said O
Marlow B-PER
should O
not O
be O
approached O

Police O
responded O
to O
a O
report O
of O
shots O
fired O
just O
before O
noon O
Friday O
, O
Porter B-PER
said O
, O
and O
the O
four O
victims O
died O
at O
the O
scenes O
. O

This O
is O
the O
first O
violent O
crime O
in O
this O
neighborhood O
in O
recent O
memory O
, O
Porter B-PER
said O
. O

We O
are O
working O
to O
determine O
if O
there O
was O
any O
motive O
to O
this O
horrible O
tragedy O
or O
if O
mental O
illness O
played O
any O
role O
. O

Wendy B-PER
Chapman I-PER
, O
a O
neighbor O
of O
one O
victim O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
affiliate O
WKEF B-ORG
the O
neighborhood O
is O
a O
quiet O
place O
. O

I O
would O
have O
never O
, O
even O
in O
this O
neighborhood O
, O
I O
would O
never O
expect O
anything O
, O
never O
, O
” O
Chapman B-PER
told O
the O
Dayton B-LOC
station O
. O

Police O
do O
not O
believe O
there O
is O
an O
ongoing O
threat O
to O
the O
neighborhood O
but O
have O
deployed O
additional O
crews O
and O
the O
Dayton B-ORG
Police I-ORG
Bomb B-ORG
Squad I-ORG
out O
of O
an O
abundance O
of O
caution O
, O
Porter B-PER
said O
. O

Porter B-PER
said O
people O
should O
call O
the O
police O
dispatch O
if O
they O
have O
information O
on O
Marlow’s O
whereabouts O
or O
see O
the O
Ford B-ORG
Edge I-ORG
. O

Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
is O
a O
town O
of O
just O
under O
8,000 O
residents O
about O
9 O
miles O
north O
of O
Dayton B-LOC

CNN’s B-ORG
Zenebou B-PER
Sylla I-PER
and O
Samantha B-PER
Beech I-PER
also O
contributed O
to O
this O
story O
. O

As O
the O
Razoni B-ORG
left O
the O
Ukrainian B-LOC
port O
of O
Odesa B-LOC
on O
Monday O
with O
the O
first O
shipment O
of O
grain O
since O
the O
early O
days O
of O
Russia’s B-LOC
war O
in O
Ukraine B-LOC
, O
there O
were O
sighs O
of O
relief O
from O
Somalia B-LOC
to O
Turkey B-LOC
, O
Indonesia B-LOC
and O
China B-LOC
, O
given O
how O
reliant O
these O
countries O
have O
been O
on O
Ukrainian B-LOC
grain O
to O
meet O
their O
daily O
needs O
. O

Millions O
of O
people O
have O
been O
pushed O
into O
hunger O
as O
the O
Russian B-LOC
blockade O
fueled O
soaring O
grain O
commodity O
prices O
, O
which O
reached O
record O
highs O
this O
year O
as O
more O
than O
20 O
million O
metric O
tons O
of O
Ukrainian B-LOC
wheat O
and O
corn O
remained O
trapped O
in O
Odesa B-LOC
. O

But O
even O
as O
the O
UN-brokered O
agreement O
to O
lift O
the O
blockade O
has O
eased O
grain O
prices O
, O
experts O
say O
the O
belated O
shipments O
from O
Ukraine B-LOC
are O
no O
quick O
fix O
to O
the O
crisis O
, O
accelerated O
by O
years O
of O
pandemic-related O
disruptions O
, O
the O
climate O
crisis O
, O
conflict O
, O
food O
export O
restrictions O
and O
spiraling O
costs O
. O

All O
these O
interacting O
factors O
“ O
are O
going O
to O
remain O
for O
some O
time O
,” O
Laura B-PER
Wellesley I-PER
, O
a O
senior O
research O
fellow O
at O
think O
tank O
Chatham B-ORG
House’s I-ORG
environment O
and O
society O
program O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
“ O

It O
may O
be O
that O
we O
see O
peaks O
in O
food O
prices O
again O
, O
and O
peaks O
in O
food O
insecurity O
, O
but O
certainly O
not O
a O
resolution O
of O
the O
situation O
anytime O
soon O
. O

Global O
hunger O
has O
increased O
massively O
, O
from O
135 O
million O
people O
acutely O
food O
insecure O
in O
2019 O
to O
345 O
million O
in O
2022 O
, O
according O
to O
the O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Programme I-ORG
( O
WFP O
) O
. O

It O
includes O
“50 O
million O
people O
in O
45 O
countries O
that O
are O
knocking O
on O
famine’s O
door,” O
David B-PER
Beasley, I-PER
WFP’s O
executive O
director, O
told O
the O
House B-ORG
Foreign I-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
on O
July O
20, O
as O
he O
called O
on O
other O
donor O
countries, O
like O
Gulf B-LOC
nations, O
to O
step O
in O
an O
“avert O
catastrophe.” O

Today’s O
crisis O
is O
far O
worse O
than O
the O
previous O
food O
price O
spikes O
of O
2007 O
to O
2008 O
and O
2010 O
to O
2012 O
, O
which O
both O
fueled O
riots O
around O
the O
world O
, O
including O
revolutions O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
. O

Food O
security O
experts O
have O
warned O
of O
huge O
geopolitical O
risk O
if O
action O
is O
not O
taken O

This O
year O
has O
already O
witnessed O
political O
destabilization O
in O
“ O
Sri B-LOC
Lanka I-LOC
, O
Mali B-LOC
, O
Chad B-LOC
, O
Burkina B-LOC
Faso I-LOC
, O
riots O
and O
protests O
taking O
place O
in O
Kenya B-LOC
, O
Peru B-LOC
, O
Pakistan B-LOC
, O
Indonesia B-LOC
… O
these O
are O
only O
signs O
things O
to O
come O
is O
going O
to O
get O
worse O
, O
” O
Beasley B-PER
said O
. O

Hunger O
hotspots O
In O
the O
Horn B-LOC
of I-LOC
Africa I-LOC
, O
a O
four-year O
drought O
has O
led O
to O
food O
insecurity O
and O
starvation O
, O
according O
to O
aid O
groups O
. O

Somalian B-LOC
health O
facilities O
are O
seeing O
record O
levels O
of O
malnutrition O
following O
years O
of O
failed O
rainy O
seasons O
, O
a O
doubling O
of O
wheat O
prices O
and O
the O
economic O
fallout O
of O
the O
Covid-19 O
pandemic O
. O

Ijabu B-PER
Hassan I-PER
lost O
three O
children O
to O
malnutrition O
this O
year O
, O
telling O
CNN B-ORG
that O
her O
2-year-old O
daughter O
collapsed O
and O
died O
on O
their O
trek O
to O
the O
capital O
, O
Mogadishu B-LOC
, O
to O
seek O
help O
. O

I O
cried O
so O
much O
,” O
she O
said O
, O
“ O
I O
lost O
consciousness O
.” O

As O
desperate O
parents O
like O
Hassan B-PER
seek O
reprieve O
, O
the O
UN B-ORG
estimates O
7 O
million O
people O
— O
or O
over O
half O
of O
Somalia’s B-LOC
population O
— O
simply O
do O
not O
have O
enough O
to O
eat O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
Afghans O
have O
seen O
their O
lives O
go O
from O
bad O
to O
worse O
since O
the O
Taliban B-ORG
seized O
power O
in O
2021 O
. O

After O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
’ O
hasty O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
country O
last O
August O
, O
Washington B-LOC
and O
its O
allies O
cut O
off O
international O
funding O
to O
the O
country O
, O
which O
has O
run O
heavily O
on O
aid O
for O
years O
, O
and O
froze O
about O
$7 O
billion O
of O
the O
country O
’ O
s O
foreign O
reserves O
. O

Afghanistan B-LOC
’s O
economic O
crisis O
has O
loomed O
for O
years O
, O
the O
result O
of O
poverty O
, O
conflict O
and O
drought O
. O

But O
this O
year O
, O
as O
below O
average O
harvests O
led O
to O
unprecedented O
levels O
of O
hunger O
across O
the O
country O
, O
long O
lines O
for O
aid O
have O
become O
ubiquitous O
even O
in O
the O
capital O
Kabul’s B-LOC
middle-class O
neighborhoods O
. O

Longstanding O
conflict O
in O
countries O
like O
Somalia B-LOC
and O
Afghanistan B-LOC
has O
impacted O
people’s O
ability O
to O
access O
food O
, O
and O
the O
climate O
crisis O
is O
only O
worsening O
the O
situation O
. O

Droughts O
in O
main O
crop-producing O
regions O
, O
like O
Europe B-LOC
and O
North B-LOC
America I-LOC
, O
have O
pushed O
food O
prices O
upwards O
. O

Extreme O
weather O
across O
parts O
of O
North B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
is O
a O
chilling O
reminder O
that O
, O
blockade O
or O
no O
blockade O
, O
food O
supply O
here O
is O
highly O
insecure O
anyway O

The O
region O
is O
dependent O
on O
wheat O
from O
Europe B-LOC
, O
especially O
Ukraine B-LOC
. O

Tunisia B-LOC
, O
for O
example O
, O
gets O
nearly O
half O
its O
wheat O
from O
the O
country O
to O
make O
its O
daily O
bread O
. O

Data O
from O
EarthDaily B-ORG
Analytics I-ORG
, O
obtained O
using O
satellite O
imagery O
, O
shows O
just O
how O
hard O
it O
is O
for O
some O
nations O
here O
to O
cover O
any O
of O
the O
gap O
themselves O
. O

Looking O
at O
crop O
cover O
in O
Morocco B-LOC
, O
the O
images O
suggest O
a O
“catastrophic O
wheat O
season” O
in O
the O
country O
, O
with O
output O
far O
lower O
than O
in O
recent O
years O
, O
because O
of O
a O
drought O
that O
began O
there O
at O
the O
end O
of O
2021 O
and O
continued O
into O
early O
this O
year O
. O

Morocco B-LOC
gets O
a O
fifth O
of O
its O
wheat O
from O
Ukraine B-LOC
and O
a O
larger O
40% O
from O
France B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
Mickael B-PER
Attia I-PER
, O
crop O
analyst O
for O
EarthDaily B-ORG
Analytics I-ORG
. O

The O
current O
drought O
in O
North B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
, O
specifically O
Morocco B-LOC
, O
is O
profoundly O
impacting O
their O
ability O
to O
produce O
their O
own O
crops O
, O
not O
to O
mention O
that O
in O
the O
past O
, O
Ukraine B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
largest O
exporters O
of O
food O
to O
the O
country O
. O

The O
cost O
to O
replace O
that O
is O
very O
high O
and O
a O
struggle O
,” O
Attia B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

The O
country O
needs O
the O
import O
for O
structural O
reasons O
– O
every O
year O
national O
consumption O
is O
far O
higher O
than O
production O
– O
and O
because O
the O
country O
is O
regularly O
exposed O
to O
massive O
weather O
events O
, O
drought O
and O
climate O
change O
will O
make O
things O
worse O
in O
the O
future O
. O

Ukraine B-LOC
’s O
wheat O
production O
, O
too O
, O
is O
expected O
to O
be O
40% O
lower O
than O
last O
year O
’s O
, O
as O
its O
fields O
are O
impacted O
by O
the O
war O
; O
fertilizer O
and O
pesticides O
are O
harder O
to O
get O
; O
but O
also O
because O
of O
an O
early O
spring O
cold O
pattern O
and O
dryness O
in O
the O
country O
’s O
west O
, O
Attia B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
that O
the O
impacts O
could O
last O
well O
into O
next O
year O
. O

If O
Ukrainian O
grains O
are O
partially O
, O
physically O
missing O
because O
of O
low O
production O
and O
difficulties O
in O
exporting O
then O
, O
this O
will O
lead O
to O
greater O
food O
insecurity O
this O
year O
and O
next O
, O
he O
said O
. O

Other O
major O
wheat O
exporters O
have O
also O
been O
hit O
hard O
by O
extreme O
weather O
exacerbated O
by O
climate O
change O

France B-LOC
too O
should O
produce O
8% O
less O
wheat O
than O
last O
year O
, O
Attia B-PER
said O
. O

May O
was O
dry O
in O
most O
of O
Europe B-LOC
, O
and O
crazy O
hot O
in O
Western B-LOC
Europe I-LOC
, O
impacting O
crops O
from O
France B-LOC
and O
Spain B-LOC
, O
especially O
, O
Attia B-PER
said O
. O

June O
was O
also O
a O
dry O
and O
hot O
month O
in O
most O
of O
Europe B-LOC
, O
and O
accelerated O
the O
decrease O
in O
crops O
in O
France B-LOC
, O
Spain B-LOC
and O
Romania B-LOC
.” O

Pandemic O
and O
protectionism O
Meanwhile O
, O
many O
countries’ O
efforts O
to O
alleviate O
food O
insecurity O
were O
undone O
in O
the O
pandemic O
. O

It O
plunged O
the O
global O
economy O
into O
recession O
in O
2020 O
, O
upending O
supply O
chains O
and O
causing O
employment O
and O
transport O
problems O
. O

Governments O
began O
to O
face O
inflationary O
pressure O
and O
global O
food O
prices O
began O
to O
soar O
as O
production O
disruption O
and O
high O
demand O
from O
countries O
like O
China B-LOC
were O
“really O
tightening O
that O
balance O
between O
supply O
and O
demand O
and O
pushing O
up O
prices,” O
said O
Wellesley, B-PER
from O
Chatham B-ORG
House. I-ORG

Economies O
of O
poorer O
countries O
have O
been O
left O
in O
tatters O
while O
middle O
income O
nations O
have O
incurred O
large O
debts O
, O
limiting O
their O
governments’ O
ability O
to O
offer O
social O
safety O
nets O
and O
provisions O
that O
would O
help O
the O
most O
vulnerable O
through O
this O
food O
supply O
crisis O
, O
she O
added O
. O

In O
Peru B-LOC
and O
Brazil B-LOC
, O
people O
working O
in O
the O
large O
informal O
jobs O
sector O
lost O
their O
savings O
and O
earning O
power O
during O
the O
pandemic’s O
lockdowns O
. O

So O
these O
people O
moved O
from O
middle O
classes O
to O
poor O
… O
in O
Brazil B-LOC
the O
number O
of O
people O
living O
in O
severe O
food O
insecurity O
is O
extremely O
high O
,” O
Maximo B-PER
Torero I-PER
, O
the O
chief O
economist O
of O
the O
Food B-ORG
and I-ORG
Agriculture I-ORG
Organization I-ORG
( O
FAO B-ORG
) O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

In O
2021 O
, O
a O
record O
36% O
of O
Brazilians B-LOC
were O
at O
risk O
of O
going O
hungry O
, O
surpassing O
the O
world O
average O
for O
the O
first O
time O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Getulio B-ORG
Vargas I-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
( O
FGV O
) O
, O
a O
Brazilian O
academic O
institution O
, O
which O
analyzed O
Gallup B-ORG
data O
. O

The O
war O
has O
brought O
home O
just O
how O
many O
people O
and O
countries O
have O
come O
to O
rely O
on O
a O
complex O
and O
globalized O
commodities O
system O

Europe’s B-LOC
dependency O
on O
Russian B-LOC
gas O
has O
exposed O
its O
vulnerabilities O
. O

While O
countries O
like O
Turkey B-LOC
, O
Egypt B-LOC
, O
Somalia B-LOC
, O
Congo B-LOC
and O
Tanzania B-LOC
are O
some O
of O
the O
most O
dependent O
on O
Ukrainian O
and O
Russian O
wheat O
, O
nations O
like O
Eritrea B-LOC
bought O
the O
grain O
exclusively O
from O
the O
two O
nations O
in O
2021 O
. O

Analysts O
suggest O
the O
supply O
chain O
crisis O
might O
lead O
to O
more O
localized O
or O
regional O
sourcing O
strategies O
– O
but O
that O
might O
take O
a O
while O

Let O
me O
give O
you O
an O
example O
– O
Africa B-LOC
uses O
3% O
of O
the O
fertilizers O
in O
the O
world O
,” O
Torero B-PER
said O
, O
yet O
Dangote’s B-ORG
fertilizer O
plant O
in O
Nigeria B-LOC
sends O
95.5% O
of O
its O
product O
to O
Latin B-LOC
America I-LOC
. O

Nothing O
stays O
in O
Africa B-LOC
. O

It O
is O
not O
that O
( O
the O
Dangote B-ORG
plant O
does O
not O
want O
to O
export O
in O
Africa B-LOC
, O
it’s O
( O
because O
there O
are O
too O
many O
barriers O
to O
export O
( O
to O
other O
parts O
of O
( O
Africa B-LOC
) O
) O
, O
he O
said O
, O
adding O
that O
the O
infrastructure O
was O
poor O
and O
the O
risk O
high O
. O

Going O
the O
other O
way O
and O
imposing O
protectionist O
policies O
is O
also O
problematic O

As O
food O
prices O
exploded O
following O
Russia’s B-LOC
invasion O
, O
countries O
began O
restricting O
exports O
. O

India B-LOC
the O
world’s O
largest O
producer O
of O
sugar O
, O
limited O
sugar O
exports O
to O
10 O
million O
tons O
and O
banned O
wheat O
exports O
. O

Today O
, O
more O
than O
20 O
countries O
have O
some O
sort O
of O
export O
restrictions O
in O
place O
, O
dashing O
hopes O
that O
these O
items O
might O
help O
alleviate O
hunger O
elsewhere O
. O

“That O
has O
an O
immediate O
effect O
of O
pushing O
up O
prices, O
but O
over O
time, O
it O
also O
is O
kind O
of O
eroding O
trust O
and O
predictability O
in O
the O
global O
market,” O
Wellesley B-PER
said. O

Then O
there O
is O
the O
issue O
of O
fertilizer O
prices O
that O
remain O
high O
because O
it O
is O
energy O
intensive O
to O
produce O
and O
Russia B-LOC
and O
Ukraine B-LOC
are O
major O
suppliers O
of O
its O
key O
components O
: O
urea O
, O
potash O
and O
phosphate O
. O

Some O
analysts O
warn O
that O
as O
usage O
of O
fertilizer O
goes O
down O
, O
we O
will O
see O
smaller O
yields O
in O
2023 O
. O

And O
while O
the O
main O
concern O
has O
rested O
on O
grain O
supplies O
, O
some O
worry O
that O
the O
production O
of O
rice O
, O
a O
cornerstone O
of O
many O
diets O
in O
Asia B-LOC
and O
sub-Saharan B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
, O
could O
take O
a O
hit O
amid O
high O
fertilizer O
costs O
. O

Even O
if O
there O
are O
currently O
high O
inventories O
of O
rice O
, O
protectionism O
and O
people O
turning O
to O
rice O
as O
a O
substitute O
for O
wheat O
could O
impact O
prices O
. O

Sub-Saharan B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
imports O
the O
most O
rice O
in O
the O
world O
, O
so O
if O
the O
price O
of O
rice O
goes O
up O
, O
then O
the O
most O
vulnerable O
countries O
will O
be O
substantially O
affected O
, O
Torero B-PER
of O
the O
FAO B-ORG
said O
. O

The O
Razoni O
, O
a O
Sierre B-LOC
Leone I-LOC
-registered O
ship O
currently O
en O
route O
to O
Lebanon B-LOC
, O
is O
carrying O
around O
26,500 O
metric O
tons O
of O
corn O
. O

To O
meet O
2021 O
August O
shipment O
levels O
, O
we’d O
have O
to O
see O
seven O
of O
those O
ships O
happen O
every O
single O
day O
for O
things O
to O
actually O
get O
back O
to O
where O
we O
were O
, O
” O
Jonathan B-PER
Haines I-PER
, O
a O
senior O
analyst O
at O
commodity O
data O
group O
Gro B-ORG
Intelligence I-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

There O
is O
a O
lot O
of O
uncertainty O
if O
that O
can O
happen O
, O
but O
flow O
is O
undoubtably O
“going O
to O
really O
pick O
up O
,” O
he O
added O
. O

The O
Ukrainian B-LOC
government O
and O
the O
Turkish B-LOC
Defense O
Ministry O
said O
three O
more O
ships O
were O
expected O
to O
leave O
Ukrainian B-LOC
Black B-LOC
Sea I-LOC
ports O
on O
Friday O
laden O
with O
grain O

As O
and O
when O
wheat O
prices O
drop O
to O
pre-war O
levels O
, O
Torero B-PER
worries O
that O
the O
return O
of O
Ukrainian B-LOC
and O
Russian B-LOC
grain O
on O
the O
markets O
could O
further O
reduce O
wheat O
prices O
and O
in O
the O
process O
impoverish O
poor O
farmers O
, O
who O
shouldered O
high O
fertilizer O
and O
energy O
costs O
to O
plant O
their O
crops O
. O

Just O
as O
the O
food O
crisis O
has O
had O
wide O
and O
varying O
impacts O
on O
people O
, O
the O
solutions O
are O
complex O
and O
multifaceted O
. O

These O
include O
improvements O
in O
how O
fertilizers O
are O
used O
, O
investments O
in O
social O
safety O
nets O
, O
decoupling O
food O
production O
from O
fossil O
fuel O
dependence O
while O
slashing O
greenhouse O
gas O
emissions O
, O
and O
a O
push O
to O
make O
the O
agricultural O
sector O
more O
resilient O
to O
global O
shocks O
by O
diversifying O
production O
and O
trade O
relationships O
, O
experts O
say O
. O

These O
all O
seem O
like O
things O
to O
tackle O
another O
day O
given O
the O
severity O
of O
the O
current O
situation O

They O
are O
not,” O
Wellesley B-PER
said. O
“ O

They O
are O
problems O
contributing O
to O
today’s O
situation O
( O
and O
) O
will O
recur O
over O
the O
years O
to O
come O
– O
particularly O
as O
climate O
impacts O
continue O
to O
worsen O
. O

A O
suspect O
in O
the O
shooting O
deaths O
of O
four O
people O
at O
multiple O
sites O
outside O
of O
Dayton B-LOC
, O
Ohio B-LOC
, O
has O
been O
arrested O
, O
police O
said O

Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
was O
taken O
into O
custody O
Saturday O
night O
by O
police O
in O
Lawrence B-LOC
, O
Kansas B-LOC
, O
Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
Police B-ORG
Chief O
John B-PER
Porter I-PER
said O
at O
a O
news O
conference O
. O

Marlow B-PER
was O
wanted O
in O
connection O
with O
the O
Friday O
shootings O
in O
Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
, O
a O
small O
town O
north O
of O
Dayton B-LOC
. O

The O
arrest O
comes O
a O
day O
after O
the O
victims O
were O
found O
at O
multiple O
crime O
scenes O

A O
motive O
for O
the O
shootings O
is O
still O
unclear O

Lawrence B-LOC
police O
“had O
reason O
to O
believe” O
Marlow B-PER
was O
in O
their O
city O
and O
launched O
a O
city-wide O
search O
for O
the O
suspect, O
the O
Lawrence B-ORG
Police I-ORG
Department I-ORG
said O
in O
a O
statement. O

A O
Lawrence B-LOC
police O
officer O
called O
for O
additional O
personnel O
after O
noticing O
a O
vehicle O
matching O
the O
description O
of O
the O
car O
the O
suspect O
was O
believed O
to O
be O
driving O
, O
according O
to O
the O
statement O
. O

As O
the O
officers O
were O
on O
the O
way O
, O
the O
vehicle O
turned O
into O
a O
parking O
lot O
and O
Marlow B-PER
stepped O
out O
, O
Lawrence B-LOC
police O
said O
. O

After O
he O
exited O
the O
car O
, O
police O
arrested O
him O
, O
the O
statement O
said O
. O

Authorities O
had O
described O
Marlow B-PER
as O
likely O
armed O
and O
dangerous O
. O

Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
remains O
the O
primary O
suspect,” O
Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
Police B-ORG
said O
in O
a O
Facebook B-ORG
statement O
Saturday O
“ O

We O
have O
no O
current O
information O
to O
make O
us O
believe O
others O
were O
involved O
in O
these O
horrific O
acts O
. O
” O
“ O

Following O
the O
shootings O
, O
it O
appears O
Stephen B-PER
Marlow I-PER
drove O
to O
Interstate O
70 O
and O
headed O
west O
, O
” O
the O
statement O
added O
, O
noting O
they O
believed O
he O
had O
left O
Ohio B-LOC
. O

Law O
enforcement O
agencies O
in O
multiple O
states O
have O
been O
made O
aware O
of O
this O
and O
are O
on O
high O
alert O
. O

Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
is O
about O
640 O
miles O
from O
Lawrence B-LOC
, O
Kansas B-LOC
. O

Police O
responded O
to O
a O
report O
of O
shots O
fired O
just O
before O
noon O
Friday O
, O
Porter B-PER
said O
, O
and O
the O
four O
victims O
died O
at O
the O
scenes O
. O

This O
is O
the O
first O
violent O
crime O
in O
this O
neighborhood O
in O
recent O
memory O
, O
Porter B-PER
said O
. O

We O
are O
working O
to O
determine O
if O
there O
was O
any O
motive O
to O
this O
horrible O
tragedy O
or O
if O
mental O
illness O
played O
any O
role O
. O

Wendy B-PER
Chapman I-PER
, O
a O
neighbor O
of O
one O
victim O
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
affiliate O
WKEF B-ORG
the O
neighborhood O
is O
a O
quiet O
place O
. O

I O
would O
have O
never O
, O
even O
in O
this O
neighborhood O
, O
I O
would O
never O
expect O
anything O
, O
never O
, O
” O
Chapman B-PER
told O
the O
Dayton B-LOC
station O
. O

Butler B-LOC
Township I-LOC
is O
a O
town O
of O
just O
under O
8,000 O
residents O
about O
nine O
miles O
north O
of O
Dayton B-LOC

In O
the O
neighboring O
city O
of O
Vandalia B-LOC
, O
authorities O
increased O
the O
number O
of O
officers O
on O
patrol O
following O
the O
shooting O
, O
Mayor O
Richard B-PER
Herbst I-PER
said O
in O
a O
Facebook B-ORG
post O
. O

The O
city O
also O
canceled O
outdoor O
activities O
and O
closed O
recreation O
facilities O
“as O
a O
precaution,” O
the O
mayor O
said, O
noting O
that O
there O
were O
no O
“specific O
threats O
against O
City O
facilities.” O

CNN B-ORG
’s O
Zenebou B-PER
Sylla I-PER
, O
Liam B-PER
Reilly I-PER
and O
Samantha B-PER
Beech I-PER
also O
contributed O
to O
this O
story O

Tesla B-ORG
’s O
autopilot O
and O
self-driving O
claims O
are O
under O
fire O
again O
, O
this O
time O
from O
the O
California B-ORG
Department I-ORG
of O
Motor B-ORG
Vehicles I-ORG
in O
a O
complaint O
it O
filed O
on O
July O
28 O
. O

The O
complaint O
alleges O
that O
the O
company O
made O
“untrue O
or O
misleading” O
statements O
in O
advertisements O
on O
its O
website O
by O
claiming O
that O
Tesla B-ORG
vehicles O
were O
or O
could O
be O
equipped O
with O
advanced O
driver O
assistance O
system O
features O
. O

The O
Tesla B-ORG
(TSLA) O
advertisements O
ran O
in O
marketing O
materials O
on O
the O
company’s O
website O
“on O
at O
least O
five O
dates” O
between O
May B-LOC
2021 O
and O
July B-LOC
2022 O
, O
the O
complaint O
said O
. O

They O
included O
descriptions O
such O
as O
“Autopilot” O
and O
“Full O
Self-Driving O
Capability” O
and O
used O
such O
wording O
as O
“All O
you O
will O
need O
to O
do O
is O
get O
in O
and O
tell O
your O
car O
where O
to O
go…Your O
Tesla B-ORG
will O
figure O
out O
the O
optimal O
route, O
navigating O
urban O
streets, O
complex O
intersections O
and O
freeways,” O
the O
suit O
said. O

Another O
claim O
that O
the O
California B-ORG
DMV I-ORG
alleged O
was O
misleading O
said O
, O
“ O
The O
system O
is O
designed O
to O
be O
able O
to O
conduct O
short O
and O
long-distance O
trips O
with O
no O
action O
required O
by O
the O
person O
in O
the O
driver’s O
seat O
.” O
“ O

These O
advertisements O
are O
a O
deceptive O
practice” O
under O
California’s B-LOC
Civil O
Code, O
the O
DMV B-ORG
complaint O
said. O

Tesla B-ORG
does O
not O
typically O
respond O
to O
requests O
for O
comment O
. O

Tesla B-ORG
has O
published O
disclaimers O
from O
as O
recently O
as O
June B-LOC
warning O
the O
features O
still O
require O
active O
driver O
supervision O
, O
which O
contradict O
the O
“misleading O
labels O
and O
claims,” O
the O
complaint O
added O
. O

Tesla B-ORG
’s O
advertising O
actions O
could O
cause O
it O
to O
temporarily O
lose O
its O
manufacturer O
license O
and O
special O
plates O
number O
in O
California B-LOC
, O
the O
complaint O
warned O
. O

Data O
released O
in O
June O
by O
the O
National B-ORG
Highway I-ORG
Traffic I-ORG
Safety I-ORG
Administration I-ORG
found O
there O
were O
273 O
crashes O
in O
the O
last O
nine O
months O
involving O
Tesla B-ORG
driver-assist O
technologies O
, O
caused O
by O
either O
its O
“full O
self-driving” O
software O
or O
its O
precursor O
, O
Tesla B-ORG
Autopilot O
. O

Of O
497 O
total O
crashes O
studied O
by O
the O
NHTSA B-ORG
, O
43% O
of O
those O
caused O
by O
driver-assist O
technologies O
took O
place O
in O
California B-LOC
, O
the O
data O
found O

Tesla’s B-ORG
Autopilot O
feature O
comes O
standard O
in O
all O
of O
its O
vehicles O
, O
making O
it O
one O
of O
the O
industry’s O
most O
commonly O
used O
autopilot O
systems O
. O

While O
Tesla B-ORG
reminds O
drivers O
to O
stay O
alert O
while O
using O
it O
, O
a O
2021 O
MIT B-ORG
study O
revealed O
that O
users O
who O
used O
the O
system O
were O
more O
distracted O
and O
looked O
away O
from O
the O
road O
more O
often O
than O
when O
they O
were O
driving O
without O
the O
feature O
. O

Tesla B-ORG
has O
15 O
days O
to O
respond O
to O
the O
complaint O
in O
order O
to O
avoid O
a O
default O
decision O
