Secretary O
of O
State O
Antony B-PER
Blinken I-PER
criticized O
the O
Russian B-LOC
legal O
system O
more O
broadly O
, O
saying O
the O
sentence O
“ O
puts O
a O
spotlight O
on O
our O
significant O
concerns O
with O
Russia’s B-LOC
legal O
system O
and O
the O
Russian B-LOC
government’s O
use O
of O
wrongful O
detentions O
to O
advance O
its O
own O
agenda O
, O
using O
individuals O
as O
political O
pawns O
.” O

He O
said O
the O
US B-ORG
is O
working O
to O
bring O
home O
Griner B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Whelan I-PER
, O
an O
American O
citizen O
who O
has O
been O
held O
by O
Russia B-LOC
for O
alleged O
espionage O
since O
2018 O
. O

This O
is O
an O
absolute O
priority O
of O
mine O
and O
the O
Department’s O
,” O
Blinken B-PER
said O

It’s O
now O
“up O
to O
the O
Russian B-LOC
side” O
on O
whether O
Griner’s O
conviction O
opens O
new O
doors O
for O
negotiations O
of O
a O
prisoner O
swap, O
National B-ORG
Security I-ORG
Council I-ORG
spokesperson O
John B-PER
Kirby I-PER
said. O

We’re O
still O
open O
to O
having O
our O
proposal O
seriously O
and O
positively O
considered O
, O
and O
if O
on O
the O
Russian B-LOC
side O
that O
means O
they O
feel O
like O
they’re O
more O
empowered O
to O
do O
that O
, O
then O
so O
be O
it O
, O
Kirby B-PER
told O
reporters O
in O
Thursday’s O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
briefing O
. O

Kirby B-PER
reiterated O
the O
US O
position O
remains O
that O
it O
wants O
Russia B-LOC
to O
“take O
the O
deal O
on O
the O
table O
because O
it’s O
a O
good O
one O
, O
it’s O
a O
fair O
one O
, O
and O
it’ll O
help O
bring O
Paul B-PER
and O
Brittney B-PER
home O
. O

CNN B-ORG
National O
Security O
Analyst O
Steve B-PER
Hall I-PER
said O
the O
harsh O
sentence O
was O
not O
a O
surprise O
and O
argued O
that O
Russia’s B-LOC
court O
proceedings O
are O
not O
legitimate O
. O

This O
is O
all O
performance O
in O
Russia B-LOC
. O

There O
was O
never O
any O
doubt O
as O
to O
what O
was O
going O
to O
happen O
,” O
he O
said O
. O
“ O

What O
Vladimir B-PER
Putin I-PER
is O
trying O
to O
do O
is O
basically O
drive O
up O
the O
bargaining O
price O
of O
Ms. O
Griner B-PER
. O

Last O
week O
, O
CNN B-ORG
reported O
that O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration O
proposed O
a O
prisoner O
swap O
with O
Russia B-LOC
, O
offering O
to O
release O
a O
convicted O
Russian O
arms O
trafficker O
, O
Viktor B-PER
Bout I-PER
, O
in O
exchange O
for O
Griner O
and O
Whelan O
. O

Russian B-LOC
officials O
countered O
the O
US B-ORG
offer O
, O
multiple O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
discussions O
have O
said O
, O
but O
US B-ORG
officials O
did O
not O
accept O
the O
request O
as O
a O
legitimate O
counteroffer O
. O

The O
Kremlin B-LOC
warned O
Tuesday O
that O
US O
“megaphone O
diplomacy” O
will O
not O
help O
negotiations O
for O
a O
prisoner O
exchange O
involving O
Griner B-PER

Kremlin B-LOC
spokesperson O
Dmitry B-PER
Peskov I-PER
said O
Moscow B-LOC
believes O
these O
talks O
should O
be O
“discrete.” O

Griner’s O
WNBA O
team O
, O
the O
Phoenix B-LOC
Mercury I-ORG
, O
played O
the O
Connecticut B-LOC
Sun I-ORG
on O
Thursday O
night O
. O

Before O
the O
game O
, O
the O
teams O
held O
a O
42-second O
moment O
of O
silence O
as O
players O
linked O
arms O
. O

Near O
the O
end O
of O
the O
tribute O
, O
spectators O
started O
chanting O
, O
“ O
Bring O
her O
home O
! O

Bring O
her O
home O
! O

Griner O
, O
a O
six-time O
WNBA O
all-star O
, O
wears O
No O
. O

42 O
for O
the O
Mercury O
. O

The O
Mercury B-ORG
lost O
77-64 O

Point O
guard O
Skylar B-PER
Diggins-Smith I-PER
, O
wearing O
a O
“ O
We O
Are O
BG O
” O
T-shirt O
, O
said O
after O
the O
game O
the O
verdict O
was O
devastating O
. O

Nobody O
wanted O
to O
even O
play O
today O
,” O
she O
told O
reporters O
. O
“ O

How O
are O
you O
supposed O
to O
approach O
the O
game O
, O
approach O
the O
court O
and O
with O
a O
clear O
mind O
, O
and O
our O
whole O
group O
is O
crying O
before O
the O
game O
? O

Because O
you O
try O
to O
honor O
her O
and O
you O
try O
to O
come O
out O
and O
still O
play O
hard O
for O
her O

Earlier, O
the O
Mercury B-ORG
released O
a O
statement O
calling O
the O
verdict O
“ O
a O
sobering O
milestone O
in O
the O
168-day O
nightmare” O
of O
her O
detention. O

We O
are O
inspired O
every O
day O
by O
BG’s O
strength O
and O
we O
are O
steadfastly O
committed O
to O
keeping O
her O
top-of-mind O
publicly O
until O
she O
is O
safely O
back O
on O
American B-LOC
soil O

We O
will O
not O
allow O
her O
to O
be O
forgotten O

We O
are O
BG O
,” O
the O
statement O
reads O
. O

Head O
coach O
Vanessa B-PER
Nygaard I-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
the O
guilty O
verdict O
and O
Griner’s O
sentence O
is O
“unacceptable.” O

It’s O
just O
heartbreaking O
the O
coach O
said O
.” O

To O
hear O
her O
words O
and O
her O
apologies O
. O

Just O
trying O
to O
send O
love O
, O
prayers O
and O
strength O
to O
her O
. O

In O
a O
joint O
statement O
, O
WNBA O
Commissioner O
Cathy B-PER
Engelbert I-PER
and O
NBA O
Commissioner O
Adam B-PER
Silver I-PER
criticized O
the O
verdict O
and O
sentence O
as O
“unjustified O
and O
unfortunate O
, O
but O
not O
unexpected O
. O

The O
WNBA B-ORG
and O
NBA’s B-ORG
commitment O
to O
her O
safe O
return O
has O
not O
wavered O
and O
it O
is O
our O
hope O
that O
we O
are O
near O
the O
end O
of O
this O
process O
of O
finally O
bringing O
BG O
home O
to O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
,” O
they O
said O

Defense O
asked O
for O
leniency O
in O
closing O
arguments O
The O
court O
hearing O
Thursday O
began O
shortly O
after O
Griner B-PER
arrived O
in O
handcuffs O
, O
escorted O
by O
Russian B-LOC
officers O
into O
the O
defendant’s O
cage O

Once O
uncuffed O
, O
she O
spoke O
with O
her O
legal O
team O
and O
then O
held O
up O
a O
photo O
of O
the O
UMMC B-ORG
Ekaterinburg B-LOC
basketball O
team O
, O
the O
Russian B-LOC
squad O
she O
played O
for O
during O
the O
WNBA O
offseason O
. O

In O
closing O
arguments O
, O
Blagovolina B-PER
argued O
that O
Griner B-PER
never O
used O
marijuana O
in O
Russia B-LOC
and O
that O
she O
never O
had O
the O
intention O
of O
doing O
so O
. O

She O
had O
no O
need O
to O
bring O
the O
vape O
cartridges O
to O
Russia B-LOC
, O
the O
lawyer O
added O
. O

All O
this O
confirms O
the O
complete O
absence O
of O
intent O
in O
her O
actions O
, O
Blagovolina B-PER
argued O
. O

Even O
if O
Griner O
ever O
used O
medical O
marijuana O
, O
it O
was O
only O
at O
home O
back O
in O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
rare O
and O
only O
with O
a O
doctor’s O
prescription O
, O
she O
added O
. O

She O
couldn’t O
have O
known O
how O
strict O
the O
laws O
were O
in O
Russia B-LOC
, O
Blagovolina B-PER
said O
. O

Boykov B-PER
also O
argued O
Griner B-PER
had O
no O
opportunity O
to O
properly O
examine O
the O
court O
documents O

He O
said O
that O
the O
Russian B-LOC
constitution O
guarantees O
everyone O
the O
right O
to O
use O
their O
native O
language O
and O
the O
free O
choice O
of O
the O
language O
of O
communication O

Boykov B-PER
cited O
an O
instance O
when O
a O
language O
interpreter O
provided O
to O
Griner B-PER
flipped O
through O
a O
lengthy O
document O
offered O
by O
an O
investigator O
for O
translation O
and O
then O
told O
Griner B-PER
, O
“ O
Basically O
, O
it O
means O
that O
you O
are O
guilty O
. O
” O

Throughout O
the O
trial O
, O
Griner’s O
attorneys O
have O
laid O
out O
arguments O
undermining O
the O
prosecution’s O
case O
and O
claiming O
her O
detention O
was O
not O
handled O
correctly O
after O
she O
was O
stopped O
February O
17 O
by O
personnel O
at O
the O
Sheremetyevo B-LOC
International I-LOC
Airport I-LOC
. O

Her O
detention O
, O
search O
and O
arrest O
were O
“improper,” O
Boykov B-PER
said O
last O
week O
, O
noting O
more O
details O
would O
be O
revealed O
during O
closing O
arguments O
. O

After O
she O
was O
stopped O
in O
the O
airport O
, O
Griner B-PER
was O
made O
to O
sign O
documents O
that O
she O
did O
not O
fully O
understand O
, O
she O
testified O
. O

At O
first O
, O
she O
said O
, O
she O
was O
using O
Google B-ORG
translate O
on O
her O
phone O
but O
was O
later O
moved O
to O
another O
room O
where O
her O
phone O
was O
taken O
and O
she O
was O
made O
to O
sign O
more O
documents O
. O

No O
lawyer O
was O
present O
, O
Griner B-PER
testified O
, O
and O
her O
rights O
were O
not O
explained O
to O
her O
. O

Those O
rights O
would O
include O
access O
to O
an O
attorney O
once O
she O
was O
detained O
and O
the O
right O
to O
know O
what O
she O
was O
suspected O
of O

Under O
Russian B-LOC
law O
, O
she O
should O
have O
been O
informed O
of O
her O
rights O
within O
three O
hours O
of O
her O
arrest O
. O

On O
Tuesday O
, O
at O
the O
seventh O
hearing O
in O
her O
case O
, O
a O
defense O
expert O
testified O
that O
the O
examination O
of O
the O
substance O
contained O
in O
Griner’s B-PER
vape O
cartridges O
did O
not O
comply O
with O
Russian B-LOC
law O
. O

Blagovolina B-PER
also O
told O
CNN B-ORG
her O
team’s O
experts O
identified O
“ O
a O
few O
defects O
” O
in O
the O
machines O
used O
to O
measure O
the O
substance O

At O
trial O
, O
Griner B-PER
testified O
she O
has O
a O
doctor’s O
prescription O
for O
medical O
cannabis O
and O
had O
no O
intention O
of O
bringing O
the O
drug O
into O
Russia B-LOC
. O

Following O
her O
detention O
in O
February O
, O
she O
was O
tested O
for O
drugs O
and O
was O
clean O
, O
her O
lawyers O
previously O
said O
. O

We O
continue O
to O
insist O
that O
, O
by O
indiscretion O
, O
in O
a O
hurry O
, O
she O
packed O
her O
suitcase O
and O
did O
not O
pay O
attention O
to O
the O
fact O
that O
substances O
allowed O
for O
use O
in B-LOC
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
ended O
up O
in O
this O
suitcase O
and O
arrived O
in O
the O
Russian B-LOC
Federation I-LOC
, O
” O
Boykov B-PER
, O
of O
Moscow B-ORG
Legal I-ORG
Center I-ORG
, O
has O
said O
. O

CNN B-ORG
’s O
Jill B-PER
Martin I-PER
, O
Elizabeth B-PER
Wolfe I-PER
, O
Allie B-PER
Malloy I-PER
, O
Travis B-PER
Caldwell I-PER
, O
Dakin B-PER
Andone I-PER
, O
Kylie B-PER
Atwood I-PER
, O
Evan B-PER
Perez I-PER
, O
Jennifer B-PER
Hansler I-PER
, O
Natasha B-PER
Bertrand I-PER
, O
Carolyn B-PER
Manno I-PER
and O
Frederik B-PER
Pleitgen I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Congress B-ORG
has O
passed O
a O
bill O
that O
will O
invest O
more O
than O
$200 O
billion O
over O
the O
next O
five O
years O
to O
help O
the O
US B-LOC
regain O
a O
leading O
position O
in O
semiconductor O
chip O
manufacturing O

With O
bipartisan O
support O
, O
the O
CHIPS O
and O
Science O
Act O
was O
passed O
by O
lawmakers O
in O
late O
July B-LOC
, O
and O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
signed O
the O
bill O
into O
law O
Tuesday O
. O

Once O
a O
leader O
in O
semiconductor O
chip O
manufacturing O
, O
the O
US B-LOC
has O
lost O
ground O
as O
other O
countries O
like O
China B-LOC
ramped O
up O
production O
, O
forcing O
many O
American B-LOC
manufacturers O
to O
import O
chips O
– O
which O
are O
essential O
to O
the O
production O
of O
cars O
, O
smartphones O
and O
medical O
equipment O
. O

The O
new O
funding O
is O
intended O
to O
help O
companies O
bring O
chip O
manufacturing O
back O
to O
the O
US B-LOC
and O
as O
a O
result O
, O
help O
lower O
costs O
and O
prevent O
supply O
chain O
disruptions O

The O
current O
global O
chip O
shortage O
has O
limited O
production O
of O
new O
vehicles O
, O
for O
example O
, O
leaving O
Americans B-LOC
facing O
stubbornly O
high O
car O
prices O
. O

Chip O
maker O
Intel B-ORG
is O
already O
expected O
to O
reap O
some O
of O
the O
benefits O
of O
the O
new O
funding O
, O
specifically O
to O
help O
boost O
its O
previously O
announced O
investment O
to O
build O
a O
semiconductor O
plant O
in O
Ohio B-LOC
. O

This O
new O
law O
gives O
people O
like O
me O
a O
chance O
and O
allows O
us O
to O
grow O
our O
businesses O
, O
said O
Joshua B-PER
Aviv I-PER
at O
the O
bill O
signing O
event O
at O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
on O
Tuesday O
. O

Aviv B-PER
is O
the O
CEO O
and O
founder O
of O
an O
electric O
vehicle O
charging O
company O
called O
SparkCharge B-ORG
that O
manufactures O
its O
parts O
at O
a O
factory O
in O
Buffalo B-LOC
, O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
. O

For O
years O
, O
my O
industry O
has O
been O
at O
the O
mercy O
of O
the O
supply O
chain O
, O
” O
Aviv B-PER
added O
. O

The O
legislation O
will O
spend O
money O
on O
a O
variety O
of O
manufacturing O
incentives O
aimed O
at O
boosting O
American B-LOC
chip O
manufacturing O
as O
well O
as O
investments O
in O
research O
development O
and O
workforce O
training O

The O
spending O
is O
not O
paid O
for O
by O
any O
offsets O
and O
instead O
will O
add O
to O
the O
federal O
deficit O

Here’s O
what O
is O
in O
the O
spending O
package O
, O
according O
to O
summaries O
by O
Democratic B-ORG
leadership I-ORG
. O

$52.7 O
billion O
for O
chip O
manufacturing O
and O
research O
The O
package O
will O
invest O
$39 O
billion O
over O
five O
years O
to O
expand O
domestic O
semiconductor O
manufacturing O

It O
will O
provide O
companies O
incentives O
to O
build O
, O
expand O
and O
modernize O
US O
facilities O
and O
equipment O
. O

The O
legislation O
will O
also O
create O
a O
new O
25% O
tax O
credit O
for O
companies O
that O
invest O
in O
semiconductor O
manufacturing O
equipment O
or O
the O
construction O
of O
manufacturing O
facilities O

Private O
companies O
that O
receive O
financial O
assistance O
will O
be O
restricted O
from O
expanding O
certain O
chip O
manufacturing O
in O
China B-LOC
for O
10 O
years O

The O
law O
will O
provide O
$11 O
billion O
over O
five O
years O
to O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Commerce I-ORG
to O
help O
spur O
research O
and O
development O
in O
advanced O
semiconductor O
manufacturing O
, O
to O
invest O
in O
new O
technologies O
and O
expand O
workforce O
training O
opportunities O
. O

Another O
$1.5 O
billion O
will O
fund O
the O
Public B-ORG
Wireless I-ORG
Supply I-ORG
Chain I-ORG
Innovation I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
to O
help O
telecommunications O
companies O
compete O
with O
Chinese B-LOC
telecom O
giant O
Huawei B-ORG
and O
limit O
the O
scope O
of O
other O
telecommunications O
companies O
with O
close O
ties O
to O
China B-LOC
. O

Millions O
of O
dollars O
will O
target O
workforce O
development O
to O
make O
sure O
workers O
are O
available O
to O
support O
more O
manufacturing O

$170 O
billion O
for O
scientific O
research O
, O
innovation O
and O
space O
exploration O
The O
legislation O
calls O
for O
a O
historic O
investment O
in O
scientific O
research O
and O
development O
that O
amounts O
to O
nearly O
$170 O
billion O
over O
five O
years O
, O
an O
$82.5 O
billion O
increase O
in O
the O
federal O
government’s O
baseline O
authorization O
. O

The O
majority O
of O
that O
funding O
will O
funnel O
through O
two O
government O
agencies O
: O
the O
National B-ORG
Science I-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
and O
the O
Department B-ORG
of O
Energy’s B-ORG
Office I-ORG
of O
Science O
. O

The O
investments O
will O
help O
create O
a O
National B-ORG
Science I-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
Directorate I-ORG
for I-ORG
Technology I-ORG
, O
Innovation I-ORG
and I-ORG
Partnerships I-ORG
to O
accelerate O
American B-LOC
development O
in O
technologies O
like O
artificial O
intelligence O
, O
quantum O
computing O
, O
advanced O
manufacturing O
, O
6G O
communications O
, O
energy O
and O
materials O
science O
. O

The O
federal O
funding O
will O
also O
fund O
the O
creation O
of O
new O
regional O
technology O
hubs O
across O
the O
country O
, O
strengthen O
small O
manufacturers O
as O
well O
as O
reduce O
long-term O
supply O
chain O
vulnerabilities O
in O
areas O
such O
as O
advanced O
manufacturing O
, O
next-generation O
communications O
, O
computer O
hardware O
and O
pharmaceuticals O
. O

About O
$13 O
billion O
will O
go O
to O
education O
in O
the O
science O
, O
technology O
, O
engineering O
and O
math O
fields O
– O
known O
as O
STEM O
– O
including O
scholarships O
and O
fellowships O
, O
with O
a O
focus O
of O
increasing O
access O
to O
education O
in O
these O
fields O
in O
rural O
areas O
. O

Universities O
, O
community O
colleges O
and O
high O
schools O
may O
be O
eligible O
for O
the O
money O
in O
an O
effort O
to O
strengthen O
America’s B-LOC
workforce O
so O
that O
it O
can O
support O
new O
chip O
manufacturing O
. O

There O
is O
a O
great O
deal O
of O
money O
focused O
on O
providing O
the O
needed O
talent O
, O
said O
Rep. O
Eddie B-PER
Bernice I-PER
Johnson I-PER
of O
Texas B-LOC
, O
chairwoman O
of O
the O
House B-ORG
Committee I-ORG
on O
Science I-ORG
, O
Space I-ORG
and I-ORG
Technology I-ORG
. O

The O
legislation O
also O
provides O
new O
funding O
for O
NASA B-ORG
, O
with O
the O
goals O
of O
sending O
astronauts O
to O
Mars B-LOC
and O
the O
first O
woman O
and O
person O
of O
color O
to O
the O
moon O
. O

This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
information O
. O

Everett B-LOC
Police I-ORG
in O
Washington B-LOC
state O
is O
hoping O
the O
public O
can O
help O
identify O
the O
man O
that O
stiffed O
an O
11-year-old O
boy O
with O
a O
fake O
$100 O
bill O
to O
buy O
lemonade O
from O
his O
stand O
. O

Over O
the O
summer O
, O
an O
11-year-old O
Jeremy B-PER
spent O
his O
allowance O
money O
to O
set O
up O
a O
lemonade O
stand O
on O
Beverly B-LOC
Blvd I-LOC
. O

As O
he O
worked O
in O
the O
sun O
trying O
to O
earn O
a O
little O
extra O
spending O
money O
, O
he O
was O
approached O
by O
the O
pictured O
suspect O
, O
who O
offered O
him O
a O
100-dollar O
bill O
for O
a O
drink O
but O
asked O
for O
exact O
change O
, O
” O
Everett B-ORG
Police I-ORG
said O
in O
a O
Facebook B-ORG
post O
. O

Jeremy B-PER
used O
all O
his O
allowance O
money O
to O
give O
the O
man O
$85 O
dollars O
in O
change O
, O
only O
to O
later O
find O
out O
that O
the O
$100 O
dollar O
bill O
was O
fake O
when O
he O
went O
to O
a O
local O
gas O
station O
to O
buy O
something O
and O
was O
left O
with O
no O
allowance O
money O
. O

However O
, O
this O
sad O
story O
does O
have O
a O
good O
ending O
. O

When O
a O
neighbor O
of O
the O
family O
found O
out O
what O
happened O
to O
Jeremy B-PER
, O
she O
helped O
organize O
a O
GoFundMe B-ORG
account O
for O
him O
that O
has O
so O
far O
raised O
more O
than O
$ O
1,800 O
. O

Police O
are O
asking O
anyone O
with O
information O
on O
the O
suspect O
to O
please O
call O
( O
425 O
) O
257 O
- O
8450 O
, O
or O
to O
send O
a O
Facebook B-ORG
message O

Netflix B-ORG
has O
had O
a O
terrible O
2022 O

In O
April O
, O
it O
said O
it O
lost O
subscribers O
for O
the O
first O
time O
since O
2011 O
. O

Its O
stock O
has O
tumbled O
more O
than O
60% O
so O
far O
this O
year O

Yet O
its O
recent O
struggles O
may O
not O
be O
the O
start O
of O
a O
downward O
spiral O
or O
the O
beginning O
of O
the O
end O
for O
the O
streaming O
giant O

Rather, O
it’s O
a O
sign O
that O
Netflix B-ORG
is O
becoming O
a O
more O
traditional O
media O
company. O

Netflix B-ORG
(NFLX) O
was O
originally O
valued O
as O
a O
Big O
Tech O
company O
, O
part O
of O
the O
Wall B-LOC
Street I-LOC
acronym O
, O
“FAANG,” O
which O
stood O
for O
Facebook B-ORG
(FB), O
Apple B-ORG
(AAPL), O
Amazon B-ORG
(AMZN), O
Netflix B-ORG
(NFLX) O
and O
Google B-ORG
(GOOG). O

Wall B-LOC
Street I-LOC
once O
valued O
the O
company O
at O
about O
$300 O
billion O
— O
a O
number O
on O
par O
with O
many O
Big B-ORG
Tech I-ORG
companies O
that O
Netflix B-ORG
(NFLX) O
’s O
business O
model O
ultimately O
couldn’t O
live O
up O
to O
. O

I O
think O
Netflix B-ORG
was O
extremely O
overvalued O
,” O
Julia B-PER
Alexander I-PER
, O
director O
of O
strategy O
at O
Parrot B-ORG
Analytics I-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
Business I-ORG
. O

Unlike O
those O
companies O
that O
have O
different O
tentacles O
, O
Netflix B-ORG
does O
not O
have O
a O
lot O
of O
tentacles O
. O

But O
Netflix B-ORG
was O
never O
really O
a O
tech O
company O
. O

Yes O
, O
it O
relied O
on O
subscriber O
growth O
like O
many O
companies O
in O
the O
tech O
world O
, O
but O
its O
subscriber O
growth O
was O
built O
on O
having O
films O
and O
TV O
shows O
that O
people O
wanted O
to O
watch O
and O
pay O
for O
. O

That’s O
more O
a O
like O
a O
studio O
in O
Hollywood B-LOC
than O
a O
tech O
company O
in O
Silicon B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
. O

Netflix B-ORG
looked O
a O
lot O
more O
like O
a O
tech O
company O
than O
, O
say O
, O
Disney B-ORG
, O
Comcast B-ORG
, O
Paramount B-ORG
or O
CNN B-ORG
parent O
company O
Warner B-ORG
Bros I-ORG
. O
Discovery I-ORG
. O

But O
as O
those O
traditional O
media O
companies O
start O
to O
look O
a O
lot O
more O
like O
Netflix B-ORG
, O
Netflix B-ORG
in O
turn O
is O
starting O
to O
take O
page O
out O
of O
its O
rivals’ O
playbooks O
: O
It’s O
going O
to O
start O
serving O
ads O
and O
it O
has O
been O
releasing O
some O
shows O
over O
the O
course O
of O
weeks O
and O
months O
rather O
than O
all O
at O
once O
. O

Netflix B-ORG
has O
said O
that O
its O
cheaper O
ad O
tier O
and O
clampdown O
on O
password O
sharing O
may O
come O
next O
year O

It’s O
partnering O
with O
Microsoft B-ORG
(MSFT) O
for O
its O
ad O
business O
. O

I O
think O
in O
many O
ways O
the O
moves O
Netflix B-ORG
are O
making O
suggest O
a O
transition O
from O
tech O
company O
to O
media O
company O
,” O
Andrew B-PER
Hare I-PER
, O
a O
senior O
vice O
president O
of O
research O
at O
Magid B-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
Business I-ORG
. O

With O
the O
introduction O
of O
ads O
, O
crackdown O
on O
password O
sharing O
, O
marquee O
shows O
like O
‘Stranger B-ORG
Things’ I-ORG
experimenting O
with O
a O
staggered O
release O
, O
we O
are O
seeing O
Netflix B-ORG
looking O
more O
like O
a O
traditional O
media O
company O
every O
day O
. O

Hare B-PER
added O
that O
Netflix’s B-ORG
former O
business O
strategy O
, O
which O
was O
“ O
once O
sacrosanct O
is O
now O
being O
thrown O
out O
the O
window O
. O

Netflix B-ORG
once O
forced O
Hollywood B-LOC
deeply O
out O
of O
its O
comfort O
zone O
. O

They O
brought O
streaming O
to O
the O
American B-LOC
living O
room,” O
he O
said. O

Now O
it O
appears O
some O
more O
conventional O
practices O
could O
be O
what O
Netflix B-ORG
needs O
. O

At O
Netflix B-ORG
right O
now O
, O
“ O
a O
lot O
of O
these O
strategic O
moves O
are O
being O
made O
as O
they O
mature O
and O
move O
into O
the O
next O
phase O
as O
a O
company O
, O
” O
noted O
Hare B-PER
. O

That O
includes O
focusing O
on O
cash O
flow O
and O
revenue O
rather O
than O
just O
growth O
. O

In O
other O
words O
, O
old O
school O
business O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
— O

CNN B-ORG
Business’ I-ORG
Moss B-PER
Cohen I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report. O

It’s O
hard O
to O
believe O
we O
are O
face-to-face O
with O
a O
new O
health O
crisis O
, O
monkeypox O
, O
before O
we O
are O
even O
out O
of O
the O
woods O
with O
the O
previous O
– O
but O
still O
very O
much O
current O
– O
crisis O
, O
Covid-19 O
. O

The O
pandemic O
, O
which O
has O
held O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
and O
almost O
every O
other O
country O
in O
its O
grip O
, O
should O
have O
taught O
us O
valuable O
lessons O
about O
how O
to O
manage O
a O
public O
health O
emergency O
, O
but O
it O
seems O
we O
are O
making O
some O
of O
the O
same O
mistakes O
we O
made O
not O
even O
three O
years O
ago O
, O
when O
the O
SARS-CoV-2 O
virus O
started O
to O
spread O
. O

Testing O
for O
the O
monkeypox O
virus O
, O
once O
very O
limited O
, O
is O
now O
more O
available O
, O
but O
underused O
. O

The O
demand O
for O
vaccines O
is O
outpacing O
the O
supply O

There O
are O
nearly O
2 O
million O
courses O
the O
highly O
effective O
TPOXX O
antiviral O
sitting O
in O
the O
Strategic B-ORG
National I-ORG
Stockpile I-ORG
, O
but O
many O
health O
care O
providers O
are O
still O
having O
a O
hard O
time O
getting O
the O
medication O
for O
their O
patients O
. O

We O
are O
one O
of O
the O
wealthiest O
countries O
in O
the O
world O
, O
spending O
more O
than O
$4 O
trillion O
dollars O
a O
year O
on O
health O
care O
, O
more O
per O
person O
than O
anywhere O
else O
. O

With O
all O
those O
resources O
and O
technology O
, O
it’s O
not O
as O
if O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
is O
incapable O
of O
mounting O
a O
significant O
response O
to O
an O
emerging O
outbreak O
. O

And O
there O
is O
little O
doubt O
we O
will O
eventually O
do O
what O
should O
have O
already O
been O
done O
: O
declare O
monkeypox O
a O
public O
health O
emergency O
, O
appoint O
a O
national O
coordinator O
and O
mount O
a O
more O
significant O
response O
. O

But O
why O
do O
we O
wait O
so O
long O
, O
drag O
our O
feet O
and O
endure O
so O
much O
suffering O
in O
the O
meantime O
. O

As O
I O
have O
learned O
over O
the O
past O
few O
years O
, O
there O
is O
a O
significant O
difference O
between O
preparedness O
and O
response O
, O
even O
though O
the O
two O
are O
often O
conflated O
. O

The O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
is O
extraordinarily O
prepared O
, O
ranked O
No O
. O

1 O
for O
pandemic O
preparedness O
in O
the O
2021 O
Global B-ORG
Health I-ORG
Security I-ORG
Index I-ORG
. O

Instead, O
we O
are O
leading O
in O
a O
different O
way. O

As O
of O
today O
, O
we O
have O
the O
most O
confirmed O
cases O
of O
monkeypox O
on O
the O
planet O
, O
more O
than O
5,000 O
. O

That O
is O
almost O
25% O
of O
the O
global O
numbers O
, O
even O
though O
we O
are O
just O
under O
5% O
of O
the O
world’s O
population O
. O

It O
is O
now O
clear O
: O
Preparedness O
alone O
does O
not O
guarantee O
a O
rapid O
response O
. O

With O
Covid-19 O
, O
and O
now O
monkeypox O
, O
we O
were O
too O
slow O
to O
respond O
. O

It O
was O
as O
if O
we O
are O
sitting O
in O
a O
turbo-charged O
Ferrari B-ORG
, O
capable O
of O
massive O
acceleration O
, O
but O
instead O
only O
idling O
in O
the O
driveway O
. O

Cavalry O
culture O
Over O
the O
past O
three O
years O
, O
we O
have O
witnessed O
something O
counterintuitive O
. O

It O
was O
predominantly O
wealthy O
countries O
that O
were O
hit O
hardest O
during O
the O
Covid-19 O
pandemic O
. O

They O
had O
some O
of O
the O
highest O
death O
rates O
, O
despite O
their O
enormous O
resources O
. O

While O
there O
are O
many O
reasons O
for O
this O
, O
including O
misinformation O
, O
lack O
of O
public O
trust O
, O
and O
the O
entangling O
of O
public O
health O
and O
politics O
, O
I O
think O
there O
is O
something O
else O
, O
as O
well O
: O
We O
have O
adopted O
what O
I O
call O
a O
“cavalry O
culture.” O

We O
wait O
for O
the O
cavalry O
to O
ride O
in O
and O
rescue O
us O
, O
instead O
of O
taking O
smaller O
preventive O
steps O
– O
such O
as O
establishing O
modern O
and O
reliable O
data O
systems O
, O
mastering O
our O
supply O
chain O
along O
the O
way O
, O
and O
acting O
early O
to O
head O
off O
the O
outbreak O
in O
the O
first O
place O
. O

If O
that O
sounds O
familiar O
, O
it’s O
because O
we O
too O
often O
do O
the O
same O
with O
our O
personal O
health O
matters O
. O

According O
to O
research O
published O
in O
The B-ORG
Lancet I-ORG
Public I-ORG
Health I-ORG
, O
nearly O
half O
of O
chronic O
disease O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
is O
mostly O
preventable O
, O
with O
lifestyle O
changes O
. O

Even O
knowing O
that O
, O
however O
, O
the O
medical O
system O
is O
set O
up O
for O
the O
cavalry O
to O
come O
in O
with O
expensive O
medications O
and O
high-tech O
interventions O
, O
instead O
of O
providing O
equitable O
access O
and O
incentives O
for O
preventative O
care O
. O

There O
are O
a O
couple O
of O
important O
axioms O
in O
public O
health O
. O

One O
is O
by O
the O
time O
you O
think O
you O
must O
act O
to O
contain O
an O
outbreak O
, O
it O
is O
already O
too O
late O
. O

And, O
if O
you O
think O
you O
are O
overreacting, O
you O
are O
probably O
reacting O
just O
the O
right O
amount. O

In O
the O
case O
of O
Covid O
, O
and O
now O
monkeypox O
, O
we O
seem O
to O
have O
forgotten O
those O
basic O
public O
health O
principles O
. O

And, O
the O
real O
question O
now O
seems O
to O
be: O
When O
will O
the O
government O
finally O
hit O
the O
gas O
pedal O
on O
our O
highly O
tuned O
Ferrari? B-ORG

I O
don’t O
want O
to O
suggest O
any O
of O
this O
is O
easy O

There O
are O
significant O
issues O
of O
uncertainty O
and O
unpredictability O

Much O
like O
a O
hurricane O
forming O
at O
sea O
, O
we O
often O
don’t O
know O
exactly O
where O
or O
how O
hard O
it O
will O
hit O
. O

We O
want O
to O
be O
measured O
, O
calm O
in O
our O
response O
and O
to O
cause O
as O
little O
disruption O
as O
possible O
. O

We O
want O
to O
be O
thoughtful O
and O
gather O
as O
much O
information O
as O
is O
available O

And O
therein O
lies O
one O
of O
our O
biggest O
problems O
: O
basic O
data O
. O

I O
have O
often O
wondered O
, O
how O
is O
it O
that O
a O
numbers-driven O
, O
high-tech O
country O
like O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
can’t O
get O
basic O
data O
right O
. O

Data O
disaster O
As O
long O
as O
I’ve O
been O
reporting O
on O
the O
Covid O
pandemic O
, O
I O
have O
always O
had O
to O
offer O
the O
caveat O
that O
case O
numbers O
are O
probably O
off O
, O
sometimes O
wildly O
so O
. O

We O
have O
probably O
never O
had O
a O
clear O
vision O
on O
just O
how O
widely O
the O
virus O
was O
spreading O
at O
any O
given O
time O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
, O
and O
going O
into O
the O
fall O
2022 O
, O
the O
situation O
isn’t O
really O
any O
better O
. O

In O
early O
July O
, O
the O
Institute B-ORG
for I-ORG
Health I-ORG
Metrics I-ORG
, O
a O
research O
center O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Washington I-ORG
, O
released O
a O
model O
suggesting O
that O
actual O
Covid-19 O
cases O
are O
seven O
times O
higher O
than O
reported O
cases O
. O

At O
times O
, O
it O
seems O
the O
tech O
platforms O
for O
Snapchat B-ORG
and O
Twitter B-ORG
offer O
more O
data O
analytics O
than O
the O
patchwork O
of O
state O
and O
federal O
systems O
that O
underpin O
the O
public O
health O
of O
our O
country O
. O

First, O
there’s O
a O
lack O
of O
data O
access O
needed O
to O
understand O
where O
disease O
outbreaks O
are O
spreading. O

This O
is O
due O
to O
data O
collection O
limitations O
that O
Congress B-ORG
needs O
to O
fix O
,” O
said O
Dr. O
Tom B-PER
Frieden I-PER
, O
president O
and O
CEO O
of O
Resolve B-ORG
to I-ORG
Save I-ORG
Lives I-ORG
and O
a O
former O
director O
of O
the O
US B-ORG
Centers I-ORG
for I-ORG
Disease I-ORG
Control I-ORG
and I-ORG
Prevention I-ORG
. O

He O
said O
there O
is O
also O
a O
need O
to O
update O
analog O
systems O
and O
connect O
them O
to O
each O
other O
– O
getting O
them O
to O
speak O
the O
same O
language O

Right O
now O
, O
it’s O
the O
Tower O
of O
Babel O
. O

Second, O
we O
lack O
sufficient O
numbers O
and, O
in O
some O
cases, O
skills O
of O
people O
and O
systems O
at O
the O
federal, O
state O
and O
local O
levels O
that O
can O
deliver O
services O
and O
communicate O
effectively O
with O
communities. O

Finally O
, O
we O
are O
in O
perpetual O
panic O
and O
neglect O
funding O
cycles O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

As O
a O
result O
of O
all O
of O
the O
things O
Frieden B-PER
is O
describing O
, O
our O
current O
data O
collection O
and O
reporting O
system O
leaves O
important O
information O
fractured O
into O
dozens O
of O
states O
and O
territories O
, O
and O
thousands O
of O
county O
pieces O
for O
the O
CDC B-ORG
to O
puzzle O
together O
. O

I O
have O
been O
struck O
as O
we O
at O
CDC B-ORG
are O
now O
conquering O
another O
public O
health O
challenge O
– O
monkeypox O
– O
as O
to O
how O
little O
authority O
we O
at O
CDC B-ORG
have O
to O
receive O
the O
data O
,” O
CDC B-ORG
Director O
Dr. O
Rochelle B-PER
Walensky I-PER
told O
the O
Washington B-LOC
Post I-LOC
. O

Walensky B-PER
is O
talking O
about O
basic O
data O
, O
like O
where O
the O
vaccine O
has O
gone O
, O
who O
has O
been O
vaccinated O
, O
whether O
the O
vaccine O
is O
working O
, O
and O
even O
monkeypox O
case O
data O
like O
who O
is O
getting O
infected O
, O
their O
age O
and O
race/ethnicity O
. O

Why O
might O
this O
be O
so O
? O

States O
don’t O
routinely O
share O
vaccine O
doses O
administered O
data O
with O
the O
federal O
government O
– O
Covid O
was O
really O
the O
first O
time O
that O
we O
were O
able O
to O
successfully O
put O
data O
use O
agreements O
in O
place O
,” O
Claire B-PER
Hannan I-PER
, O
the O
executive O
director O
of O
the O
Association B-ORG
of I-ORG
Immunization I-ORG
Managers I-ORG
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

Part O
of O
the O
reason O
is O
because O
“states O
have O
laws O
in O
place O
to O
protect O
identifiable O
information.” O

Some O
information O
has O
been O
getting O
to O
the O
CDC B-ORG
, O
but O
it O
is O
challenging O
to O
get O
and O
incomplete O
. O

The O
CDC O
director O
told O
the O
Washington B-LOC
Post I-LOC
, O
“ O
We O
have O
been O
speaking O
to O
our O
state O
and O
local O
partners O
probably O
at O
least O
three O
times O
a O
week O
, O
all O
of O
them O
. O
… O

That O
is O
not O
how O
you O
synthesize O
data O

We O
need O
… O
standardization O
of O
those O
data O
, O
and O
we O
need O
to O
have O
those O
data O
come O
to O
us O
in O
a O
standardized O
fashion O
so O
that O
they O
can O
be O
connected O
, O
we O
can O
compile O
them O
and O
rapidly O
report O
them O
out O
. O

We O
cannot O
at O
CDC B-ORG
collect O
the O
data O
and O
make O
informed O
decisions O
by O
calling O
64 O
jurisdictions O
, O
and O
honestly O
, O
3,000 O
counties O
. O

The O
CDC B-ORG
is O
currently O
working O
on O
agreements O
that O
would O
broaden O
the O
agency’s O
access O
to O
states’ O
data O
, O
as O
they O
successfully O
did O
with O
Covid O
. O

Hannan B-PER
explained O
“The O
need O
to O
quickly O
get O
the O
[monkeypox] O
vaccine O
out O
left O
no O
time O
to O
get O
data O
sharing O
agreements O
in O
place O
.” O

But O
even O
if O
those O
agreements O
were O
in O
place O
, O
it O
still O
doesn’t O
mean O
the O
states’ O
ability O
to O
actually O
obtain O
vaccine O
doses O
would O
be O
made O
any O
easier O
. O

That’s O
because O
the O
states O
wouldn’t O
be O
using O
the O
same O
data O
system O
for O
ordering O
and O
tracking O
doses O
they O
generally O
use O

Because O
the O
US O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Health I-ORG
and I-ORG
Human I-ORG
Services I-ORG
and O
the O
Administration B-ORG
for I-ORG
Strategic I-ORG
Preparedness I-ORG
and I-ORG
Response I-ORG
are O
in O
charge O
of O
monkeypox O
vaccine O
distribution O
, O
there O
would O
be O
yet O
another O
data O
system O
involved O
. O

They O
were O
asking O
states O
to O
request O
the O
vaccine O
using O
paper O
forms O
and O
email O
said O
Hannan B-PER

They O
were O
asking O
states O
to O
complete O
forms O
[ O
with O
fillable O
fields O
] O
on O
those O
who O
were O
receiving O
the O
vaccine O
and O
return O
these O
forms O
to O
the O
federal O
government O
. O

The O
problem O
was O
there O
weren’t O
even O
the O
right O
fields O
for O
the O
specific O
questions O
being O
asked O
, O
such O
as O
reason O
for O
vaccination O
or O
type O
of O
exposure O
or O
risk O
, O
Hannan B-PER
said O
. O

It O
wasn’t O
that O
the O
necessary O
forms O
weren’t O
being O
filled O
out O
, O
it O
was O
that O
they O
couldn’t O
be O
filled O
out O
because O
of O
disparate O
data O
platforms O
. O

It O
is O
a O
baffling O
level O
of O
bureaucracy O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
an O
unfolding O
outbreak O

Testing O
, O
vaccines O
, O
therapeutics O
As O
things O
stand O
now O
, O
the O
issues O
with O
data O
collection O
, O
testing O
, O
vaccines O
, O
treatments O
and O
communication O
are O
sounding O
a O
lot O
like O
the O
ones O
we O
experienced O
with O
Covid-19 O
. O

But, O
to O
be O
clear, O
monkeypox O
is O
not O
that O
much O
like O
Covid. O

For O
now O
, O
it O
seems O
to O
spread O
primarily O
through O
sores O
or O
lesions O
during O
close O
, O
personal O
touch O
and O
shared O
objects O
like O
towels O
and O
linens O
, O
as O
well O
as O
respiratory O
secretions O
during O
prolonged O
face-to-face O
contact O
. O

The O
monkeypox O
outbreak O
is O
also O
different O
for O
another O
fundamental O
reason O

Unlike O
with O
Covid O
, O
which O
was O
caused O
by O
a O
novel O
virus O
, O
the O
basic O
tools O
already O
exist O
either O
for O
monkeypox O
or O
its O
close O
relative O
, O
smallpox O
. O

We O
didn’t O
have O
to O
build O
them O
from O
scratch O

That O
means O
we O
could O
have O
had O
them O
or O
put O
them O
to O
better O
use O
by O
now O

Take O
testing O

At O
the O
start O
of O
the O
outbreak O
, O
testing O
capability O
was O
capped O
at O
about O
6,000 O
tests O
per O
week O
, O
which O
meant O
that O
doctors O
really O
had O
to O
ration O
them O
to O
a O
narrow O
group O
of O
people O
– O
primarily O
a O
subset O
of O
men O
who O
have O
sex O
with O
men O
. O

Since O
then O
, O
the O
CDC B-ORG
has O
partnered O
with O
five O
labs O
to O
scale O
up O
our O
capabilities O
and O
we O
should O
soon O
be O
able O
to O
process O
up O
to O
80,000 O
tests O
a O
week O
. O

But O
the O
tests O
are O
being O
underutilized O
, O
according O
to O
CNN B-ORG
reporting O
. O

Experts O
blamed O
the O
low O
uptake O
on O
several O
factors O
, O
including O
a O
lack O
of O
awareness O
among O
doctors O
about O
the O
virus O
and O
the O
fear O
of O
stigma O
among O
patients O
. O

So, O
just O
as O
with O
Covid, O
the O
real O
scope O
of O
the O
monkeypox O
outbreak O
is O
probably O
underappreciated. O

Confirmed O
or O
probable O
cases O
stand O
around O
5,000 O
, O
according O
to O
CDC B-ORG
data O
, O
but O
the O
number O
could O
be O
several O
fold O
higher O
. O

Another O
tool O
that O
could O
be O
tremendously O
helpful O
is O
testing O
of O
wastewater O

As O
we O
have O
seen O
with O
Covid O
, O
it O
can O
better O
define O
the O
scope O
of O
the O
outbreak O
and O
where O
it O
will O
emerge O
next O
. O

Two O
months O
into O
the O
outbreak O
, O
we O
still O
aren’t O
doing O
this O
widely O
for O
monkeypox O
. O

And O
then O
there O
are O
vaccines O

Unlike O
Covid O
, O
where O
we O
spent O
upward O
of O
$20 O
billion O
to O
develop O
, O
test O
and O
distribute O
vaccines O
, O
we O
already O
have O
a O
vaccine O
specifically O
approved O
for O
monkeypox O
. O

Supplies O
were O
limited O
and O
the O
initial O
US B-LOC
vaccination O
strategy O
focused O
on O
known O
monkeypox O
cases O
and O
their O
immediate O
contacts O

But O
the O
outbreak O
continued O
to O
grow O
, O
and O
the O
strategy O
had O
to O
change O
. O

The O
count O
of O
people O
eligible O
for O
the O
two-dose O
Jynneos O
vaccine O
has O
now O
expanded O
to O
an O
estimated O
1.5 O
million O

With O
that O
same O
cavalry O
culture O
, O
we O
are O
woefully O
behind O
in O
getting O
those O
doses O
to O
people O
who O
want O
them O
. O

At O
this O
time O
, O
only O
336,710 O
doses O
have O
been O
shipped O
to O
states O
. O

Ordering O
only O
just O
began O
for O
about O
800,000 O
more O
doses O
. O

This O
scarcity O
has O
created O
long O
lines O
in O
monkeypox O
hotspots O
like O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
City I-LOC
, O
which O
has O
the O
highest O
number O
of O
cases O
in O
the O
country O
. O

It O
also O
means O
that O
the O
vaccine O
, O
which O
can O
be O
given O
within O
14 O
days O
of O
exposure O
( O
but O
preferably O
within O
four O
) O
to O
prevent O
or O
reduce O
the O
severity O
of O
disease O
, O
is O
currently O
being O
used O
more O
as O
a O
treatment O
– O
a O
post-exposure O
prophylaxis O
– O
rather O
than O
as O
a O
real O
preventive O
measure O
. O

It’s O
very O
clear O
with O
the O
spread O
of O
this O
that O
there O
now O
has O
to O
be O
a O
balance O
between O
vaccines O
available O
for O
those O
who O
clearly O
have O
been O
exposed O
, O
as O
well O
as O
those O
at O
risk O
, O
Fauci B-PER
said O
. O

What O
you O
want O
to O
do O
is O
a O
balance O
between O
vaccinating O
those O
who O
clearly O
have O
had O
an O
exposure O
but O
go O
well O
beyond O
that O

It’s O
a O
missed O
opportunity O
that O
won’t O
be O
rectified O
immediately O
, O
even O
with O
the O
soon-to-arrive O
786,000 O
doses O
announced O
by O
HHS B-ORG
this O
week O
. O

Needs O
will O
still O
outstrip O
supply O

Finally O
, O
there O
is O
the O
issue O
of O
treatment O
. O

The O
CDC B-ORG
has O
made O
the O
antiviral O
smallpox O
treatment O
tecovirimat O
, O
called O
TPOXX O
, O
available O
to O
monkeypox O
patients O
who O
have O
or O
are O
at O
high O
risk O
of O
severe O
disease O
under O
an O
“alternate O
regulatory O
mechanism O
.” O

There O
are O
1.7 O
million O
courses O
of O
TPOXX O
stockpiled O

But O
once O
again O
, O
getting O
the O
medication O
to O
patients O
who O
could O
immediately O
benefit O
has O
proven O
to O
be O
bureaucratically O
burdensome O
for O
both O
patients O
and O
providers O
. O

You’re O
talking O
about O
a O
five O
six-day O
time O
lag O
to O
get O
that O
medication O
to O
you O
at O
a O
local O
doctor’s O
office O
, O
no O
matter O
where O
you O
are O
. O

And O
the O
paperwork O
, O
and O
all O
of O
the O
bureaucracy O
to O
make O
that O
happen O
is O
very O
cumbersome O
, O
takes O
a O
few O
hours O
of O
your O
time O
. O

And O
that’s O
the O
barrier,” O
Dr. O
Stacy B-PER
Lane, I-PER
founder O
of O
the O
LGBTQ-centered O
Central B-ORG
Outreach I-ORG
Wellness I-ORG
Center I-ORG
in O
Pittsburgh, B-LOC
told O
me O
recently. O

Fortunately O
, O
those O
rules O
were O
loosened O
somewhat O
last O
week O
, O
allowing O
patients O
to O
get O
treated O
more O
quickly O
and O
reducing O
the O
amount O
of O
documentation O
needed O
. O

The O
CDC B-ORG
and O
the O
US B-ORG
Food I-ORG
and I-ORG
Drug I-ORG
Administration I-ORG
are O
working O
to O
further O
streamline O
the O
process O

In O
the O
meantime O
, O
though O
, O
patients O
are O
suffering O
. O

Even O
though O
most O
cases O
are O
“mild,” O
they O
are O
still O
uncomfortable, O
or O
downright O
painful, O
depending O
on O
where O
sores O
appear. O

Plus, O
there O
is O
a O
risk O
of O
long-term O
complications O
if O
the O
pox O
lesions O
develop O
in O
areas O
around O
the O
eye O
or O
GI O
tract. O

All O
of O
these O
gaps O
have O
the O
hardest O
hit O
community O
on O
edge O
. O

Largely O
public O
health O
officials O
know O
how O
this O
has O
spread O

They O
know O
how O
to O
vaccinate O
people O
… O
we O
know O
how O
to O
treat O
it O
, O
and O
we O
know O
how O
to O
prevent O
it O
, O
” O
says O
Samuel B-PER
Garrett-Pate I-PER
, O
managing O
director O
of O
external O
affairs O
of O
Equality B-ORG
California I-ORG
, O
the O
largest O
statewide O
LBGTQ+ O
civil O
rights O
organization O
. O
“ O

It O
unfortunately O
seems O
that O
despite O
two O
years O
of O
building O
up O
our O
public O
health O
infrastructure O
to O
prevent O
what O
happened O
with O
Covid-19 O
from O
ever O
happening O
again O
, O
despite O
the O
fact O
that O
we O
are O
better O
prepared O
in O
terms O
of O
already O
having O
a O
vaccine O
available O
, O
the O
CDC B-ORG
and O
FDA B-ORG
seem O
to O
be O
caught O
flat-footed O
once O
again O
. O

And O
I O
think O
as O
a O
result O
, O
you’re O
seeing O
very O
real O
and O
understandable O
fear O
anxiety O
among O
the O
LGBTQ O
community O
. O

Is O
it O
too O
late O
? O

Dr. O
Scott B-PER
Gottlieb I-PER
, O
a O
former O
FDA B-ORG
commissioner O
and O
current O
board O
member O
of O
Pfizer B-ORG
, O
has O
been O
pessimistic O
about O
the O
trajectory O
of O
monkeypox O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

We’re O
now O
at O
the O
cusp O
of O
this O
becoming O
an O
endemic O
virus O
, O
where O
this O
now O
becomes O
something O
that’s O
persistent O
that O
we O
need O
to O
continue O
to O
deal O
with O
. O

I O
think O
the O
window O
for O
getting O
control O
of O
this O
and O
containing O
it O
probably O
has O
closed O
and O
if O
it O
hasn’t O
closed O
, O
it’s O
certainly O
starting O
to O
close O
, O
he O
said O
on O
Face B-ORG
the I-ORG
Nation I-ORG
on O
July O
17 O
. O

CDC’s O
Walensky B-PER
pushed O
back O
on O
Gottlieb’s B-PER
assessment O
calling O
it O
“misinformed O
and O
off O
base,” O
saying O
that O
while O
it’s O
true O
there O
is O
much O
work O
to O
do, O
the O
US B-LOC
has O
made O
dramatic O
progress O
on O
priorities O
like O
testing, O
vaccines O
and O
education. O

There O
has O
been O
measurable O
progress O
in O
these O
areas O
, O
no O
doubt O
. O

But, O
I O
do O
worry O
that O
we O
once O
again O
waited O
too O
long. O

We O
sat O
idling O
in O
our O
Ferrari B-ORG
, O
perhaps O
not O
wanting O
to O
believe O
that O
somehow O
we O
had O
suddenly O
found O
ourselves O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
yet O
another O
outbreak O
. O

I O
remember O
when O
I O
first O
saw O
a O
case O
of O
monkeypox O
– O
it O
was O
in O
2008 O
, O
in O
the O
Democratic B-LOC
Republic I-LOC
of O
the O
Congo I-LOC
, O
one O
of O
the O
handful O
of O
countries O
in O
Africa B-LOC
where O
the O
disease O
is O
endemic O
. O

To O
tell O
you O
the O
truth O
, O
I O
never O
thought O
I O
would O
see O
it O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

After O
all O
, O
it O
was O
a O
virus O
that O
hadn’t O
traveled O
much O
since O
it O
was O
first O
identified O
in O
DRC B-LOC
in O
1970 O
. O

My O
guess O
was O
that O
most O
of O
my O
medical O
colleagues O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
would O
likely O
only O
see O
pictures O
of O
the O
distinctive O
pox O
lesions O
in O
textbooks O

The O
world O
, O
however O
, O
is O
changing O
, O
as O
we O
have O
been O
reminded O
of O
twice O
in O
the O
last O
few O
years O
. O

There O
are O
new O
pathogens O
emerging O
, O
and O
existing O
pathogens O
are O
more O
easily O
traveling O
the O
world O
. O

We O
have O
learned O
painful O
lessons O
in O
the O
last O
few O
years O
, O
and O
we O
are O
now O
in O
the O
midst O
of O
our O
first O
significant O
test O
since O
the O
Covid O
pandemic O
began O
, O
to O
see O
if O
we O
do O
any O
better O
this O
time O
around O
. O

There O
is O
no O
doubt O
we O
are O
capable O
, O
and O
we O
are O
prepared O
. O

The O
question O
is O
will O
we O
use O
all O
those O
remarkable O
resources O
and O
respond O
, O
or O
we O
will O
wait O
and O
suffer O
until O
the O
cavalry O
has O
to O
rescue O
us O
once O
again O
: O

CNN B-ORG
Health’s O
Andrea B-PER
Kane I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report. O

الشرطة O
الأمريكية O
تعلن O
اعتقال O
المشتبه O
به O
الرئيسي O
في O
جرائم O
قتل O
4 O
مسلمين O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

At O
the O
Conservative B-ORG
Political I-ORG
Action I-ORG
Conference I-ORG
Texas B-LOC
on O
Saturday O
, O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
overwhelmingly O
won O
an O
unofficial O
straw O
poll O
of O
attendees O
who O
were O
asked O
who O
they O
preferred O
as O
the O
Republican O
nominee O
for O
president O
in O
2024 O
. O

He’s O
more O
popular O
than O
ever,” O
said O
Jim B-PER
McLaughlin, I-PER
a O
pollster O
for O
Trump B-PER
who O
conducted O
the O
straw O
poll. O

McLaughlin B-PER
announced O
the O
results O
from O
the O
CPAC B-ORG
Texas B-LOC
main O
stage O
about O
two O
hours O
before O
Trump’s B-PER
scheduled O
appearance O

Among O
the O
attendees O
who O
voted O
, O
69% O
said O
they O
preferred O
Trump B-PER
, O
with O
24% O
saying O
they O
would O
prefer O
Florida B-LOC
Republican O
Gov. O
Ron B-PER
DeSantis I-PER
. O

When O
asked O
about O
who O
they O
would O
prefer O
if O
Trump B-PER
did O
not O
run O
for O
president O
, O
65% O
of O
respondents O
said O
they O
preferred O
DeSantis B-PER
, O
while O
8% O
said O
they O
would O
support O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
Jr. I-PER
. O
The O
straw O
poll O
is O
not O
a O
scientific O
survey O
, O
with O
a O
pool O
limited O
to O
CPAC B-ORG
attendees O
, O
and O
is O
not O
representative O
of O
the O
broader O
GOP B-ORG
electorate O
. O

The O
results O
are O
reflective O
of O
straw O
polls O
at O
previous O
CPACs O
since O
Trump B-PER
left O
office O
, O
which O
showed O
the O
former O
President O
with O
a O
large O
lead O
among O
the O
conservative O
activists O
and O
DeSantis B-PER
as O
the O
favorite O
alternative O
. O

In O
February O
, O
Trump B-PER
won O
a O
straw O
poll O
at O
CPAC B-ORG
in O
Orlando B-LOC
, O
Florida B-LOC
, O
with O
59% O
of O
the O
vote O
. O

DeSantis O
came O
in O
second O
in O
that O
poll O
with O
28% O
of O
the O
vote O
, O
and O
former O
Secretary O
of O
State O
Mike B-PER
Pompeo I-PER
came O
in O
a O
distant O
third O
with O
2% O
of O
the O
vote O
. O

In O
a O
July O
2021 O
CPAC B-ORG
straw O
poll O
, O
Trump B-PER
topped O
the O
GOP B-ORG
field O
with O
support O
from O
70% O
of O
conference O
attendees O
, O
compared O
to O
21% O
who O
selected O
DeSantis B-PER
last O
year O
. O

In O
an O
interview O
with O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
Magazine B-ORG
last O
month O
, O
Trump B-PER
said O
he O
was O
still O
deciding O
when O
– O
not O
if O
– O
he O
should O
announce O
a O
2024 O
campaign O
. O

DeSantis O
is O
also O
widely O
considered O
to O
be O
a O
contender O
for O
the O
2024 O
GOP O
presidential O
nomination O

CNN’s B-ORG
Sara B-PER
Murray I-PER
and O
Steve B-PER
Contorno I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report. O

More O
than O
a O
dozen O
major O
news O
organizations O
have O
filed O
a O
lawsuit O
against O
the O
Texas B-LOC
Department I-ORG
of I-ORG
Public I-ORG
Safety I-ORG
to O
obtain O
public O
records O
relating O
to O
the O
Robb B-LOC
Elementary I-LOC
School I-LOC
massacre O

The O
coalition O
includes O
CNN B-ORG
, O
the O
Texas B-LOC
Tribune I-ORG
, O
and O
many O
of O
the O
state O
and O
the O
country’s O
biggest O
news O
outlets O
. O

The O
news O
organizations O
have O
been O
fighting O
for O
weeks O
to O
obtain O
information O
on O
behalf O
of O
the O
public O
amid O
serial O
falsehoods O
and O
stonewalling O
from O
Texas B-LOC
officials O
in O
the O
aftermath O
of O
the O
mass O
shooting O

The O
lawsuit O
, O
filed O
in O
state O
court O
in O
Austin B-LOC
, O
arises O
under O
the O
Texas B-LOC
Public O
Information O
Act O
, O
which O
enables O
news O
outlets O
and O
members O
of O
the O
public O
to O
pursue O
litigation O
to O
obtain O
records O
. O

The O
news O
outlets O
cited O
many O
previous O
requests O
for O
information O
and O
an O
“ensuing O
failure O
to O
disclose O
public O
records O
concerning O
this O
abhorrent O
tragedy O
.” O

The O
Texas B-LOC
Department O
of O
Public O
Safety I-ORG
has O
offered O
inconsistent O
accounts O
of O
how O
law O
enforcement O
responded O
to O
the O
Uvalde B-LOC
tragedy O
, O
and O
its O
lack O
of O
transparency O
has O
stirred O
suspicion O
and O
frustration O
in O
a O
community O
that O
is O
still O
struggling O
with O
grief O
and O
shock O
, O
said O
Laura B-PER
Lee I-PER
Prather I-PER
, O
a O
First O
Amendment O
lawyer O
at O
Haynes B-ORG
Boone I-ORG
who O
represents O
the O
plaintiffs O
. O

DPS B-ORG
has O
refused O
numerous O
requests O
by O
these O
news O
organizations O
even O
though O
it’s O
clear O
under O
Texas B-LOC
law O
that O
the O
public O
is O
entitled O
to O
have O
access O
to O
these O
important O
public O
records O

We O
ask O
that O
the O
court O
grant O
our O
petition O
so O
that O
the O
people O
of O
Texas B-LOC
can O
understand O
the O
truth O
about O
what O
happened O
. O

The O
suit O
notes O
that O
the O
public O
safety O
department O
has O
“selectively O
disclosed” O
information, O
but O
has O
dismissed O
more O
thorough O
records O
requests. O

Thus O
the O
news O
outlets O
want O
the O
court O
to O
order O
the O
department O
“to O
produce O
all O
responsive O
records O
.” O

The O
other O
participating O
news O
organizations O
are O
ABC B-ORG
, O
CBS B-ORG
, O
NBC B-ORG
, O
The O
New B-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
, O
Wall B-ORG
Street I-ORG
Journal I-ORG
owner O
Dow B-ORG
Jones I-ORG
, O
The O
Washington B-ORG
Post I-ORG
, O
and O
ProPublica B-ORG
; O
local O
TV O
and O
media O
companies O
Gannett B-ORG
, O
Graham B-ORG
Media I-ORG
, O
Scripps B-ORG
and O
TEGNA B-ORG
Nicole B-PER
Carroll I-PER
, O
the O
editor O
in O
chief O
of O
Gannett’s B-ORG
USA B-ORG
Today I-ORG
, O
said O
on O
CNN’s B-ORG
“Reliable O
Sources” O
last O
month O
that O
the O
coalition O
is O
necessary O
because O
“we O
need O
to O
get O
to O
the O
truth O
. O

And O
we’re O
fighting O
for O
these O
records O
so O
we O
can O
get O
the O
truth O
. O

Officials O
have O
“ O
been O
stonewalling O
us O
” O
and O
changing O
their O
stories O
, O
she O
pointed O
out O
. O
“ O

We’ve O
been O
misled, O
documents O
have O
been O
withheld. O

The O
rounds O
bounced O
off O
the O
armored O
vehicle O
, O
as O
police O
carried O
a O
limp O
civilian O
to O
the O
sidewalk O
– O
another O
victim O
of O
the O
brutal O
, O
daily O
shootings O
that O
plague O
the O
Haitian B-LOC
capital O
Port-au-Prince B-LOC
and O
the O
surrounding O
area O
. O

Here O
, O
inside O
the O
gang-held O
territory O
of O
Croix-des-Bouquets B-LOC
, O
Haiti’s B-LOC
SWAT O
team O
has O
driven O
into O
a O
gunfight O
that O
has O
already O
torn O
up O
a O
civilian O
bus O
. O

Can O
you O
see O
where O
it O
came O
from O
? O

the O
SWAT O
members O
breathlessly O
asked O
each O
other O
inside O
the O
armored O
vehicle O

It O
provides O
only O
a O
tiny O
sliver O
of O
a O
window O
onto O
the O
streets O
outside O
, O
which O
at O
one O
moment O
appear O
deserted O
, O
the O
next O
teeming O
with O
civilians O
trying O
to O
flee O
to O
safety O
. O

In O
the O
past O
72 O
hours O
, O
police O
have O
killed O
a O
leader O
of O
the O
400 O
Mawozo O
gang O
and O
rescued O
six O
hostages O
from O
them O
, O
they O
say O
. O

But O
the O
gang O
- O
one O
of O
dozens O
terrorizing O
the O
capital O
- O
have O
not O
been O
dislodged O
from O
these O
streets O

Can O
you O
see O
that O
red O
sign O
‘SMS’ O
? O

That’s O
them,” O
said O
a O
SWAT B-ORG
officer, O
indicating O
the O
gunmen’s O
position. O

Like O
his O
team O
, O
he O
did O
not O
want O
to O
be O
named O
, O
citing O
their O
safety O
. O

He O
pointed O
down O
the O
road O
towards O
a O
small O
shack O
, O
as O
dozens O
of O
people O
flooded O
from O
a O
side-alley O
into O
the O
street O
. O

Get O
away O
he O
said O
to O
the O
crowd O
, O
over O
the O
armored O
car’s O
loudspeaker O
. O

You’re O
too O
exposed O

It’s O
dangerous O

The O
officer O
ordered O
the O
vehicle O
to O
move O
into O
a O
new O
position O
. O

When O
we O
get O
to O
the O
spot O
, O
open O
up O
on O
anything O
that O
moves O
, O
he O
said O
. O

Heavy O
gunfire O
between O
police O
and O
gang O
members O
followed O

It O
is O
a O
common O
scene O
of O
injury O
, O
gunfire O
and O
panic O
in O
one O
of O
the O
dozens O
of O
neighborhoods O
controlled O
by O
gangs O
as O
Port-au-Prince B-LOC
appears O
to O
descend O
into O
a O
full-blown O
war O
between O
police O
and O
increasingly O
well-equipped O
and O
organized O
criminal O
groups O
. O

And O
this O
is O
a O
familiar O
routine O
: O
Police B-ORG
probe O
into O
gang O
areas O
to O
show O
their O
reach O
, O
and O
gangs O
respond O
with O
intense O
volleys O
of O
bullets O
. O

In O
the O
area O
of O
Cité B-LOC
Soleil I-LOC
, O
ten O
days O
of O
violence O
in O
July O
left O
more O
than O
470 O
people O
dead O
, O
injured O
or O
missing O
, O
according O
to O
the O
UN B-ORG
, O
after O
the O
G9 O
gang O
tried O
to O
expand O
its O
reach O
in O
the O
area O
, O
taking O
territory O
from O
rival O
gangs O
. O

Social O
media O
video O
from O
inside O
the O
area O
shows O
gangs O
using O
a O
bulldozer O
covered O
with O
steel O
plates O
to O
act O
as O
armor O
demolishing O
homes O
, O
presumably O
those O
of O
rivals O
. O

Other O
houses O
had O
been O
burned O
, O
with O
other O
video O
showing O
dozens O
of O
locals O
fleeing O
the O
area O
on O
foot O
at O
night O
, O
during O
the O
peak O
of O
the O
fighting O
. O

Civilians O
who O
fled O
Cité B-LOC
Soleil I-LOC
found O
little O
respite O
, O
with O
dozens O
receiving O
food O
handouts O
from O
the O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Programme I-ORG
and O
sheltering O
in O
the O
open O
air O
of O
the O
Hugo B-PER
Chavez I-PER
recreational O
park O
. O

Flies O
blanket O
the O
rain-sodden O
concrete O
floor O
of O
the O
sporting O
amphitheater O
stage O
, O
where O
children O
as O
young O
as O
four O
months O
struggle O
to O
sleep O
, O
exposed O
to O
the O
elements O
. O

One O
has O
bruises O
from O
a O
fall O
, O
another O
a O
painful O
and O
ugly O
rash O
, O
but O
they O
are O
alive O
. O

Here, O
Natalie B-PER
Aristel I-PER
angrily O
shows O
us O
her O
new, O
unpalatable O
home. O

Here’s O
where O
I O
sleep O
in O
a O
puddle O
,” O
she O
said O
, O
pointing O
at O
the O
water O
. O

They O
burned O
my O
house O
and O
shot O
my O
husband O
seven O
times,” O
she O
says, O
referring O
to O
gang O
members. O

I O
can’t O
even O
afford O
to O
go O
see O
him O
[ O
in O
hospital O
] O

In O
this O
park O
, O
even O
if O
they O
brought O
some O
food O
, O
there’s O
never O
enough O
for O
everyone O
. O

The O
kids O
are O
dying O
. O

Others O
are O
missing O
. O

I O
have O
four O
kids O
, O
but O
my O
first O
is O
missing O
and O
I O
can’t O
find O
him O
, O
another O
woman O
said O
. O

We’ve O
been O
totally O
abandoned O
by O
the O
state O
and O
have O
to O
pay O
to O
even O
use O
a O
toilet,” O
another O
added. O

A O
young O
boy O
added O
: O
“ O
My O
mother O
and O
father O
have O
died O
. O
” O

My O
aunt O
saved O
me O

I O
want O
to O
go O
to O
school O
but O
it O
was O
torn O
down O
. O

Locals O
speak O
of O
a O
perfect O
storm O
of O
calamities O
– O
and O
warn O
the O
country O
increasingly O
feels O
on O
the O
verge O
of O
societal O
collapse O

What O
remains O
of O
the O
country’s O
emergency O
interim O
government O
, O
created O
last O
year O
after O
the O
assassination O
of O
President O
Jovenel B-PER
Moïse I-PER
, O
is O
beginning O
to O
crumble O
and O
steeped O
in O
accusations O
of O
inactivity O
. O

His O
successor O
, O
Prime O
Minister O
Ariel B-PER
Henry I-PER
, O
has O
pledged O
to O
combat O
insecurity O
and O
hold O
new O
elections O
, O
but O
so O
far O
shown O
little O
progress O
toward O
either O
goal O
. O

Meanwhile O
, O
analysts O
calculate O
inflation O
in O
the O
country O
at O
30 O
. O

Gas O
is O
scarce O
and O
the O
subject O
of O
angry O
queues O
at O
stations O
. O

The O
UN B-ORG
has O
warned O
gang O
violence O
may O
put O
the O
youngest O
children O
in O
areas O
of O
active O
fighting O
at O
risk O
of O
imminent O
starvation O
, O
as O
their O
parents O
cannot O
access O
food O
or O
go O
to O
work O
. O

One O
Haitian B-LOC
security O
forces O
source O
speaking O
to O
CNN B-ORG
estimated O
that O
gangs O
control O
or O
influence O
three O
quarters O
of O
the O
city O

Frantz B-PER
Elbe, I-PER
Director O
General O
of O
the O
Haitian O
National O
Police, O
rejects O
the O
assertion. O

It O
is O
not O
a O
general O
problem O
in O
the O
metropolitan O
area O
,” O
he O
told O
CNN B-ORG
, O
declining O
to O
give O
a O
percentage O
. O

Yet O
it O
is O
indisputable O
that O
vital O
parts O
of O
the O
national O
infrastructure O
are O
now O
entirely O
in O
criminal O
hands O

The O
city’s O
vital O
port O
– O
Haiti’s B-LOC
main O
– O
is O
controlled O
by O
gangs O
, O
who O
dominate O
the O
road O
outside O
. O

So O
is O
the O
main O
highway O
to O
the O
country’s O
south O
, O
which O
means O
the O
fragile O
part O
of O
the O
country O
that O
was O
hit O
by O
an O
earthquake O
last O
year O
has O
been O
effectively O
cut O
off O
from O
the O
capital O
. O

Gangs O
are O
also O
expanding O
their O
control O
in O
the O
city’s O
east O
, O
where O
Croix-des-Bouquets B-LOC
lies O
, O
and O
in O
the O
north O
, O
around O
Cité B-LOC
Soleil I-LOC
, O
observers O
said O
. O

Kidnappings O
are O
rampant O
and O
indiscriminate O
– O
one O
of O
few O
thriving O
industries O
in O
Haiti B-LOC

Seventeen O
American B-LOC
and O
Canadian B-LOC
missionaries O
were O
kidnapped O
last O
year O
after O
visiting O
an O
orphanage O
in O
Croix-des-Bouquets B-LOC
, O
and O
only O
released O
after O
a O
ransom O
was O
paid O
to O
the O
400 O
Mawozo O
gang O
. O

Police O
, O
often O
outgunned O
, O
are O
doing O
what O
they O
can O
, O
Elbe B-PER
tells O
CNN B-ORG
. O

The O
gangs O
are O
changing O
the O
way O
they O
fight O

It O
used O
to O
be O
with O
knives O
, O
and O
now O
it O
is O
with O
big O
weapons O
. O

The O
police O
need O
to O
be O
well-equipped O
. O

With O
the O
little O
we O
have O
, O
we O
will O
do O
what O
we O
can O
to O
fight O
the O
gang O
members O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

The O
challenge O
they O
face O
is O
exposed O
by O
a O
brief O
checkpoint O
set O
up O
in O
Croix-des-Bouquets B-LOC
, O
where O
a O
truck O
has O
been O
dragged O
across O
a O
main O
road O
by O
the O
gangs O
, O
and O
torched O

Police O
bring O
in O
an O
armored O
military O
bulldozer O
to O
push O
the O
wreckage O
to O
the O
roadside O
, O
which O
is O
already O
littered O
with O
other O
truck O
carcasses O
. O

The O
bulldozer O
operator O
, O
asked O
if O
he O
works O
under O
fire O
, O
replies O
: O
“ O
Often O
.” O

SWAT O
police O
set O
up O
a O
perimeter O
, O
scanning O
nearby O
rooftops O
. O

Locals O
and O
the O
vehicles O
they O
travel O
in O
are O
stopped O
and O
checked O

One O
man O
says O
the O
situation O
is O
“bad, O
very O
bad,” O
before O
another O
gives O
him O
a O
stern O
glance. O

He O
suddenly O
changes O
tone O
: O
“ O
We O
know O
nothing O
.” O

Fear O
is O
the O
currency O
of O
this O
war O
, O
though O
it O
is O
unclear O
if O
he O
fears O
speaking O
to O
the O
press O
, O
or O
the O
police O
, O
or O
what O
the O
gang O
may O
learn O
he O
said O
later O
. O

To O
flee O
this O
fear O
, O
however O
, O
requires O
enduring O
more O
. O

A O
short O
boat O
journey O
from O
the O
mainland O
is O
the O
island O
of O
La B-LOC
Gonave I-LOC
, O
a O
hub O
for O
human O
traffickers O
. O

The O
lackadaisical O
tempo O
and O
blue O
water O
of O
one O
tiny O
inlet O
on O
La B-LOC
Gonave I-LOC
belies O
its O
poverty O

Heat O
trash O
hunger O
and O
the O
business O
of O
leaving O
dominate O
this O
world O

One O
, O
a O
smuggler O
who O
introduced O
himself O
as O
Johnny B-PER
, O
calmly O
explained O
how O
his O
business O
works O
. O

The O
journey O
is O
often O
one-way O
for O
the O
boat O
, O
so O
each O
endeavor O
requires O
the O
boat O
to O
be O
bought O
outright O
, O
at O
a O
cost O
of O
about O
US O
$ O
10,000 O
, O
he O
says O
. O

To O
cover O
that O
cost O
, O
Johnny B-PER
needs O
at O
least O
two O
hundred O
customers O
, O
who O
will O
huddle O
in O
its O
disheveled O
hull O
. O

Shreds O
of O
netting O
appear O
to O
plug O
any O
gaps O
between O
in O
the O
hull O
, O
and O
loose O
wooden O
planks O
will O
make O
up O
the O
boat’s O
interior O
. O

Johnny B-PER
shows O
where O
the O
pump O
and O
motors O
will O
eventually O
go O

If O
we O
die O
, O
we O
die O
. O

If O
we O
make O
it O
, O
we O
make O
it O
,” O
he O
said O
. O

He O
added O
he O
hoped O
to O
pack O
his O
boat O
with O
250 O
passengers O
, O
as O
he O
considered O
it O
in O
“good” O
condition O
. O

The O
ultimate O
destination O
is O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
, O
with O
Cuba B-LOC
and O
the O
Turks B-LOC
and I-LOC
Caicos I-LOC
islands O
sometimes O
accidental O
stops O
along O
the O
way O
. O

And O
it O
is O
from O
these O
three O
places O
that O
the O
International B-ORG
Organization I-ORG
for I-ORG
Migration I-ORG
has O
reported O
surging O
numbers O
of O
forced O
repatriations O
of O
Haitians O
in O
the O
first O
seven O
months O
of O
this O
year O
, O
with O
20,016 O
so O
far O
, O
compared O
to O
19,629 O
for O
all O
of O
2021 O
. O

Some O
Haitians B-LOC
appear O
to O
be O
getting O
closer O
to O
the O
journey’s O
end O
, O
with O
the O
US B-ORG
Coast I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
interdicting O
6,114 O
Haitians B-LOC
between O
October O
and O
late O
June O
– O
four O
times O
as O
many O
as O
between O
October O
2020 O
and O
October O
2021 O
. O

In O
the O
past O
weekend O
alone O
, O
more O
than O
330 O
migrants O
from O
Haiti B-LOC
were O
rescued O
by O
the O
US B-ORG
Coast I-ORG
Guard I-ORG
near O
the O
Florida B-LOC
Keys I-LOC
. O

The O
numbers O
are O
as O
staggering O
as O
the O
risks O
. O

Previous O
journeys O
from O
this O
inlet O
have O
ended O
in O
tragedy O

Johnny B-PER
is O
unclear O
on O
the O
timing O
of O
the O
last O
boat O
, O
but O
precise O
about O
the O
potential O
losses O
: O
One O
recent O
trip O
he O
organized O
led O
to O
the O
deaths O
of O
29 O
people O
. O

The O
boat O
had O
an O
engine O
problem O
,” O
he O
said O
. O

Water O
got O
inside O
the O
boat O

We O
called O
for O
help O
, O
but O
they O
took O
too O
long O
. O

The O
boat O
was O
sinking O
while O
I O
was O
trying O
to O
save O
people O

When O
help O
came O
, O
it O
was O
too O
late O
. O

While O
CNN B-ORG
cannot O
independently O
confirm O
Johnny’s B-PER
account O
of O
the O
system O
, O
two O
other O
locals O
who O
said O
they O
were O
involved O
in O
trafficking O
described O
similar O
details O
independently O
. O

Authorities O
in O
the O
neighboring O
Caribbean O
nations O
the O
Bahamas B-LOC
and O
Turks B-LOC
and I-LOC
Caicos I-LOC
have O
repeatedly O
reported O
finding O
the O
remains O
of O
would-be O
migrants O
after O
boats O
capsized O
in O
their O
waters O

Despite O
the O
risks O
, O
many O
Haitians B-PER
are O
still O
desperate O
for O
a O
way O
out O
. O

Locals O
on O
La B-LOC
Gonave I-LOC
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
at O
least O
40 O
people O
who O
aimed O
to O
attempt O
the O
boat O
trip O
were O
already O
on O
the O
island O
and O
the O
rest O
would O
follow O
from O
the O
mainland O
once O
Johnny B-PER
said O
the O
boat O
was O
ready O

One O
potential O
passenger O
, O
a O
university O
graduate O
who O
was O
once O
a O
teacher O
, O
described O
why O
he O
would O
risk O
all O
to O
take O
the O
voyage O
. O

I O
worked O
as O
a O
teacher O
, O
but O
it O
did O
not O
work O
out O
. O

Now, O
I O
am O
driving O
a O
motorcycle O
every O
day O
in O
the O
sun O
and O
the O
dust. O

How O
will O
I O
be O
able O
to O
take O
care O
of O
my O
family O
when O
I O
have O
one O
? O

He O
said O
he O
saved O
a O
year’s O
money O
to O
make O
the O
journey O
, O
and O
did O
not O
fear O
the O
rickety O
conditions O
of O
the O
boat O
. O

I O
can O
be O
eaten O
by O
a O
shark O
or O
make O
it O
to O
America B-LOC
. O

Wisconsin B-LOC
Republican O
Sen. O
Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
and O
Democratic O
Lt. O

Gov. O
Mandela B-PER
Barnes I-PER
are O
political O
opposites. O

But O
as O
the O
two O
prepare O
for O
what O
could O
become O
one O
of O
the O
most O
closely O
watched O
Senate B-ORG
races O
of O
the O
2022 O
cycle O
, O
they O
are O
leveling O
similar O
attacks O
to O
define O
each O
other O
: O
Casting O
their O
opponent O
as O
too O
extreme O
and O
out O
of O
touch O
with O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters O
, O
while O
arguing O
the O
other O
is O
not O
a O
true O
representative O
of O
the O
state’s O
working O
class O
. O

The O
problem O
is O
Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
has O
turned O
his O
back O
on O
working O
people O
and O
I’ve O
fought O
for O
working O
people O
my O
entire O
career O
, O
even O
before O
I O
was O
an O
office O
, O
” O
Barnes B-PER
said O
when O
asked O
for O
the O
single O
biggest O
difference O
between O
himself O
and O
Johnson B-PER
, O
who O
made O
millions O
running O
a O
plastics O
manufacturer O
before O
he O
entered O
public O
office O
. O

His O
wealth O
isn’t O
the O
problem O
– O
it’s O
the O
fact O
that O
he O
is O
ultra-wealthy O
and O
out O
of O
touch O
. O

Johnson’s O
campaign O
declined O
to O
make O
him O
available O
to O
CNN B-ORG
, O
but O
a O
Johnson B-PER
campaign O
adviser O
previewed O
a O
notably O
similar O
message O
. O

(Barnes) O
is O
out O
of O
touch O
with O
where O
the O
majority O
of O
the O
state O
is O
,” O
said O
adviser O
Ben B-PER
Voelkel I-PER
, O
citing O
some O
of O
the O
more O
liberal O
positions O
Barnes O
has O
backed O
throughout O
his O
career O
. O

Mandela B-PER
Barnes I-PER
talks O
a O
lot O
about O
his O
dad O
working O
the O
third O
shift O
work O
. O

Mandela B-PER
Barnes I-PER
hasn’t O
done O
any O
of O
that O

He O
has O
been O
a O
career O
political O
activist O
. O

Johnson O
has O
already O
described O
Barnes B-PER
as O
Democrats’ O
“most O
radical O
left O
candidate,” O
adding O
that O
“a O
radical O
left O
Senator O
from O
Wisconsin B-LOC
is O
not O
the O
solution.” O

Johnson B-PER
recently O
called O
him O
“a O
progressive O
puppet O
out O
to O
fundamentally O
change O
America B-LOC
.” O

The O
attacks O
– O
delivered O
ahead O
of O
Tuesday’s O
Wisconsin B-LOC
Senate O
primaries O
, O
which O
appear O
to O
be O
already O
decided O
– O
are O
previews O
of O
what O
will O
likely O
become O
an O
acrimonious O
race O
, O
one O
that O
experts O
expect O
will O
see O
tens O
of O
millions O
spent O
on O
negative O
advertising O
as O
each O
side O
attempts O
to O
solidify O
their O
base O
voters O
in O
November O
. O

Johnson O
, O
the O
incumbent O
, O
faces O
no O
primary O
challenge O
after O
he O
opted O
to O
run O
for O
a O
third O
term O
. O

The O
senator O
, O
who O
promised O
to O
only O
serve O
another O
full O
term O
when O
he O
ran O
for O
reelection O
in O
2016 O
, O
waffled O
on O
the O
third O
term O
for O
months O
, O
but O
eventually O
decided O
to O
get O
into O
the O
race O
because O
“ O
America B-LOC
is O
in O
peril O
” O
and O
he O
wants O
to O
end O
Democratic B-ORG
control O
of O
Washington B-LOC
. O

Barnes O
initially O
had O
significant O
primary O
challengers O
, O
including O
Milwaukee B-LOC
Bucks I-ORG
executive O
Alex B-PER
Lasry I-PER
, O
who O
spent O
more O
than O
$11 O
million O
of O
his O
own O
money O
airing O
ads O
throughout O
the O
state O
. O

But O
over O
the O
span O
of O
a O
week O
last O
month O
, O
Barnes’ B-PER
three O
top O
primary O
opponents O
– O
Lasry B-PER
, O
Wisconsin B-LOC
state O
Treasurer O
Sarah B-PER
Godlewski I-PER
and O
Outagamie B-LOC
County I-LOC
Executive O
Tom B-PER
Nelson I-PER
– O
all O
dropped O
out O
of O
the O
race O
and O
endorsed O
the O
lieutenant O
governor O
, O
effectively O
ending O
the O
primary O
. O

I O
could O
not O
have O
imagined O
it O
ending O
up O
this O
way O
,” O
Barnes B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
“ O

To O
me O
, O
it O
shows O
just O
how O
important O
beating O
Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
is O
, O
just O
how O
important O
expanding O
the O
democratic O
majority O
is O
. O

As O
the O
two O
candidates O
turn O
their O
focus O
on O
each O
other O
, O
Wisconsin B-LOC
represents O
yet O
another O
example O
of O
a O
high O
stakes O
Senate O
race O
where O
the O
contrast O
between O
candidates O
is O
significant O
, O
including O
Republican O
Herschel B-PER
Walker I-PER
vs. O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Raphael B-PER
Warnock I-PER
in O
Georgia B-LOC
, O
Republican O
Mehmet B-PER
Oz I-PER
against O
Lt. O

Gov. O
John B-PER
Fetterman I-PER
in O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
and O
Republican O
Blake B-PER
Masters I-PER
vs. O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Mark B-PER
Kelly I-PER
in O
Arizona B-LOC

‘ O
The O
most O
vulnerable O
Republican O
incumbent O
’ O
The O
Barnes B-PER
strategy O
is O
to O
define O
Johnson B-PER
as O
a O
changed O
man O
, O
someone O
who O
went O
to O
Washington B-LOC
as O
an O
insurgent O
candidate O
but O
then O
enmeshed O
himself O
into O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
led O
by O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
. O

The O
attacks O
will O
include O
Johnson’s B-PER
own O
admission O
that O
the O
2017 O
tax O
bill O
passed O
by O
Republicans B-ORG
in O
Washington B-LOC
benefited O
his O
own O
company O
; O
his O
reported O
role O
in O
attempting O
to O
push O
a O
slate O
of O
fake O
electors O
after O
the O
2020 O
election O
; O
and O
his O
more O
recent O
suggestion O
that O
Social B-ORG
Security I-ORG
and O
Medicare B-ORG
, O
two O
popular O
social O
spending O
programs O
, O
be O
changed O
from O
mandatory O
to O
discretionary O
spending O
, O
something O
experts O
argue O
could O
effectively O
end O
the O
programs O
. O

What O
we O
ought O
to O
be O
doing O
is O
we O
ought O
to O
turn O
everything O
into O
discretionary O
spending O
so O
that O
it’s O
all O
evaluated O
so O
that O
we O
can O
fix O
problems O
or O
fix O
programs O
that O
are O
broken O
that O
are O
going O
to O
be O
going O
bankrupt O
, O
Johnson B-PER
said O
earlier O
this O
month O
. O

Barnes B-PER
wasted O
no O
time O
jumping O
on O
the O
comment O
, O
using O
it O
to O
argue O
that O
Johnson’s B-PER
personal O
wealth O
makes O
it O
impossible O
for O
him O
to O
understand O
what O
these O
programs O
mean O
to O
working O
class O
people O
. O

If O
he O
wants O
be O
anti-Social O
Security O
, O
that’s O
on O
him O
, O
Barnes B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
, O
using O
the O
Johnson B-PER
comment O
to O
inoculate O
himself O
from O
Republican O
charges O
of O
being O
too O
extreme O
. O

That’s O
much O
more O
extreme O
than O
wanting O
working O
families O
and O
people O
all O
across O
Wisconsin B-LOC
have O
a O
fair O
shot O
. O

With O
the O
primary O
all O
but O
decided O
, O
Barnes B-PER
put O
out O
an O
attack O
ad O
earlier O
this O
month O
that O
hit O
Johnson B-PER
on O
outsourcing O
jobs O
, O
using O
the O
senator’s O
defense O
of O
a O
company O
that O
took O
jobs O
out O
of O
Wisconsin B-LOC
. O

Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
couldn’t O
be O
more O
out O
of O
touch O
with O
Wisconsin B-LOC
,” O
the O
ad O
says O
. O

Democrats O
are O
also O
preparing O
to O
paint O
Johnson B-PER
as O
a O
candidate O
who O
has O
become O
a O
conspiracy O
theory O
promoter O
, O
including O
questioning O
the O
push O
to O
vaccinate O
people O
against O
the O
coronavirus O
, O
calling O
climate O
change O
“bullsh*t,” O
and O
suggesting O
– O
without O
any O
evidence O
– O
that O
the O
FBI B-ORG
had O
more O
inside O
knowledge O
than O
it O
let O
on O
about O
the O
US O
Capitol B-LOC
insurrection O
on O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
. O

Republican O
operatives O
working O
on O
Senate B-ORG
campaigns O
acknowledged O
the O
impact O
some O
of O
Johnson’s B-PER
comments O
have O
had O
on O
his O
image O

A O
recent O
Marquette B-ORG
Law I-ORG
School I-ORG
poll O
found O
that O
46% O
of O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters O
viewed O
him O
unfavorably O
, O
compared O
to O
37% O
who O
had O
a O
favorable O
view O
. O

But O
one O
operative O
argued O
that O
some O
positive O
Johnson B-PER
messaging O
over O
the O
summer O
, O
including O
significant O
spending O
by O
an O
outside O
group O
focused O
on O
inflation O
and O
a O
Johnson B-PER
campaign O
ad O
focus O
on O
legislation O
that O
allowed O
for O
more O
experimental O
drug O
treatments O
, O
have O
done O
some O
rehabilitation O
. O

His O
numbers O
are O
moving O
in O
the O
right O
direction,” O
the O
operative O
said, O
adding O
that, O
no O
matter O
what, O
“it O
is O
going O
to O
be O
a O
close O
race.” O

Democrats B-ORG
see O
negative O
views O
of O
Johnson B-PER
as O
central O
to O
their O
plan O
of O
turning O
the O
general O
election O
into O
a O
referendum O
of O
the O
senator O

Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
is O
without O
a O
doubt O
, O
the O
most O
vulnerable O
Republican O
incumbent O
on O
the O
map O
, O
said O
Amanda B-PER
Sherman I-PER
Baity I-PER
, O
spokeswoman O
for O
the O
Democratic B-ORG
Senatorial I-ORG
Campaign I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
. O

Defined O
by O
all O
these O
left-wing O
positions’ O
The O
attacks O
on O
Barnes B-PER
center O
on O
accusations O
that O
he O
is O
too O
extreme O
for O
the O
state O
, O
using O
his O
time O
as O
a O
community O
organizer O
, O
a O
state O
assemblyman O
from O
a O
solidly O
Democratic O
district O
and O
a O
“longtime O
leader” O
in O
the O
Working B-ORG
Families I-ORG
Party I-ORG
against O
him O
as O
he O
runs O
for O
Senate O
. O

The O
hits O
include O
his O
ties O
to O
members O
of O
the O
“Squad,” O
a O
group O
of O
liberal O
lawmakers O
in O
Congress B-ORG
who O
are O
often O
attacked O
by O
Republicans; B-ORG
a O
photo O
taken O
of O
him O
holding O
up O
an O
“Abolish O
ICE” O
T-shirt; O
and O
positions O
like O
ending O
cash O
bail, O
supporting O
the O
Green O
New O
Deal O
and O
a O
host O
of O
other O
views O
the O
Johnson B-PER
campaign O
believes O
are O
too O
“extreme” O
for O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters. O

Barnes B-PER
has O
said O
he O
does O
not O
support O
abolishing O
the O
U.S. O
Immigration B-ORG
and I-ORG
Customs I-ORG
Enforcement I-ORG
but O
supports O
“addressing O
the O
concerns O
and O
issues O
and O
challenges O
that O
people O
have O
so O
that O
we O
can O
have O
a O
fair, O
comprehensive O
immigration O
reform O
system.” O

All O
of O
these O
things O
are O
positions O
that O
might O
get O
you O
applause O
at O
a O
Working B-ORG
Families I-ORG
Party I-ORG
rally O
or O
get O
you O
the O
endorsement O
of O
AOC O
or O
Bernie B-PER
Sanders I-PER
or O
Elizabeth B-PER
Warren I-PER
, O
but O
when O
you O
look O
across O
the O
state O
, O
that O
is O
not O
where O
50+1 O
of O
the O
state O
sits O
, O
” O
Voelkel B-PER
said O
. O

One O
issue O
that O
Barnes’ B-PER
campaign O
must O
confront O
is O
the O
fact O
that O
polls O
show O
that O
many O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters O
don’t O
know O
enough O
about O
him O
to O
have O
an O
opinion O
– O
something O
that O
can O
be O
both O
helpful O
and O
hurtful O
. O

Barnes O
is O
not O
nearly O
as O
known O
in O
the O
state O
as O
Johnson O
,” O
said O
Charles B-PER
Franklin I-PER
, O
pollster O
for O
the O
Marquette B-ORG
Law I-ORG
School I-ORG
poll O
, O
citing O
a O
recent O
poll O
that O
found O
over O
50% O
of O
Democratic B-ORG
primary O
voters O
didn’t O
know O
enough O
about O
the O
lieutenant O
governor O
to O
form O
an O
opinion O
.” O

That O
is O
an O
opportunity O
for O
the O
Johnson B-ORG
side O
… O
to O
really O
try O
to O
step O
in O
and O
define O
Barnes O

And O
they O
plan O
to O
do O
just O
that O
, O
with O
the O
Johnson B-ORG
campaign I-ORG
and O
outside O
groups O
already O
gearing O
up O
to O
cast O
Barnes B-PER
as O
out O
of O
step O
with O
most O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters O
. O

He O
is O
going O
to O
be O
defined O
by O
all O
these O
left-wing O
positions O
that O
he O
took O
in O
the O
past O
, O
said O
Jack B-PER
Pandol I-PER
, O
spokesman O
for O
Senate B-ORG
Leadership I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
, O
a O
Republican O
super O
PAC O
focused O
on O
Senate O
races O
. O

There O
is O
a O
lot O
that O
voters O
are O
going O
to O
be O
made O
aware O
of O
in O
the O
coming O
months O
and O
that O
will O
be O
the O
first O
information O
that O
some O
voters O
are O
getting O
about O
Barnes B-PER

Barnes O
responded O
to O
these O
attacks O
by O
saying O
Republicans B-ORG
“ O
tried O
to O
say O
the O
same O
thing O
about O
Tammy B-PER
Baldwin I-PER
,” O
and O
she O
went O
on O
to O
win O
the O
state’s O
other O
Senate O
seat O
in O
2012 O
and O
reelection O
in O
2018 O
.” O

People O
like O
Ron B-PER
Johnson I-PER
are O
going O
to O
lie O
about O
whatever O
, O
anything O
he O
can O
think O
of O
, O
to O
take O
the O
heat O
off O
his O
own O
bad O
behavior O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
‘ O

We O
were O
polarized O
before O
it O
was O
cool’ O
The O
question O
among O
experts O
in O
Wisconsin B-LOC
is O
whether O
after O
years O
of O
polarization O
and O
remarkably O
tight O
elections O
, O
there O
are O
even O
enough O
persuadable O
voters O
in O
the O
state O
to O
make O
the O
general O
election O
anything O
more O
than O
a O
base-focused O
race O
. O

Wisconsin B-LOC
has O
been O
a O
swing O
state O
for O
years O
. O

When O
Trump B-PER
won O
it O
in O
2016 O
, O
he O
was O
the O
first O
Republican O
to O
win O
it O
since O
1984 O
. O

While O
Biden B-PER
won O
the O
state O
back O
in O
2020 O
, O
the O
state O
has O
long O
had O
years O
of O
Republican O
governors O
, O
including O
Scott B-PER
Walker I-PER
from O
2011 O
to O
2019 O
, O
and O
Republicans O
control O
both O
chambers O
of O
the O
state O
legislature O
. O

We O
were O
polarized O
before O
it O
was O
cool O
, O
said O
Joe B-PER
Zepecki I-PER
, O
a O
Democratic O
operative O
in O
Wisconsin B-LOC
, O
arguing O
that O
the O
fights O
around O
union O
rights O
in O
2011 O
and O
2012 O
led O
to O
the O
state O
being O
deeply O
polarized O
long O
before O
the O
arrival O
of O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
. O

So O
that O
shrinking O
segment O
of O
swing O
voters O
is O
kind O
of O
the O
ball O
game O

Yes O
, O
the O
political O
environment O
may O
be O
bad O
, O
but O
Republicans’ B-ORG
brand O
is O
rotten O
with O
those O
voters O
. O

This O
is O
why O
political O
watchers O
like O
Franklin B-PER
and O
others O
expect O
a O
deluge O
of O
negative O
ads O
in O
the O
contest O
, O
with O
both O
sides O
running O
campaigns O
that O
“ O
reflect O
that O
polarization O
that O
we O
have O
had O
for O
a O
good O
12 O
years O
.” O

Democrats B-ORG
are O
confident O
that O
if O
they O
can O
turn O
the O
race O
into O
a O
referendum O
on O
Johnson B-PER
, O
there O
are O
enough O
votes O
who O
have O
backed O
him O
in O
the O
past O
who O
are O
ready O
for O
an O
alternative O
. O

There O
is O
absolutely O
a O
world O
of O
ticket O
splitters O
, O
a O
world O
of O
persuadable O
voters O
and O
a O
world O
of O
people O
who O
might O
or O
might O
turn O
out O
, O
said O
Ben B-PER
Wikler I-PER
, O
chair O
of O
the O
Democratic B-ORG
Party I-ORG
of O
Wisconsin B-LOC
. O

Democrats O
do O
however O
face O
a O
difficult O
national O
environment O
, O
with O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
poll O
numbers O
slumping O
and O
voters O
across O
the O
country O
skeptical O
of O
Democratic O
leadership O
in O
Washington B-LOC
. O

With O
this O
in O
mind O
, O
Barnes B-PER
argued O
it O
would O
be O
Wisconsin B-LOC
Gov. O
Tony B-PER
Evers I-PER
– O
not O
the O
president O
– O
who O
would O
have O
the O
most O
direct O
impact O
on O
the O
contest O
. O

Evers O
himself O
is O
up O
for O
reelection O

While O
he O
did O
not O
have O
a O
primary O
challenge O
, O
he O
will O
likely O
face O
a O
tough O
race O
against O
whoever O
emerges O
from O
what O
has O
been O
a O
tight O
Republican O
primary O
race O
on O
Tuesday O
. O

This O
is O
a O
very O
Wisconsin B-LOC
focused O
race O
,” O
he O
said O
, O
citing O
a O
recent O
poll O
that O
found O
48% O
of O
Wisconsin B-LOC
voters O
approved O
of O
Evers B-PER
. O
“ O

I O
would O
say O
that O
people O
know O
the O
work O
that O
we’ve O
been O
doing O
here O
in O
state O
and O
this O
race O
isn’t O
going O
to O
be O
determined O
about O
what O
people O
think O
about O
national O
politics O

Editor’s O
Note: O
Emily B-PER
Parker I-PER
is O
executive O
director O
of O
global O
content O
at O
CoinDesk B-ORG
and O
a O
former O
policy O
advisor O
at O
the O
US B-ORG
State I-ORG
Department I-ORG
and O
writer/editor O
at O
The B-ORG
Wall I-ORG
Street I-ORG
Journal. I-ORG

She O
is O
the O
author O
of O
“Now O
I O
Know O
Who O
My O
Comrades O
Are: O
Voices O
From O
the O
Internet O
Underground.” O

Cryptocurrency O
is O
having O
an O
existential O
crisis O

Last O
month O
, O
crypto O
lender O
Celsius B-ORG
filed O
for O
bankruptcy O
protection O
. O

It O
has O
frozen O
withdrawals O
since O
June B-LOC
12 O
, O
and O
it’s O
unclear O
if O
or O
when O
customers O
will O
get O
their O
money O
back O
. O

But O
Celsius O
is O
just O
one O
domino O
to O
fall O

Crypto O
lender O
Voyager B-ORG
Digital I-ORG
also O
recently O
filed O
for O
bankruptcy O
protection O
. O

Ordinary O
investors O
who O
deposited O
their O
money O
into O
Voyager B-ORG
likely O
don’t O
know O
if O
or O
when O
they O
will O
see O
their O
funds O
again O

Bitcoin O
, O
meanwhile O
, O
recently O
fell O
more O
than O
70% O
off O
its O
all-time O
high O
from O
last O
year O
. O

And O
back O
in O
May B-LOC
, O
TerraUSD B-ORG
( O
UST O
) O
, O
a O
so-called O
stablecoin O
that O
was O
supposed O
to O
trade O
at O
$ O
1 O
, O
saw O
its O
price O
fall O
well O
below O
that O
, O
causing O
steep O
losses O
for O
those O
who O
held O
it O
or O
its O
sister O
coin O
Luna B-PER
( O
Luna’s O
value O
was O
linked O
to O
UST O
. O

The O
underlying O
problem O
is O
a O
combination O
of O
risky O
lending O
, O
poor O
risk O
management O
and O
opaque O
finances O
. O

So O
when O
crypto O
prices O
crashed O
, O
likely O
as O
a O
result O
of O
fears O
of O
rising O
inflation O
and O
the O
possibility O
of O
a O
recession O
, O
some O
crypto O
companies O
didn’t O
have O
the O
capital O
to O
cushion O
the O
blow O
. O

The O
result O
has O
been O
the O
disappearance O
of O
billions O
of O
dollars O
in O
value O
, O
often O
with O
ordinary O
investors O
paying O
the O
price O
. O

Cryptocurrencies O
like O
Bitcoin B-ORG
are O
supposed O
to O
be O
independent O
of O
any O
government O

But O
we O
have O
now O
reached O
the O
point O
where O
stronger O
government O
regulation O
of O
the O
crypto O
industry O
is O
both O
necessary O
and O
inevitable O

At O
the O
same O
time O
, O
the O
industry O
can’t O
just O
wait O
for O
the O
government O
to O
act O
. O

Crypto O
companies O
must O
also O
try O
to O
better O
police O
themselves O

That O
starts O
with O
providing O
more O
transparency O

While O
transparency O
is O
one O
of O
the O
core O
ideals O
of O
blockchain O
technology O
— O
all O
transactions O
on O
the O
Bitcoin B-ORG
blockchain O
are O
viewable O
for O
the O
world O
to O
see O
, O
for O
example O
— O
some O
crypto O
companies O
are O
strikingly O
opaque O
. O

In O
the O
case O
of O
Celsius B-ORG
, O
Vermont’s B-LOC
Department I-ORG
of I-ORG
Financial I-ORG
Regulation I-ORG
has O
said O
that O
“ O
customers O
did O
not O
receive O
critical O
disclosures O
about O
its O
financial O
condition O
, O
investing O
activities O
, O
risk O
factors O
, O
and O
ability O
to O
repay O
its O
obligations O
to O
depositors O
and O
other O
creditors O
.” O

At O
the O
very O
least O
, O
companies O
need O
to O
put O
much O
clearer O
warning O
labels O
on O
their O
products O
outlining O
the O
risks O
of O
depositing O
or O
investing O
with O
them O
, O
as O
well O
as O
more O
information O
about O
how O
customers’ O
deposits O
are O
being O
used O
. O

With O
stronger O
regulation O
, O
the O
Celsius B-ORG
situation O
might O
have O
played O
out O
differently O
. O

Its O
model O
was O
essentially O
to O
take O
user O
deposits O
and O
use O
them O
for O
risky O
and O
illiquid O
investments O
, O
and O
users O
enjoyed O
high O
interest O
rates O
in O
return O
. O

Celsius B-ORG
was O
essentially O
acting O
as O
a O
bank O
, O
without O
the O
regulatory O
protections O
or O
FDIC B-ORG
insurance O
. O

Prudential B-ORG
regulation O
, O
such O
as O
those O
applying O
to O
banks O
, O
would O
almost O
certainly O
have O
prevented O
many O
of O
the O
problems O
in O
our O
sector O
, O
Caitlin B-PER
Long I-PER
, O
CEO O
of O
depository O
institution O
Custodia B-ORG
Bank I-ORG
, O
said O
in O
an O
interview O
. O

Prudential B-ORG
capital O
requirements O
, O
investment O
restrictions O
, O
background O
checks O
on O
all O
executives O
, O
annual O
supervisory O
exams O
— O
all O
those O
things O
don’t O
apply O
to O
the O
crypto O
industry O
. O

They O
do O
apply O
to O
banks O
though O
.” O

This O
kind O
of O
regulatory O
overhaul O
isn’t O
likely O
to O
come O
anytime O
soon O
, O
however O
. O

That’s O
why O
venture O
capitalists O
and O
ordinary O
investors O
alike O
should O
push O
companies O
for O
greater O
transparency O
and O
accountability O
, O
demanding O
audits O
and O
disclosures O
about O
lending O
practices O
and O
capital O
reserves O
. O

When O
crypto O
prices O
were O
sky-high O
, O
few O
took O
a O
hard O
look O
at O
these O
companies’ O
business O
practices O
. O

The O
same O
was O
true O
with O
the O
stablecoin O
UST O

When O
the O
market O
was O
strong O
, O
few O
publicly O
pointed O
out O
what O
are O
now O
obvious O
red O
flags O
, O
and O
those O
who O
did O
risked O
being O
shouted O
down O
by O
crypto O
enthusiasts O
on O
social O
media O
. O

Now, O
UST’s O
dramatic O
collapse O
may O
well O
hasten O
stablecoin O
regulation O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States. I-LOC

There O
are O
widespread O
concerns O
that O
some O
of O
the O
leading O
stablecoins O
are O
not O
nearly O
as O
stable O
as O
they O
claim O
to O
be O
. O

The O
fear O
is O
that O
if O
investors O
decided O
en O
masse O
to O
redeem O
their O
coins O
for O
the O
US B-LOC
dollars O
that O
supposedly O
back O
them O
, O
the O
stablecoin O
issuer O
would O
not O
have O
enough O
cash O
on O
hand O
to O
fulfill O
these O
orders O
. O

US O
lawmakers O
were O
reportedly O
closing O
in O
on O
a O
bipartisan O
deal O
to O
regulate O
stablecoins O
, O
but O
consideration O
for O
the O
bill O
has O
been O
delayed O
until O
after O
August B-LOC

The O
bill O
, O
which O
is O
not O
yet O
public O
, O
would O
treat O
stablecoin O
issuers O
more O
like O
banks O
and O
subject O
them O
to O
federal O
supervision O
. O

It O
would O
also O
include O
strict O
requirements O
for O
the O
assets O
that O
back O
a O
stablecoin O
. O

Another O
bill O
by O
Sens O
. O

Cynthia B-PER
Lummis I-PER
and O
Kirsten B-PER
Gillibrand I-PER
aims O
to O
bring O
more O
regulatory O
clarity O
overall O
by O
creating O
a O
standard O
for O
deciding O
which O
digital O
assets O
are O
commodities O
and O
which O
are O
securities O

A O
clearer O
and O
more O
consistent O
regulatory O
framework O
around O
what O
companies O
can O
and O
can’t O
do O
, O
as O
well O
as O
which O
federal O
agency O
regulates O
which O
digital O
assets O
, O
could O
bring O
greater O
protections O
for O
ordinary O
investors O
. O

Hester B-PER
Peirce I-PER
, O
a O
commissioner O
at O
the O
SEC B-ORG
, O
has O
long O
argued O
for O
more O
regulatory O
clarity O
. O

If O
we O
decided O
that O
crypto O
lending O
is O
an O
area O
that O
we O
can O
implicate O
the O
securities O
laws O
, O
we O
could O
have O
sat O
down O
a O
long O
time O
ago O
and O
hammered O
out O
some O
rules O
around O
that O
that O
made O
sense O
, O
she O
said O
in O
an O
interview O
, O
speaking O
in O
her O
personal O
capacity O
. O

Instead, O
what O
you O
often O
get O
is O
regulation O
by O
enforcement, O
where O
companies O
are O
punished O
after O
the O
fact. O

One O
of O
the O
problems O
with O
these O
one-off O
enforcement O
actions O
is O
that O
they O
don’t O
necessarily O
cover O
the O
whole O
crypto O
landscape O
. O

Not O
only O
is O
that O
not O
particularly O
fair O
, O
because O
sometimes O
enforcement O
actions O
come O
late O
, O
and O
sometimes O
it’s O
a O
question O
of O
‘ O
why O
did O
you O
go O
after O
this O
project O
instead O
of O
this O
project O
, O
but O
also O
because O
it O
allows O
people O
who O
are O
really O
doing O
bad O
things O
to O
get O
lost O
in O
the O
shuffle O
, O
” O
Peirce B-PER
said O
. O

These O
proposals O
are O
all O
steps O
in O
the O
right O
direction O
for O
starting O
a O
serious O
conversation O
about O
crypto O
regulation O

But O
given O
other O
priorities O
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
it’s O
unclear O
when O
new O
regulations O
would O
take O
effect O
or O
what O
they O
will O
look O
like O
in O
their O
final O
form O
. O

Smart O
regulation O
is O
necessary O
, O
but O
it O
won’t O
be O
enough O
. O

Crypto O
innovation O
moves O
faster O
than O
any O
government’s O
attempt O
to O
rein O
it O
in O
. O

Political O
negotiations O
can O
also O
delay O
the O
passage O
of O
bills O
. O

Furthermore O
, O
with O
every O
new O
crisis O
, O
cryptocurrency O
loses O
more O
credibility O
. O

This O
could O
lead O
regulators O
to O
crack O
down O
harder O
than O
they O
would O
have O
otherwise O
, O
stifling O
innovation O
in O
a O
still-evolving O
field O
. O

An O
industry O
that O
prides O
itself O
on O
decentralization O
shouldn’t O
rely O
on O
the O
government O
to O
save O
it O
from O
itself O

لم O
تذكر O
شيئا O
عن O
مقتله O
.. O
طالبان B-ORG
: O
بايدن B-PER
" O
ادعى O
" O
استهداف O
الظواهري B-PER
وليس O
لدينا O
معلومات O
عن O
إقامته O
في O
كابول B-LOC
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

Editor’s O
Note: O
Nicole B-PER
Hemmer I-PER
is O
an O
associate O
research O
scholar O
at O
Columbia B-ORG
University I-ORG
with O
the O
Obama B-PER
Presidency O
Oral O
History O
Project O
and O
the O
author O
of O
“Messengers O
of O
the O
Right: O
Conservative O
Media O
and O
the O
Transformation O
of O
American B-LOC
Politics” O
and O
the O
forthcoming O
“Partisans: O
The O
Conservative O
Revolutionaries O
Who O
Remade O
American B-LOC
Politics O
in O
the O
1990s.” O

She O
cohosts O
the O
history O
podcasts O
“Past O
Present” O
and O
“This O
Day O
in O
Esoteric O
Political O
History.” O

The O
views O
expressed O
in O
this O
commentary O
are O
her O
own O

View O
more O
opinion O
on O
CNN B-ORG
. O

Jesse O
was O
real O

I’m O
a O
real O
mom O
. O

It’s O
an O
unthinkable O
statement O
for O
a O
grief-stricken O
parent O
to O
have O
to O
make O
: O
testifying O
that O
her O
6-year-old O
son O
, O
murdered O
while O
he O
sat O
in O
school O
, O
had O
actually O
lived O
, O
and O
that O
she O
was O
the O
woman O
who O
had O
given O
birth O
to O
him O
and O
raised O
him O
for O
the O
too-few O
years O
he O
was O
alive O
. O

But O
that O
was O
the O
testimony O
Scarlett B-PER
Lewis I-PER
gave O
this O
week O
at O
a O
hearing O
to O
determine O
damages O
against O
Alex B-PER
Jones I-PER
, O
a O
conspiracy O
theorist O
and O
media O
personality O
. O

Jones O
was O
held O
responsible O
for O
defamation O
in O
a O
default O
judgment O
earlier O
this O
year O
. O

After O
20 O
children O
and O
six O
adults O
were O
murdered O
at O
Sandy B-LOC
Hook I-LOC
Elementary I-LOC
School I-LOC
in O
2012 O
, O
Jones B-PER
began O
to O
spin O
lurid O
conspiracies O
that O
the O
shootings O
never O
happened O
and O
that O
the O
shattered O
families O
were O
simply O
actors O
. O

The O
conspiracy O
triggered O
years O
of O
harassment O
as O
conspiracists O
targeted O
the O
mourning O
parents O
, O
who O
have O
had O
to O
hire O
security O
to O
protect O
themselves O
. O

Since O
the O
defamation O
suits O
were O
filed O
, O
Jones B-PER
has O
apologized O
and O
claimed O
he O
was O
in O
the O
grip O
of O
a O
“form O
of O
psychosis” O
that O
caused O
him O
to O
believe O
the O
conspiracy O
theory O
. O

The O
Sandy B-LOC
Hook I-LOC
conspiracy O
made O
Jones B-PER
the O
talk-radio O
equivalent O
of O
the O
Westboro B-ORG
Baptist I-ORG
Church I-ORG
, O
which O
staged O
vile O
anti-gay O
protests O
at O
soldiers’ O
funerals O
. O

But O
within O
just O
a O
few O
years O
, O
Jones B-PER
would O
become O
part O
of O
the O
right-wing O
power O
structure O
, O
from O
his O
interviews O
with O
soon-to-be O
president O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
to O
his O
alleged O
role O
as O
an O
organizer O
at O
the O
January O
6 O
insurrection O
. O

More O
than O
that O
, O
many O
in O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
and O
conservative O
movement O
increasingly O
sound O
like O
Jones B-PER
, O
with O
talk O
of O
false O
flags O
, O
crisis O
actors O
and O
pedophile O
rings O
now O
a O
mainstay O
of O
right-wing O
rhetoric O
. O

And O
while O
the O
Trump B-PER
presidency O
opened O
the O
door O
for O
the O
mainstreaming O
of O
Jones B-PER
, O
it’s O
important O
to O
understand O
how O
ripe O
the O
GOP O
was O
for O
Alex B-PER
Jonesification I-PER
. O

From O
its O
beginning O
in O
the O
1940s O
and O
1950s O
, O
the O
modern O
conservative O
movement O
embraced O
a O
conspiratorial O
mindset O
. O

From O
books O
that O
argued O
former O
President O
Franklin B-PER
Roosevelt I-PER
allowed O
the O
Japanese O
to O
attack O
Pearl B-LOC
Harbor I-LOC
to O
unite O
Americans O
behind O
him O
in O
war O
, O
to O
the O
anti-fluoridation O
conspiracies O
of O
the O
John B-ORG
Birch I-ORG
Society I-ORG
, O
to O
the O
communist-around-every-corner O
witch O
hunts O
of O
the O
McCarthy B-PER
era O
, O
conspiracy O
theories O
have O
become O
a O
core O
component O
of O
conservatism O
in O
America B-LOC
. O

But O
with O
the O
exception O
of O
McCarthyism O
, O
the O
conspiracy-minded O
right O
remained O
distinct O
from O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
. O

Even O
right-wing O
politicians O
, O
especially O
those O
eyeing O
the O
presidency O
, O
shied O
away O
from O
the O
wild-eyed O
conspiracy-mongers O
popular O
with O
their O
conservative O
base O
. O

That O
changed O
in O
the O
1990s O
, O
as O
politics O
, O
entertainment O
and O
conspiracy O
became O
increasingly O
intertwined O
. O

Pat B-PER
Robertson I-PER
, O
the O
televangelist O
who O
ran O
for O
the O
Republican B-ORG
presidential O
nomination O
in O
1988 O
, O
published O
his O
conspiracy O
tract O
, O
“The O
New O
World O
Order O
,” O
in O
1991 O
. O

Drawing O
from O
several O
decades’ O
worth O
of O
conspiracies O
about O
“one-world O
government,” O
Robertson B-PER
detailed O
a O
coalition O
of O
the O
Trilateral B-ORG
Commission, I-ORG
Illuminati, B-ORG
Bilderberg B-ORG
Group, I-ORG
Free B-ORG
Masons I-ORG
and O
others O
working O
to O
bring O
about O
a O
single O
global O
governance O
and, O
ultimately, O
the O
End O
Times. O

It O
was O
a O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
Times I-ORG
bestseller O
. O

Robertson B-PER
wasn’t O
the O
only O
Republican O
presidential O
candidate O
warning O
about O
the O
new O
world O
order O
. O

It O
became O
a O
staple O
of O
Pat B-PER
Buchanan I-PER
’s O
speeches O
in O
all O
three O
of O
his O
presidential O
runs O
between O
1992 O
and O
2000 O

And O
while O
the O
phrase O
spoke O
to O
anxieties O
about O
the O
geopolitics O
of O
a O
post-Cold O
War O
world O
, O
it O
also O
nodded O
to O
the O
conspiracy O
theories O
that O
were O
becoming O
increasingly O
popular O
not O
just O
among O
the O
conservative O
base O
but O
for O
Republican O
officeholders O
as O
well O
. O

During O
the O
Clinton B-ORG
years O
, O
members O
of O
Congress B-ORG
held O
inquiries O
into O
black O
helicopters O
( O
a O
staple O
of O
1990s O
conspiracies O
) O
and O
mainlined O
countless O
conspiracy O
theories O
about O
Bill B-PER
and O
Hillary B-PER
Clinton I-PER
. O

Outside O
of O
Congress B-LOC
, O
the O
newly O
powerful O
right-wing O
radio O
of O
the O
1990s O
and O
2000s O
likewise O
paved O
the O
way O
for O
an O
embrace O
of O
Jones B-PER

Glenn B-PER
Beck’s I-PER
radio O
program O
cycled O
through O
conspiracies O
with O
breathtaking O
speed O
, O
pinging O
from O
Common O
Core O
to O
George B-PER
Soros I-PER
to O
Agenda O
21 O
, O
a O
United B-ORG
Nations-based I-ORG
conspiracy O
theory O
. O

He O
mixed O
politics O
and O
conspiracy O
not O
only O
in O
his O
content O
but O
his O
advertising O

Warning O
that O
the O
End O
Times O
were O
near O
, O
that O
catastrophe O
lurked O
around O
every O
corner O
, O
Beck B-PER
pushed O
everything O
from O
gold O
to O
food O
storage O
to O
“survival O
seeds,” O
all O
aimed O
at O
helping O
listeners O
survive O
the O
impending O
collapse O
of O
society O
. O

In O
the O
years O
since O
, O
Beck B-PER
has O
admitted O
that O
he O
“ O
played O
a O
role O
, O
unfortunately O
, O
in O
helping O
tear O
the O
country O
apart O
. O
） O

These O
threads O
came O
together O
in O
the O
Obama B-PER
years O
, O
as O
Beck B-PER
became O
one O
of O
the O
most O
prominent O
voices O
in O
the O
Tea B-ORG
Party I-ORG
movement O
and O
conspiracism O
ran O
rampant O
on O
the O
right O
. O
