The B-PER
Wyden I-PER
the O
night O
and O
into O
Sunday O
morning O
, O
taking O
a O
series O
of O
back-to-back O
amendment O
votes O
that O
are O
among O
the O
last O
steps O
toward O
final O
passage O
of O
Democrats’ O
sweeping O
health O
care O
and O
climate O
bill O
– O
putting O
the O
package O
on O
track O
to O
be O
approved O
by O
the O
chamber O
as O
soon O
as O
this O
weekend O
. O
The O
process O
is O
known O
on O
Capitol B-LOC
Hill I-LOC
as O
a O
“vote-a-rama O
,” O
and O
started O
Saturday O
night O
shortly O
after O
11:30 O
p.m. O
ET O
, O
and O
which O
is O
expected O
to O
stretch O
well O
into O
Sunday O
. O
A O
vote O
on O
final O
passage O
of O
the O
bill O
will O
take O
place O
when O
amendment O
votes O
end O
, O
the O
timing O
of O
which O
it O
is O
not O
yet O
clear O
. O
The O
bill O
– O
named O
the O
Inflation O
Reduction O
Act O
– O
would O
represent O
the O
largest O
climate O
investment O
in O
US B-LOC
history O
and O
make O
major O
changes O
to O
health O
policy O
by O
giving O
Medicare O
the O
power O
for O
the O
first O
time O
to O
negotiate O
the O
prices O
of O
certain O
prescription O
drugs O
and O
extending O
expiring O
health O
care O
subsidies O
for O
three O
years O
. O
The O
legislation O
would O
impose O
new O
taxes O
to O
pay O
for O
it O
. O
The O
package O
is O
the O
product O
of O
painstaking O
negotiations O
and O
will O
give O
Democrats O
a O
chance O
to O
achieve O
major O
policy O
objectives O
ahead O
of O
the O
upcoming O
midterm O
elections O
. O
Senate O
Democrats O
are O
using O
a O
special O
process O
to O
pass O
the O
package O
without O
Republican O
votes O
. O
Once O
the O
legislation O
has O
passed O
in O
the O
Senate O
, O
it O
would O
next O
need O
to O
be O
approved O
by O
the O
House O
of O
Representatives O
before O
President B-PER
Joe I-PER
Biden I-PER
could O
sign O
it O
into O
law O
. O
What O
happens O
next O
Following O
the O
procedural O
vote O
to O
proceed O
to O
the O
bill O
, O
the O
Senate O
entered O
debate O
before O
moving O
into O
the O
“vote-a-rama O
.” O
The O
marathon O
series O
of O
amendment O
votes O
with O
no O
time O
limit O
must O
run O
its O
course O
before O
a O
final O
vote O
can O
take O
place O
. O
Republicans O
are O
using O
the O
“vote-a-rama O
” O
to O
put O
Democrats O
on O
the O
spot O
and O
force O
politically O
tough O
votes O
, O
and O
votes O
on O
contentious O
policy O
issues O
are O
expected O
. O
As O
expected O
, O
key O
insulin O
provisions O
were O
struck O
out O
of O
the O
bill O
after O
Republicans O
raised O
a O
point O
of O
order O
, O
resulting O
in O
a O
vote O
to O
strip O
them O
out O
. O
The O
final O
vote O
was O
57-43 O
. O
A O
60-vote O
threshold O
was O
needed O
to O
keep O
the O
provision O
in O
place O
. O
The O
provisions O
initially O
included O
in O
the O
bill O
would O
have O
limited O
insulin O
prices O
to O
$35 O
per O
month O
in O
both O
the O
private O
insurance O
market O
as O
well O
as O
through O
Medicare O
. O
But O
the O
Senate O
parliamentarian O
ruled O
that O
the O
cap O
on O
insulin O
in O
the O
private O
insurance O
market O
was O
not O
compliant O
with O
the O
reconciliation O
rules O
Democrats O
are O
utilizing O
to O
push O
their O
legislation O
through O
the O
chamber O
. O
Democrats O
kept O
both O
provisions O
in O
the O
bill O
anyway O
, O
but O
Republicans O
raised O
a O
point O
of O
order O
to O
force O
a O
vote O
to O
strike O
the O
provisions O
only O
from O
the O
private O
marketplace O
. O
The O
Medicare O
$35 O
insulin O
cap O
remains O
in O
place O
. O
The O
House O
is O
poised O
to O
come O
back O
to O
take O
up O
the O
legislation O
on O
Friday O
, O
August O
12 O
, O
according O
to O
House O
Majority O
Leader O
Steny B-PER
Hoyer I-PER
’s O
office O
. O
How O
Democrats O
plan O
to O
pass O
the O
sweeping O
legislation O
Senate O
Democrats O
only O
need O
a O
simple O
majority O
for O
final O
passage O
of O
the O
bill O
since O
they O
are O
using O
a O
process O
known O
as O
reconciliation O
, O
which O
allows O
them O
to O
avoid O
a O
Republican O
filibuster O
and O
corresponding O
60-vote O
threshold O
. O
In O
order O
to O
pass O
a O
bill O
through O
the O
reconciliation O
process O
, O
however O
, O
the O
package O
must O
comply O
with O
a O
strict O
set O
of O
budget O
rules O
. O
The O
Senate O
parliamentarian O
has O
to O
decide O
whether O
the O
provisions O
in O
the O
bill O
meet O
the O
rules O
to O
allow O
Democrats O
to O
use O
the O
filibuster-proof O
budget O
process O
to O
pass O
the O
legislation O
along O
straight O
party O
lines O
. O
Senate O
Majority O
Leader O
Chuck B-PER
Schumer I-PER
announced O
Saturday O
that O
after O
undergoing O
the O
parliamentarian’s O
review O
, O
the O
bill O
“remains O
largely O
intact O
.” O
“The O
bill O
, O
when O
passed O
, O
will O
meet O
all O
of O
our O
goals O
– O
fighting O
climate O
change O
, O
lowering O
health O
care O
costs O
, O
closing O
tax O
loopholes O
abused O
by O
the O
wealthy O
and O
reducing O
the O
deficit O
,” O
the O
New O
York O
Democrat O
said O
. O
In O
a O
key O
ruling O
, O
the O
parliamentarian O
, O
Elizabeth B-PER
MacDonough I-PER
, O
allowed O
a O
major O
component O
of O
the O
Democrats’ O
prescription O
drug O
pricing O
plans O
to O
move O
ahead O
– O
giving O
Medicare O
the O
power O
to O
negotiate O
the O
prices O
of O
certain O
prescription O
drugs O
for O
the O
first O
time O
. O
But O
MacDonough O
narrowed O
another O
provision O
aimed O
at O
lowering O
drug O
prices O
– O
imposing O
penalties O
on O
drug O
companies O
if O
they O
increase O
their O
prices O
faster O
than O
inflation O
. O
Democrats O
had O
wanted O
the O
measure O
to O
apply O
both O
to O
Medicare O
and O
the O
private O
insurance O
market O
. O
But O
the O
parliamentarian O
ruled O
the O
inflation O
cap O
could O
only O
apply O
to O
Medicare O
, O
a O
Democratic O
aide O
said O
. O
Meanwhile O
, O
MacDonough O
ruled O
to O
keep O
intact O
several O
climate O
measures O
from O
the O
Environment O
and O
Public O
Works O
Committee O
in O
the O
reconciliation O
bill O
, O
including O
a O
methane O
fee O
that O
would O
apply O
to O
oil O
and O
gas O
producers O
leaking O
the O
potent O
greenhouse O
gas O
methane O
above O
a O
certain O
threshold O
. O
Earlier O
Saturday O
, O
Senate O
Finance O
Chair O
Ron B-PER
Wyden I-PER
of O
Oregon B-LOC
announced O
that O
the O
clean O
energy O
tax O
portion O
of O
the O
bill O
“adheres O
to O
Senate O
rules O
, O
and O
important O
provisions O
to O
ensure O
our O
clean O
energy O
future O
is O
built O
in O
America B-LOC
have O
been O
approved O
by O
the O
parliamentarian O
.” O
How O
the O
bill O
addresses O
the O
climate O
crisis O
For O
a O
party O
that O
failed O
to O
pass O
major O
climate O
legislation O
over O
10 O
years O
ago O
, O
the O
reconciliation O
bill O
represents O
a O
major O
, O
long-fought O
victory O
for O
Democrats O
. O
The O
nearly O
$370 O
billion O
clean O
energy O
and O
climate O
package O
is O
the O
largest O
climate O
investment O
in O
US B-LOC
history O
, O
and O
the O
biggest O
victory O
for O
the O
environmental O
movement O
since O
the O
landmark O
Clean O
Air O
Act O
. O
It O
also O
comes O
at O
a O
critical O
time O
; O
this O
summer O
has O
seen O
punishing O
heat O
waves O
and O
deadly O
floods O
across O
the O
country O
, O
which O
scientists O
say O
are O
both O
linked O
to O
a O
warming O
planet O
. O
Analysis O
from O
Schumer’s O
office O
– O
as O
well O
as O
multiple O
independent O
analyses O
– O
suggests O
the O
measures O
would O
reduce O
US B-LOC
carbon O
emissions O
by O
up O
to O
40% O
by O
2030 O
. O
Strong O
climate O
regulations O
from O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration O
and O
action O
from O
states O
would O
be O
needed O
to O
get O
to O
Biden’s O
goal O
of O
cutting O
emissions O
50% O
by O
2030 O
. O
The O
bill O
also O
contains O
many O
tax O
incentives O
meant O
to O
bring O
down O
the O
cost O
of O
electricity O
with O
more O
renewables O
, O
and O
spur O
more O
American B-MISC
consumers O
to O
switch O
to O
electricity O
to O
power O
their O
homes O
and O
vehicles O
. O
Lawmakers O
said O
the O
bill O
represents O
a O
monumental O
victory O
and O
is O
also O
just O
the O
start O
of O
what O
’s O
needed O
to O
combat O
the O
climate O
crisis O
. O
“This O
isn’t O
about O
the O
laws O
of O
politics O
, O
this O
is O
about O
the O
laws O
of O
physics O
,” O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Brian B-PER
Schatz I-PER
of O
Hawaii B-LOC
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
“We O
all O
knew O
coming O
into O
this O
effort O
that O
we O
had O
to O
do O
what O
the O
science O
tells O
us O
what O
we O
need O
to O
do O
.” O
Key O
health O
care O
and O
tax O
policy O
in O
the O
bill O
The O
bill O
would O
empower O
Medicare O
to O
negotiate O
prices O
of O
certain O
costly O
medications O
administered O
in O
doctors’ O
offices O
or O
purchased O
at O
the O
pharmacy O
. O
The O
Health O
and O
Human O
Services O
secretary O
would O
negotiate O
the O
prices O
of O
10 O
drugs O
in O
2026 O
, O
and O
another O
15 O
drugs O
in O
2027 O
and O
again O
in O
2028 O
. O
The O
number O
would O
rise O
to O
20 O
drugs O
a O
year O
for O
2029 O
and O
beyond O
. O
This O
controversial O
provision O
is O
far O
more O
limited O
than O
the O
one O
House O
Democratic O
leaders O
have O
backed O
in O
the O
past O
. O
But O
it O
would O
open O
the O
door O
to O
fulfilling O
a O
longstanding O
party O
goal O
of O
allowing O
Medicare O
to O
use O
its O
heft O
to O
lower O
drug O
costs O
. O
Democrats O
are O
also O
planning O
to O
extend O
the O
enhanced O
federal O
premium O
subsidies O
for O
Obamacare O
coverage O
through O
2025 O
, O
a O
year O
later O
than O
lawmakers O
recently O
discussed O
. O
That O
way O
they O
wouldn’t O
expire O
just O
after O
the O
2024 O
presidential O
election O
. O
To O
boost O
revenue O
, O
the O
bill O
would O
impose O
a O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
on O
the O
income O
large O
corporations O
report O
to O
shareholders O
, O
known O
as O
book O
income O
, O
as O
opposed O
to O
the O
Internal O
Revenue O
Service O
. O
The O
measure O
, O
which O
would O
raise O
$258 O
billion O
over O
a O
decade O
, O
would O
apply O
to O
companies O
with O
profits O
over O
$1 O
billion O
. O
Concerned O
about O
how O
this O
provision O
would O
affect O
certain O
businesses O
, O
particularly O
manufacturers O
, O
Sinema O
has O
suggested O
that O
she O
won O
changes O
to O
the O
Democrats’ O
plan O
to O
pare O
back O
how O
companies O
can O
deduct O
depreciated O
assets O
from O
their O
taxes O
. O
The O
details O
remain O
unclear O
. O
However O
, O
Sinema O
nixed O
her O
party’s O
effort O
to O
tighten O
the O
carried O
interest O
loophole O
, O
which O
allows O
investment O
managers O
to O
treat O
much O
of O
their O
compensation O
as O
capital O
gains O
and O
pay O
a O
20% O
long-term O
capital O
gains O
tax O
rate O
instead O
of O
income O
tax O
rates O
of O
up O
to O
37% O
. O
The O
provision O
would O
have O
lengthened O
the O
amount O
of O
time O
investment O
managers’ O
profit O
interest O
must O
be O
held O
from O
three O
years O
to O
five O
years O
to O
take O
advantage O
of O
the O
lower O
tax O
rate O
. O
Addressing O
this O
loophole O
, O
which O
would O
have O
raised O
$14 O
billion O
over O
a O
decade O
, O
had O
been O
a O
longtime O
goal O
of O
congressional O
Democrats O
. O
In O
its O
place O
, O
a O
1% O
excise O
tax O
on O
companies’ O
stock O
buybacks O
was O
added O
, O
raising O
another O
$74 O
billion O
, O
according O
to O
a O
Democratic O
aide O
. O
This O
story O
and O
headline O
have O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
developments O
. O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Jessica O
Dean I-ORG
, O
Manu O
Raju I-ORG
, O
Ella O
Nilsen I-ORG
, O
Tami O
Luhby I-ORG
, O
Katie O
Lobosco I-ORG
, O
Morgan O
Rimmer I-ORG
, O
Melanie O
Zanona I-ORG
and O
Kristin O
Wilson I-ORG
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Inside O
Sienna B-PER
Miller I-PER
's O
charming O
English B-LOC
country O
cottage O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Style O
! O
[fwp_0] O
( O
https O
: O
// O
ads.stickyadstv.com O
/ O
user-matching O
? O
id O
= O
185 O
& O
_fw_gdpr O
= O
0 O
& O
_fw_gdpr_consent O
= O
) O
! O
[fwp_1] O
( O
https O
: O
// O
ads.stickyadstv.com O
/ O
auto-user-sync O
) O

Rep. B-MISC
Peter B-PER
Meijer I-PER
of O
Michigan B-LOC
, O
one O
of O
10 O
House O
Republicans O
who O
voted O
to O
impeach O
former O
President B-PER
Donald I-PER
Trump I-PER
last O
year O
, O
has O
lost O
to O
a O
fervent O
election O
denier O
running O
with O
Trump’s O
support O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projected O
early O
Wednesday O
. O
Republicans O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
and O
Arizona B-LOC
– O
two O
states O
at O
the O
center O
of O
Trump’s O
2020 O
election O
denial O
campaign O
– O
voted O
on O
Tuesday O
in O
primaries O
for O
crucial O
federal O
and O
state O
contests O
as O
the O
shape O
of O
the O
2022 O
midterms O
comes O
into O
focus O
less O
than O
a O
hundred O
days O
from O
Election O
Day O
. O
Trump’s O
picks O
will O
win O
the O
GOP O
gubernatorial O
nod O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
as O
well O
as O
the O
GOP O
nominations O
for O
US B-ORG
Senate I-ORG
, O
secretary O
of O
state O
and O
attorney O
general O
in O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
In O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
one O
significant O
loss O
was O
that O
of O
state O
House O
Speaker O
Rusty B-PER
Bowers I-PER
, O
who O
delivered O
emotional O
testimony O
before O
the O
House O
January B-MISC
6 I-MISC
committee O
about O
his O
resolve O
in O
the O
face O
of O
enormous O
pressure O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
results O
. O
He’ll O
lose O
a O
GOP O
state O
Senate O
primary O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projected O
early O
Wednesday O
. O
Trump’s O
loss O
in O
those O
battleground O
states O
two O
years O
ago O
seeded O
right-wing O
anger O
and O
turned O
Republican O
primary O
campaigns O
up O
and O
down O
the O
ballot O
into O
referendums O
on O
his O
election O
lies O
. O
Allies O
of O
the O
former O
President B-PER
sought O
offices O
crucial O
to O
the O
balance O
of O
power O
in O
Washington B-LOC
and O
in O
state O
governments O
, O
where O
the O
GOP O
is O
hoping O
to O
gain O
control O
of O
the O
election O
apparatus O
ahead O
of O
the O
2024 O
presidential O
contest O
. O
With O
his O
loss O
to O
former O
Trump B-PER
administration O
official O
John B-PER
Gibbs I-PER
, O
Meijer B-PER
becomes O
the O
second O
of O
the O
so-called O
“impeachment O
10” O
to O
lose O
reelection O
after O
South B-LOC
Carolina I-LOC
Rep. B-MISC
Tom B-PER
Rice I-PER
lost O
to O
a O
Trump-backed O
challenger O
in O
June O
. O
Two O
others O
– O
Washington B-LOC
Reps. O
Jaime B-PER
Herrera I-PER
Beutler I-PER
and O
Dan B-PER
Newhouse I-PER
– O
were O
also O
facing O
challengers O
from O
their O
own O
party O
on O
Tuesday O
, O
but O
CNN B-ORG
has O
not O
yet O
projected O
whether O
they’ll O
be O
advancing O
to O
the O
general O
election O
. O
( O
Under O
Washington’s O
primary O
system O
, O
the O
top O
two O
finishers O
regardless O
of O
party O
advance O
to O
November O
.) O
Rep. B-MISC
Liz B-PER
Cheney I-PER
of O
Wyoming B-LOC
, O
perhaps O
the O
most O
high-profile O
of O
the O
House O
Republicans O
to O
have O
voted O
for O
impeachment O
because O
of O
her O
role O
as O
vice O
chair O
of O
the O
House O
select O
committee O
investigating O
January B-MISC
6 I-MISC
, O
2021 O
, O
faces O
a O
Trump-backed O
opponent O
later O
this O
month O
. O
One O
of O
the O
impeachment O
10 O
– O
California B-LOC
Rep. B-MISC
David B-PER
Valadao I-PER
– O
survived O
earlier O
this O
year O
, O
advancing O
to O
the O
November O
election O
in O
the O
Golden O
State’s O
top O
two O
system O
, O
while O
four O
of O
the O
Republicans O
who O
voted O
for O
impeachment O
are O
not O
running O
for O
reelection O
. O
Meijer’s O
primary O
in O
his O
western O
Michigan B-LOC
district O
had O
become O
a O
flashpoint O
in O
both O
parties’ O
national O
infighting O
because O
Gibbs O
was O
the O
beneficiary O
of O
Democratic O
meddling O
. O
The O
party’s O
House O
campaign O
arm O
, O
believing O
that O
Gibbs O
would O
be O
a O
less O
viable O
general O
election O
candidate O
, O
ran O
more O
than O
$300,000 O
in O
ads O
ostensibly O
attacking O
his O
alliance O
with O
Trump O
with O
the O
goal O
of O
boosting O
him O
in O
the O
primary O
. O
But O
that O
strategy O
angered O
some O
on O
the O
left O
who O
thought O
it O
undermined O
their O
broader O
messaging O
against O
political O
extremism O
in O
the O
GOP O
, O
while O
sparking O
fears O
the O
gamble O
could O
backfire O
if O
Gibbs O
makes O
it O
to O
Congress O
. O
As O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
KFILE O
first O
reported O
in O
2018 O
, O
Gibbs O
has O
a O
history O
of O
conspiratorial O
and O
inflammatory O
tweets O
and O
defended O
a O
notorious O
anti-Semitic O
troll O
banned O
by O
Twitter B-ORG
. O
In O
Michigan’s O
gubernatorial O
primary O
, O
Trump-backed O
Tudor B-PER
Dixon I-PER
had O
the O
support O
of O
former O
Education O
Secretary O
Betsy B-PER
DeVos I-PER
and O
benefited O
from O
the O
disqualification O
of O
five O
would-be O
candidates O
after O
thousands O
of O
forged O
signatures O
were O
found O
on O
nominating O
petitions O
. O
A O
conservative O
commentator O
who O
had O
coalesced O
support O
from O
prominent O
Republicans O
in O
the O
state O
, O
Dixon O
beat O
back O
criticism O
that O
she O
was O
an O
establishment O
candidate O
who O
wasn’t O
“MAGA” O
enough O
. O
Dixon O
will O
be O
taking O
on O
Democratic O
Gov. B-PER
Gretchen I-PER
Whitmer I-PER
, O
who O
is O
seeking O
a O
second O
term O
. O
Whitmer O
is O
a O
key O
piece O
of O
the O
Democratic O
bulwark O
against O
Republican O
power O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
, O
where O
the O
GOP O
controls O
both O
legislative O
chambers O
. O
Tuesday O
also O
provided O
voters O
with O
their O
first O
chance O
to O
directly O
respond O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Supreme I-ORG
Court’s O
striking O
down O
of O
federal O
abortion O
rights O
earlier O
this O
summer O
– O
an O
issue O
that O
national O
Democrats O
hope O
will O
energize O
their O
base O
in O
the O
fall O
. O
Kansas B-LOC
voters O
have O
decided O
to O
maintain O
the O
right O
to O
an O
abortion O
in O
their O
state’s O
constitution O
by O
voting O
“no” O
on O
a O
proposed O
constitutional O
amendment O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
The O
procedure O
is O
currently O
legal O
up O
to O
22 O
weeks O
in O
Kansas B-LOC
, O
where O
people O
from O
Texas B-LOC
, O
Oklahoma B-LOC
and O
Missouri B-LOC
have O
traveled O
for O
services O
amid O
Republican-led O
efforts O
to O
roll O
back O
abortion O
rights O
. O
Senate O
primaries O
will O
set O
crucial O
fall O
matchups O
. O
In O
Missouri B-LOC
, O
state O
Attorney O
General O
Eric B-PER
Schmitt I-PER
will O
win O
the O
GOP O
Senate O
nomination O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
His O
victory O
is O
a O
relief O
for O
national O
party O
leadership O
anxious O
that O
former O
Gov. B-PER
Eric I-PER
Greitens I-PER
would O
win O
and O
then O
lose O
the O
general O
election O
in O
November O
. O
Greitens O
had O
resigned O
in O
2018 O
amid O
a O
sex O
scandal O
and O
accusations O
of O
campaign O
misconduct O
and O
more O
recently O
faced O
allegations O
of O
abuse O
from O
his O
ex-wife O
, O
which O
he O
has O
denied O
. O
Schmitt O
and O
Greitens O
shared O
an O
11th-hour O
endorsement O
from O
Trump B-PER
, O
who O
said O
on O
Monday O
he O
was O
backing O
“Eric” O
and O
leaving O
it O
up O
to O
voters O
to O
decide O
which O
one O
, O
although O
both O
candidates O
immediately O
tried O
to O
claim O
the O
endorsement O
for O
themselves O
. O
Echoing O
a O
pledge O
from O
Greitens O
, O
Schmitt O
– O
who O
was O
endorsed O
by O
Sens. O
Ted B-PER
Cruz I-PER
of O
Texas B-LOC
and O
Mike B-PER
Lee I-PER
of O
Utah B-LOC
– O
said O
last O
week O
that O
he O
would O
not O
support O
Senate O
Minority O
Leader O
Mitch B-PER
McConnell I-PER
for O
leader O
. O
While O
Trump O
hedged O
his O
bets O
, O
the O
state’s O
junior O
senator O
, O
Josh B-PER
Hawley I-PER
, O
suffered O
a O
loss O
after O
backing O
Rep. B-MISC
Vicky B-PER
Hartzler I-PER
. O
One O
of O
two O
members O
of O
Congress O
seeking O
the O
nomination O
, O
she O
was O
critical O
of O
Trump O
in O
the O
aftermath O
of O
January B-MISC
6 I-MISC
, O
but O
still O
voted O
against O
certifying O
the O
presidential O
vote O
and O
touted O
her O
voting O
record O
with O
Trump O
on O
the O
trail O
. O
In O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
Blake B-PER
Masters I-PER
, O
an O
acolyte O
of O
Silicon O
Valley O
billionaire O
Peter B-PER
Thiel I-PER
who O
was O
Trump’s O
pick O
in O
that O
race O
, O
won O
the O
Republicans’ O
nomination O
to O
take O
on O
Democratic O
Sen. B-PER
Mark I-PER
Kelly I-PER
in O
November O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
A O
proxy O
war O
between O
Trump O
and O
Pence O
The O
race O
to O
succeed O
term-limited O
Arizona B-LOC
Republican O
Gov. B-PER
Doug B-PER
Ducey I-PER
split O
the O
party O
, O
with O
Ducey O
and O
former O
Vice O
President O
Mike B-PER
Pence I-PER
endorsing O
Karrin B-PER
Taylor I-PER
Robson I-PER
and O
Trump O
backing O
former O
television O
reporter O
Kari B-PER
Lake I-PER
, O
whose O
campaign O
was O
fueled O
by O
the O
former O
President’s O
election O
lies O
. O
Down O
the O
ballot O
in O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
Trump-backed O
election-denying O
state O
Rep. B-MISC
Mark B-PER
Finchem I-PER
, O
who O
attended O
the O
January B-MISC
6 I-MISC
, O
2021 O
rally O
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
will O
win O
the O
Republican O
nomination O
for O
Arizona B-LOC
Secretary O
of O
State O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
The O
Democratic O
primary O
for O
Arizona B-LOC
Secretary O
of O
State O
remains O
too O
early O
to O
call O
. O
And O
in O
the O
attorney O
general’s O
race O
, O
Trump’s O
preferred O
candidate O
, O
election O
denier O
Abraham B-PER
Hamadeh I-PER
, O
won O
the O
Republican O
nomination O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
Democratic O
Secretary O
of O
State O
Katie B-PER
Hobbs I-PER
will O
win O
the O
Democratic O
nod O
for O
governor O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O
Moderate O
prevails O
in O
member O
vs. O
member O
primary O
. O
Besides O
the O
GOP O
drama O
in O
Michigan’s O
3rd O
District O
, O
Meanwhile O
, O
in O
Michigan’s O
11th O
Congressional O
District O
, O
Rep. B-MISC
Haley B-PER
Stevens I-PER
will O
defeat O
fellow O
Democratic O
Rep. B-MISC
Andy B-PER
Levin I-PER
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
, O
in O
a O
clash O
of O
incumbents O
that O
was O
the O
latest O
chapter O
of O
a O
proxy O
fight O
between O
moderates O
and O
progressives O
. O
UDP’s O
outlay O
, O
along O
with O
bundling O
by O
AIPAC O
, O
spurred O
another O
pro-Israel O
group O
, O
the O
liberal O
J O
Street O
, O
to O
jump O
in O
on O
Levin’s O
behalf O
, O
splashing O
$700,000 O
in O
a O
July O
ad O
buy O
for O
him O
. O

articleBody O
Former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
’s O
legal O
team O
is O
in O
direct O
communication O
with O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
officials O
, O
the O
first O
sign O
of O
talks O
between O
the O
two O
sides O
as O
the O
criminal O
probe O
into O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
accelerates O
, O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
tell O
CNN B-ORG
. O
The O
talks O
revolve O
around O
whether O
Trump B-PER
would O
be O
able O
to O
shield O
conversations O
he O
had O
while O
he O
was O
president O
from O
federal O
investigators O
. O
In O
recent O
weeks O
, O
investigators O
have O
moved O
aggressively O
into O
Trump’s B-PER
orbit O
, O
subpoenaing O
top O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
officials O
, O
focusing O
on O
efforts O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
and O
executing O
searches O
of O
lawyers O
who O
sought O
to O
aid O
those O
efforts O
. O
The O
Trump B-PER
team O
’s O
discussions O
are O
with O
the O
US B-ORG
attorney O
’s O
office O
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
DC I-LOC
, O
which O
is O
in O
charge O
of O
the O
investigation O
, O
and O
its O
top O
January O
6 O
prosecutor O
Thomas B-PER
Windom I-PER
, O
the O
sources O
said O
. O
At O
this O
stage O
, O
the O
conversations O
are O
focused O
mostly O
on O
whether O
any O
communications O
that O
witnesses O
from O
the O
Trump B-PER
West O
Wing O
had O
with O
the O
former O
President O
can O
be O
kept O
from O
a O
federal O
criminal O
grand O
jury O
under O
Trump’s B-PER
claims O
of O
executive O
privilege O
, O
the O
people O
said O
. O
The O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
has O
been O
anticipating O
a O
court O
fight O
with O
Trump B-PER
over O
executive O
privilege O
. O
The O
issue O
has O
arisen O
as O
grand O
jury O
subpoenas O
have O
been O
issued O
to O
two O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
counsel’s O
office O
officials O
and O
to O
former O
Vice B-PER
President I-PER
Mike B-PER
Pence I-PER
’s O
chief O
counsel O
and O
chief O
of O
staff O
. O
Trump B-PER
’s O
legal O
defense O
team O
has O
warned O
him O
that O
indictments O
are O
possible O
, O
sources O
tell O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Some O
members O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
legal O
team O
have O
discussed O
his O
potential O
defense O
strategies O
on O
at O
least O
two O
occasions O
in O
recent O
months O
, O
according O
to O
two O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
, O
as O
they O
brace O
for O
new O
developments O
in O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
probe O
and O
a O
separate O
investigation O
by O
Georgia B-LOC
officials O
into O
his O
potentially O
criminal O
meddling O
in O
the O
state’s O
2020 O
election O
results O
. O
Rolling O
Stone O
previously O
reported O
that O
Trump B-PER
had O
been O
briefed O
. O
Trump B-PER
has O
grilled O
his O
attorneys O
on O
whether O
they O
actually O
believe O
he O
will O
face O
formal O
charges O
, O
sources O
said O
. O
Yet O
the O
former O
President O
has O
expressed O
a O
heavy O
dose O
of O
skepticism O
that O
he O
will O
be O
indicted O
, O
one O
of O
the O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
said O
. O
Another O
source O
close O
to O
the O
former O
President O
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
Trump B-PER
also O
has O
posed O
questions O
about O
a O
potential O
indictment O
to O
members O
of O
his O
inner O
circle O
, O
some O
of O
whom O
believe O
the O
President O
is O
concerned O
about O
the O
possibility O
of O
federal O
charges O
. O
But O
one O
person O
close O
to O
Trump B-PER
said O
he O
is O
noticeably O
more O
engaged O
when O
he O
is O
chatting O
with O
friends O
and O
advisers O
about O
the O
2022 O
midterms O
and O
his O
possible O
presidential O
campaign O
in O
2024 O
than O
he O
has O
been O
during O
briefings O
on O
legal O
strategy O
. O
This O
person O
described O
the O
former O
President O
as O
dismissive O
in O
conversations O
about O
his O
legal O
troubles O
, O
often O
repeating O
his O
“ O
witch O
hunt O
” O
mantra O
as O
he O
claims O
the O
various O
probes O
he O
’s O
facing O
are O
plainly O
driven O
by O
political O
opponents O
. O
A O
Trump B-PER
spokesman O
said O
in O
a O
statement O
to O
CNN B-ORG
: O
“ O
There O
is O
clearly O
a O
concerted O
effort O
to O
undermine O
the O
vital O
, O
Constitutionally-rooted O
Executive O
and O
Attorney-Client O
Privileges O
through O
partisan O
, O
political O
persecution O
. O
” O
“ O
How O
can O
any O
future O
President O
ever O
have O
private O
conversations O
with O
his O
attorneys O
, O
counselors O
, O
and O
other O
senior O
advisors O
if O
any O
such O
advisor O
is O
forced O
, O
either O
during O
or O
after O
the O
Presidency O
, O
in O
front O
of O
an O
Unselect B-ORG
Committee I-ORG
or O
other O
entity O
, O
and O
be O
forced O
to O
reveal O
those O
privileged O
, O
confidential O
discussions O
? O
” O
the O
spokesman O
said O
. O
“ O
President B-PER
Trump I-PER
will O
not O
be O
deterred O
by O
witch O
hunts O
or O
kangaroo O
courts O
from O
continuing O
to O
defend O
and O
fight O
for O
America O
, O
our O
Constitution O
, O
and O
the O
Truth O
. O
” O
The O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
declined O
to O
comment O
. O
Mark B-PER
Meadows I-PER
could O
be O
a O
key O
witness O
In O
recent O
months O
, O
the O
former O
President O
has O
ignored O
advice O
from O
some O
of O
his O
advisers O
to O
avoid O
speaking O
with O
former O
and O
current O
aides O
who O
have O
become O
entangled O
in O
the O
House B-ORG
select I-ORG
committee’s O
probe O
into O
January O
6 O
and O
may O
become O
part O
of O
the O
criminal O
investigation O
, O
people O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Trump B-PER
has O
specifically O
been O
counseled O
to O
cut O
contact O
with O
his O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
chief O
of O
staff O
Mark B-PER
Meadows I-PER
, O
whose O
actions O
leading O
up O
to O
and O
on O
the O
day O
of O
the O
US B-ORG
Capitol O
insurrection O
have O
been O
deeply O
scrutinized O
by O
the O
House B-ORG
panel O
, O
the O
people O
said O
. O
Two O
of O
Meadows’ O
former O
top O
aides O
, O
Cassidy B-PER
Hutchinson I-PER
and O
Alyssa B-PER
Farah I-PER
Griffin I-PER
, O
also O
have O
been O
highly O
critical O
of O
Trump B-PER
, O
with O
Hutchinson B-PER
testifying O
about O
damaging O
details O
about O
Trump’s B-PER
actions O
on O
January O
6 O
during O
her O
public O
testimony O
before O
the O
House B-ORG
panel O
in O
June O
. O
Hutchinson B-PER
is O
cooperating O
in O
the O
DOJ B-ORG
probe O
as O
well O
. O
Some O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
attorneys O
believe O
Meadows B-PER
could O
also O
be O
in O
investigators’ O
crosshairs O
and O
are O
concerned O
he O
could O
become O
a O
fact O
witness O
if O
he O
is O
pushed O
to O
cooperate O
in O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
probe O
, O
according O
to O
two O
people O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
. O
In O
response O
, O
Meadows’ O
attorney O
George B-PER
Terwilliger I-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
on O
Thursday O
: O
“ O
All O
of O
that O
is O
idle O
and O
uninformed O
speculation O
, O
apparently O
by O
people O
that O
know O
little O
but O
talk O
a O
lot O
. O
” O
Former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
attorney O
Ty B-PER
Cobb I-PER
said O
Meadows B-PER
is O
“ O
perfectly O
positioned O
to O
be O
the O
John B-PER
Dean I-PER
of O
this O
mess O
, O
” O
referring O
to O
the O
former O
Richard B-PER
Nixon I-PER
aide O
who O
offered O
crucial O
public O
testimony O
during O
the O
Watergate O
hearings O
. O
“ O
The O
reason O
[ O
Meadows B-PER
] O
is O
valuable O
is O
also O
the O
reason O
he O
is O
in O
jeopardy O
: O
He O
was O
basically O
at O
Trump’s B-PER
right O
hand O
throughout O
all O
these O
exercises O
and O
participated O
in O
key O
meetings O
and O
phone O
calls O
, O
” O
Cobb O
said O
. O
Yet O
, O
according O
to O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
relationship O
, O
Trump B-PER
and O
Meadows B-PER
have O
spoken O
a O
number O
of O
times O
. O
Another O
source O
close O
to O
Trump B-PER
described O
their O
relationship O
as O
“ O
not O
the O
same O
as O
it O
once O
was O
” O
while O
they O
served O
in O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
, O
but O
insisted O
they O
still O
maintained O
a O
relationship O
, O
even O
as O
Trump B-PER
has O
complained O
about O
Meadows B-PER
in O
his O
recent O
conversations O
with O
other O
allies O
. O
Meadows B-PER
has O
been O
known O
to O
attend O
fundraisers O
and O
events O
at O
the O
former O
President O
’s O
Mar-a-Lago O
estate O
in O
Palm B-LOC
Beach I-LOC
, O
Florida B-LOC
, O
where O
he O
also O
helped O
organize O
a O
donor O
retreat O
last O
April O
for O
the O
Conservative B-MISC
Partnership I-MISC
Institute I-MISC
, O
a O
group O
he O
runs O
with O
former O
Republican O
Sen. O
Jim B-PER
DeMint I-PER
. O
The O
securing O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
endorsement O
for O
US B-ORG
Senate O
candidate O
Ted B-PER
Budd I-PER
“ O
was O
the O
last O
time O
Meadows B-PER
was O
really O
around O
regularly O
. O
Since O
then O
, O
he O
’s O
never O
been O
a O
big O
part O
of O
the O
political O
operation O
or O
[ O
Trump’s B-PER
] O
thought O
process O
, O
” O
said O
a O
second O
person O
close O
to O
Trump B-PER
. O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Pamela B-PER
Brown I-PER
and O
Zachary B-PER
Cohen I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Southwest B-ORG
flight O
attendant O
injures O
back O
after O
hard O
landing O
, O
NTSB B-ORG
says O
| O
CNN B-ORG
Travel O
! O
[fwp_0] O
( O
https://ads.stickyadstv.com/user-matching?id=185&_fw_gdpr=0&_fw_gdpr_consent= O
) O
![fwp_1] O
( O
https://ads.stickyadstv.com/auto-user-sync O
) O
![Quantcast] O
(//pixel.quantserve.com/pixel/p-D1yc5zQgjmqr5.gif) O

What O
the O
Kansas B-LOC
abortion O
surprise O
does O
(and O
does O
not) O
mean O
for O
November O
| O
Flipboard O
! O
[]( O
https://sb.scorecardresearch.com/p?c1=2&c2=20080817&cv=2.0&cj=1 O
) O
Flipboard B-ORG
Home O
Landscape O
version O
of O
the O
Flipboard O
logo O
Newsletters* O
Search O
* O
Sign O
up O
* O
Log O
in O
* O
Home O
* O
#News O
* O
What O
the O
Kansas B-LOC
abortion O
surprise O
does O
(and O
does O
not) O
mean O
for O
November O

Here O
is O
Editor’s O
Note: O
Peter B-PER
Bergen I-PER
is O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
national O
security O
analyst, O
a O
vice O
president O
at O
New B-ORG
America I-ORG
and O
a O
professor O
of O
practice O
at O
Arizona B-ORG
State I-ORG
University I-ORG
. O
Bergen’s O
new O
paperback O
is O
“The O
Rise O
and O
fall O
of O
Osama B-PER
bin I-PER
Laden.” O
from O
which O
this O
article O
is, O
in O
part, O
adapted. O
The O
views O
expressed O
in O
this O
commentary O
are O
his O
own. O
View O
more O
opinion O
on O
CNN B-ORG
. O
In O
1961, O
after O
a O
CIA-backed O
invasion O
of O
Cuba B-LOC
failed O
spectacularly, O
President O
John B-PER
F. I-PER
Kennedy I-PER
said O
of O
the O
Bay B-LOC
of I-LOC
Pigs I-LOC
fiasco, O
“Victory O
has O
100 O
fathers O
and O
defeat O
is O
an O
orphan.” O
Last O
week, O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
took O
a O
victory O
lap O
when O
he O
announced O
that O
the O
US O
had O
tracked O
down O
and O
killed O
its O
most O
wanted O
terrorist, O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
leader O
Ayman B-PER
al-Zawahiri I-PER
, O
who O
was O
living O
in O
a O
house O
in O
Kabul B-LOC
, O
Afghanistan B-LOC
. O
Don’t O
expect O
a O
similar O
celebration O
on O
August O
30, O
the O
first O
anniversary O
of O
the O
US O
troop O
withdrawal O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
which O
ended O
the O
longest O
war O
in O
American O
history. O
Any O
realistic O
assessment O
of O
that O
action O
shows O
that O
it O
will O
long O
be O
seen O
as O
a O
defeat O
rather O
than O
a O
victory O
– O
and O
it’s O
likely O
no O
one O
will O
own O
up O
to O
the O
responsibility O
for O
the O
decision. O
The O
US O
launched O
a O
war O
against O
Afghanistan B-LOC
in O
2001 O
after O
the O
Taliban O
regime O
harbored O
Osama B-PER
bin I-PER
Laden, I-PER
giving O
him O
the O
ability O
to O
plot O
and O
carry O
out O
the O
9/11 O
terrorist O
attacks O
which O
killed O
almost O
3,000 O
Americans. O
As O
US O
and O
NATO B-ORG
troops O
battled O
Taliban O
and O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
forces, O
the O
new O
US-backed O
government O
in O
Kabul B-LOC
also O
presided O
over O
two O
decades O
of O
progress O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
. O
To O
be O
sure, O
Afghanistan B-LOC
wasn’t O
Norway, O
but O
it O
was O
becoming O
a O
somewhat O
functional, O
democratizing O
Central O
Asian O
state O
that O
saw O
striking O
progress O
in O
reducing O
child O
mortality O
and O
increasing O
life O
expectancy, O
one O
that O
provided O
jobs O
for O
women O
and O
education O
for O
millions O
of O
girls; O
it O
nurtured O
scores O
of O
independent O
media O
outlets, O
and O
held O
regular, O
if O
flawed, O
presidential O
elections. O
All O
of O
that O
changed O
when O
the O
US O
began O
withdrawing O
and O
the O
Taliban O
took O
over O
the O
entire O
country O
on O
August O
15, O
2021 O
. O
Women’s O
rights O
evaporated. O
They O
have O
no O
right O
to O
work, O
except O
in O
a O
narrow O
set O
of O
female-related O
jobs O
such O
as O
cleaning O
women’s O
toilets O
in O
Kabul B-LOC
; O
when O
they O
travel O
distances O
of O
more O
than O
45 O
miles O
they O
must O
be O
accompanied O
by O
a O
male O
relative, O
and O
the O
Taliban O
have O
ordered O
women O
to O
stay O
at O
home O
and O
to O
cover O
themselves O
completely O
should O
they O
ever O
venture O
out. O
Their O
male O
relatives O
will O
be O
punished O
by O
the O
Taliban O
if O
women O
don’t O
follow O
these O
directives. O
Girls O
do O
not O
have O
the O
right O
to O
be O
educated O
after O
the O
age O
of O
12. O
On O
the O
Taliban’s O
management O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
one O
data O
point O
suffices O
to O
underline O
the O
group’s O
gross O
incompetence: O
Around O
half O
of O
the O
Afghan O
population O
are O
today O
“facing O
acute O
hunger,” O
according O
to O
the O
UN B-ORG
. O
On O
the O
Taliban’s O
respect O
for O
other O
ethnic O
Afghan O
groups: O
There O
is O
no O
evidence O
that O
the O
Taliban O
are O
creating O
an O
“inclusive” O
government O
as O
their O
leaders O
claimed O
they O
would. O
Pashtuns O
make O
up O
almost O
all O
the O
leadership O
of O
the O
Taliban O
, O
while O
other O
ethnic O
groups O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
such O
as O
the O
Hazaras, O
Tajiks O
and O
Uzbeks O
are O
almost O
entirely O
excluded O
from O
leadership O
roles. O
On O
their O
respect O
for O
democracy: O
The O
Taliban O
, O
conveniently, O
don’t O
believe O
in O
elections. O
Instead, O
they O
are O
a O
theocracy; O
their O
leader O
is O
known O
as O
the O
“Commander O
of O
the O
Faithful,” O
a O
title O
that O
claims O
he O
is O
the O
leader O
of O
all O
Muslims. O
In O
the O
past O
year O
under O
Taliban O
rule, O
40% O
of O
Afghanistan’s O
independent O
media O
outlets O
have O
closed. O
On O
the O
Taliban’s O
alliance O
with O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
: O
Well, O
last O
week’s O
news O
made O
clear O
the O
relationship O
is O
thriving. O
The O
fact O
that O
the O
leader O
of O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
, O
Ayman B-PER
al-Zawahiri I-PER
was O
living O
in O
downtown O
Kabul B-LOC
for O
months O
– O
with O
what O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
describes O
as O
the O
awareness O
of O
some O
Taliban O
officials O
– O
speaks O
for O
itself. O
Zawahiri O
was O
killed O
late O
last O
month O
in O
a O
US O
drone O
strike O
. O
After O
the O
news O
broke O
that O
Zawahiri O
had O
been O
hiding O
in O
Kabul B-LOC
, O
Lisa B-PER
Curtis I-PER
, O
the O
top O
official O
at O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
for O
Afghanistan B-LOC
during O
the O
Trump B-PER
administration I-PER
, O
tweeted O
“#Taliban O
basically O
asserting O
Doha O
agreement O
allows O
them O
to O
shelter O
#AlQaeda. O
Proves O
it O
was O
the O
worst O
agreement O
in O
US O
history. O
Not O
worth O
the O
paper O
on O
which O
it’s O
written.” O
This O
was O
a O
particularly O
damning O
assessment O
coming O
from O
a O
senior O
American O
official O
who O
was O
working O
on O
Afghanistan B-LOC
while O
the O
Doha O
agreement O
between O
the O
US O
and O
the O
Taliban O
was O
being O
negotiated. O
One O
of O
the O
most O
powerful O
men O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
today O
is O
the O
acting O
Minister O
of O
Interior, O
Sirajuddin B-PER
Haqqani I-PER
, O
who O
has O
ties O
to O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
, O
according O
to O
a O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
report O
that O
said O
he O
is O
“assessed O
to O
be O
a O
member O
of O
the O
wider O
Al-Qaida B-MISC
leadership, O
but O
not O
of O
the O
Al-Qaida B-MISC
core O
leadership.” O
A O
February O
2020 O
opinion O
piece O
in O
The B-ORG
New I-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
with O
Haqqani’s O
byline O
blandly O
identified O
him O
only O
as O
“the O
deputy O
leader O
of O
the O
Taliban.” O
What O
the O
Times I-ORG
didn’t O
tell O
its O
readers O
is O
that O
Haqqani O
was O
also O
on O
the O
FBI’s O
most O
wanted O
list O
and O
that O
his O
men O
had O
kidnapped O
a O
reporter O
for O
… O
The B-ORG
New I-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
. O
This O
op-ed O
featured O
ludicrous O
lies O
including, O
“We O
together O
will O
find O
a O
way O
to O
build O
an O
Islamic O
system O
in O
which O
all O
Afghans O
have O
equal O
rights, O
where O
the O
rights O
of O
women O
that O
are O
granted O
by O
Islam O
– O
from O
the O
right O
to O
education O
to O
the O
right O
to O
work O
– O
are O
protected O
” O
and O
“reports O
about O
foreign O
[terrorist] O
groups O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
are O
politically O
motivated O
exaggerations O
by O
the O
warmongering O
players O
on O
all O
sides O
of O
the O
war.” O
How O
it O
happened O
The O
US O
pullout O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
a O
year O
ago O
was O
orchestrated O
by O
a O
successive O
series O
of O
decisions O
by O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
, O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
and O
the O
chief O
US O
negotiator O
with O
the O
Taliban O
, O
Ambassador O
Zalmay B-PER
Khalilzad I-PER
. O
None O
of O
these O
men O
are O
ever O
likely O
to O
fully O
acknowledge O
their O
paternity O
of O
the O
debacle O
that O
unfolded O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
which O
followed O
the O
worst O
diplomatic O
agreement O
in O
US O
history O
that O
enabled O
the O
Taliban O
to O
win O
at O
the O
negotiating O
table O
in O
Doha B-LOC
, O
Qatar B-LOC
what O
they O
could O
never O
win O
on O
the O
battlefield. O
Khalilzad O
has O
defended O
the O
deal O
saying, O
“The O
negotiation O
was O
a O
result O
of–based O
on O
the O
judgment O
that O
we O
weren’t O
winning O
the O
war O
and O
therefore O
time O
was O
not O
on O
our O
side O
and O
better O
to O
make O
a O
deal O
sooner O
than O
later.” O
By O
the O
end O
of O
the O
Trump B-PER
administration I-PER
, O
the O
fledgling O
Afghan O
state O
was O
supported O
by O
only O
some O
2,500 O
US O
troops, O
a O
tiny O
fraction O
of O
the O
more O
than O
two O
million O
men O
and O
women O
in O
the O
active-duty O
US O
military, O
reserves, O
and O
National O
Guard O
units. O
Assisted O
by O
9,000 O
allied, O
mostly O
NATO B-ORG
troops O
and O
18,000 O
contractors O
this O
small O
US O
force O
was O
enough O
to O
enable O
the O
Afghan O
military O
to O
fend O
off O
the O
Taliban O
, O
which O
was O
never O
able O
to O
capture O
and O
hold O
any O
of O
Afghanistan’s O
34 O
provincial O
capitals O
before O
Biden B-PER
announced O
the O
total O
American O
withdrawal O
in O
April O
2021 O
. O
Why O
Biden B-PER
went O
through O
with O
the O
withdrawal O
plan O
that O
he O
had O
inherited O
from O
Trump B-PER
is O
still O
something O
of O
a O
puzzle O
since O
there O
was O
no O
large, O
vocal O
constituency O
in O
the O
Democratic O
Party O
that O
was O
demanding O
a O
total O
US O
pullout O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
and O
Biden’s O
top O
military O
advisers O
had O
clearly O
warned O
him O
of O
the O
risks O
of O
doing O
so. O
In O
public O
testimony O
before O
the O
US O
Senate O
Armed O
Services O
Committee, O
US O
Chairman O
of O
the O
Joint O
Chiefs O
of O
Staff O
Gen. O
Mark B-PER
Milley I-PER
and O
US O
CENTCOM O
commander O
Gen. O
Kenneth B-PER
McKenzie I-PER
, O
said O
they O
had O
advised O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
that O
unless O
the O
US O
kept O
around O
2,500 O
troops O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
the O
Afghan O
military O
would O
collapse. O
Collapse O
it O
did. O
The O
“Taliban O
2.0” O
delusion O
The O
publication O
of O
Haqqani’s O
op-ed O
in O
The B-ORG
New I-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
was O
emblematic O
of O
the O
wishful O
thinking O
about O
the O
Taliban O
in O
the O
US O
that O
had O
persisted O
for O
years. O
In O
this O
view O
the O
Taliban O
were O
just O
a O
bunch O
of O
misunderstood O
backwoodsmen O
who O
would O
eventually O
do O
what O
was O
only O
sensible: O
break O
with O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
and O
abandon O
much O
of O
their O
misogynistic O
ideology O
as O
a O
quid O
pro O
quo O
for O
their O
recognition O
on O
the O
world O
stage. O
This O
was O
a O
classic O
case O
of O
mirror O
imaging; O
the O
belief O
that O
the O
Taliban O
would O
do O
the O
rational O
things O
some O
gullible O
Americans O
expected O
them O
to O
do, O
as O
opposed O
to O
implementing O
the O
quasi-mediaeval O
ideology O
that O
has O
been O
at O
the O
core O
of O
their O
armed O
movement O
since O
they O
first O
emerged O
almost O
three O
decades O
ago. O
It O
was O
like O
imagining O
the O
Khmer O
Rouge O
would O
“mature” O
once O
they O
had O
taken O
power O
in O
Cambodia O
. O
A O
key O
proponent O
of O
the O
view O
that O
the O
Taliban O
would O
change O
if O
the O
right O
carrots O
were O
dangled O
in O
front O
of O
them O
was O
Barnett B-PER
Rubin I-PER
of O
NYU O
, O
an O
expert O
on O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
who O
claimed O
in O
a O
paper O
that O
he O
published O
with O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
Institute O
of O
Peace O
in O
March O
2021 O
that O
the O
US O
had O
“underestimated O
the O
leverage O
that O
the O
Taliban O
’s O
quest O
for O
sanctions O
relief, O
recognition O
and O
international O
assistance O
provides.” O
Turns O
out O
that O
it O
was O
Rubin O
who O
overestimated O
how O
much O
the O
Taliban O
cared O
about O
sanctions O
relief O
and O
international O
assistance, O
while O
he O
had O
also O
vastly O
underestimated O
their O
desire O
to O
banish O
women O
from O
jobs O
and O
education O
and O
maintain O
their O
warm O
relations O
with O
their O
old O
buddies O
in O
al B-MISC
Qaeda I-MISC
. O
This O
shouldn’t O
have O
come O
as O
much O
of O
a O
surprise, O
since O
that O
was O
exactly O
how O
the O
Taliban O
had O
ruled O
the O
last O
time O
that O
they O
were O
in O
power O
in O
the O
years O
before O
9/11 O
. O
The O
Taliban O
hadn’t O
fought O
the O
US O
and O
Afghan O
militaries O
for O
two O
decades O
only O
to O
install O
a O
quasi-democracy O
when O
they O
came O
to O
power O
for O
the O
second O
time O
. O
The O
“moderate” O
Taliban O
2.0 O
that O
was O
supposedly O
emerging O
in O
recent O
years O
was O
a O
profound O
delusion O
that O
gripped O
US O
policymakers O
. O
A O
month O
after O
Biden B-PER
had O
announced O
the O
impending O
withdrawal O
of O
all O
US O
troops O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
the O
US O
negotiator O
with O
the O
Taliban O
, O
Khalilzad O
, O
testified O
to O
the O
US O
House O
Foreign O
Affairs O
Committee O
on O
May O
16, O
2021 O
, O
that O
those O
who O
thought O
the O
Taliban O
would O
quickly O
take O
over O
the O
country O
as O
the O
US O
pulled O
out O
were O
“mistaken.” O
Khalilzad O
also O
asserted O
that O
the O
Taliban O
would O
opt O
for O
a O
political O
settlement O
over O
a O
military O
victory, O
testifying, O
“They O
say O
they O
seek O
normalcy O
in O
terms O
of O
relations O
— O
acceptability, O
removal O
from O
sanctions, O
not O
to O
remain O
a O
pariah.” O
Just O
months O
later O
the O
distinctive O
white O
flags O
of O
the O
Taliban O
were O
fluttering O
over O
the O
capital, O
Kabul B-LOC
, O
and O
the O
Taliban O
began O
implementing O
their O
theocratic O
state O
. O
In O
a O
symbolic O
move O
the O
Taliban’s O
feared O
religious O
police O
soon O
commandeered O
what O
had O
formerly O
been O
the O
ministry O
for O
women’s O
affairs O
. O
Obviously, O
that O
ministry O
would O
no O
longer O
be O
needed, O
but O
the O
“Vice O
and O
Virtue O
” O
police O
would O
have O
to O
be O
properly O
accommodated O
. O
The O
United B-ORG
Nations I-ORG
released O
a O
report O
in O
May O
in O
which O
it O
observed O
that O
an O
astonishing O
41 O
members O
of O
the O
Taliban O
serving O
in O
the O
cabinet O
or O
other O
senior-level O
government O
positions O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
are O
on O
UN O
sanctions O
lists O
. O
Taliban O
2.0 O
was O
a O
mirage, O
and O
the O
Taliban O
today O
is O
Taliban O
1.0 O
with O
one O
major O
difference; O
they O
are O
far O
better O
armed O
than O
the O
Taliban O
that O
ruled O
over O
most O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
from O
1996 O
to O
2001 O
. O
Now O
they O
ride O
into O
battle O
with O
American O
armored O
vehicles O
and O
M-16 O
rifles O
that O
were O
left O
behind O
as O
the O
US O
military O
rushed O
for O
the O
exits O
last O
summer O
. O
The O
Taliban O
today O
also O
face O
a O
far O
weaker O
opposition O
movement O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
than O
was O
the O
case O
for O
the O
pre-9/11 O
Taliban O
. O
Signaling O
weakness O
to O
Russia B-LOC
and O
China B-LOC
When O
Biden B-PER
spoke O
to O
the O
American O
people O
on O
Aug. O
31, O
2021 O
, O
as O
the O
last O
US O
soldiers O
departed O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
he O
framed O
the O
withdrawal O
as O
a O
way O
of O
positioning O
the O
US O
to O
compete O
better O
against O
great-power O
rivals, O
saying, O
“We’re O
engaged O
in O
a O
serious O
competition O
with O
China B-LOC
. O
We’re O
dealing O
with O
the O
challenges O
on O
multiple O
fronts O
with O
Russia B-LOC
… O
And O
there’s O
nothing O
China B-LOC
or O
Russia B-LOC
would O
rather O
have, O
would O
want O
more O
in O
this O
competition O
than O
the O
United O
States O
to O
be O
bogged O
down O
another O
decade O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
.” O
This O
was O
an O
absurd O
rationale: O
For O
years O
both O
China B-LOC
and O
Russia B-LOC
had O
hoped O
to O
push O
American O
forces O
out O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
because O
the O
country O
borders O
both O
China B-LOC
and O
the O
republics O
of O
the O
former O
Soviet O
Union O
. O
Russia B-LOC
had O
covertly O
supported O
the O
Taliban O
, O
according O
to O
the O
US O
military, O
while O
the O
Chinese O
had O
drawn O
closer O
to O
the O
Taliban O
in O
recent O
years O
. O
As O
they O
pulled O
out O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
the O
Americans O
abandoned O
the O
vast O
Bagram B-LOC
Air O
Base O
which O
could O
house O
up O
to O
10,000 O
troops; O
a O
more O
ideal O
site O
from O
which O
to O
engage O
in O
competition O
with O
either O
China B-LOC
or O
Russia B-LOC
is O
hard O
to O
imagine O
. O
You O
could O
practically O
hear O
the O
high O
fives O
in O
the O
Kremlin O
as O
the O
US O
ignominiously O
retreated O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
which O
seemed O
to O
herald O
an O
era O
of O
the O
US O
pulling O
back O
from O
the O
world O
. O
It O
hardly O
seems O
accidental O
that O
three O
months O
later O
Russian O
President O
Vladimir B-PER
Putin I-PER
moved O
an O
army O
to O
the O
border O
with O
Ukraine B-LOC
as O
a O
prelude O
to O
his O
invasion O
of O
the O
country O
. O
A O
predictable O
fiasco O
In O
June O
2021 O
, O
I O
wrote O
for O
CNN B-ORG
, O
“We O
could O
see O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
a O
remix O
of O
the O
disastrous O
US O
pullout O
from O
Saigon B-LOC
in O
1975 O
and O
the O
summer O
of O
2014 O
in O
Iraq O
when O
ISIS O
took O
over O
much O
of O
the O
country O
following O
the O
US O
pullout O
from O
the O
country O
.” O
That O
prediction, O
unfortunately, O
proved O
to O
be O
accurate; O
the O
American O
pullout O
from O
Saigon B-LOC
looked O
like O
a O
dignified O
retreat O
compared O
to O
the O
scenes O
of O
thousands O
of O
desperate O
Afghans O
trying O
to O
get O
on O
planes O
leaving O
Kabul B-LOC
airport O
last O
August O
. O
Some O
Afghans O
were O
so O
desperate O
to O
leave O
that O
they O
clung O
to O
the O
fuselage O
of O
a O
plane O
that O
was O
taking O
off O
– O
and O
two O
plunged O
to O
their O
deaths O
. O
On O
Aug. O
25, O
2021 O
, O
13 O
US O
soldiers O
and O
at O
least O
170 O
Afghans O
were O
killed O
at O
the O
airport O
by O
a O
suicide O
bomber O
dispatched O
by O
the O
Afghan O
branch O
of O
ISIS O
. O
And O
the O
Taliban O
took O
over O
the O
entire O
country O
even O
before O
the O
last O
US O
soldiers O
had O
left O
Afghanistan B-LOC
. O
Compounding O
Biden’s O
disastrous O
policy O
decision O
to O
completely O
pull O
out O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
was O
the O
botched O
handling O
of O
the O
withdrawal O
. O
According O
to O
a O
report O
about O
that O
withdrawal O
released O
in O
February O
by O
Republican O
senators O
sitting O
on O
the O
Senate O
Foreign O
Relations O
Committee, O
the O
first O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
meeting O
to O
discuss O
evacuating O
Americans O
and O
Afghans O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
took O
place O
on O
Aug. O
14, O
only O
one O
day O
before O
the O
Taliban O
seized O
Kabul B-LOC
and O
five O
months O
after O
Biden B-PER
had O
first O
publicly O
announced O
the O
total O
US O
withdrawal O
from O
the O
country O
. O
Biden B-PER
patted O
himself O
on O
the O
back O
that O
the O
US O
military O
subsequently O
extracted O
124,000 O
Afghans O
from O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
calling O
the O
operation O
an O
“extraordinary O
success,” O
which O
was O
like O
an O
arsonist O
praising O
himself O
for O
helping O
to O
try O
to O
put O
out O
a O
fire O
that O
he O
had O
started O
. O
But O
even O
accepting O
the O
most O
self-congratulatory O
view O
of O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
’s O
handling O
of O
the O
withdrawal O
, O
the O
vast O
majority O
of O
the O
Afghans O
who O
had O
worked O
with O
the O
US O
were O
abandoned O
. O
The O
Association O
of O
Wartime O
Allies O
, O
an O
advocacy O
group O
for O
Afghans O
who O
had O
worked O
for O
the O
US O
, O
estimated O
in O
March O
that O
only O
about O
3% O
of O
the O
81,000 O
Afghans O
who O
had O
worked O
for O
the O
US O
government O
and O
had O
applied O
for O
special O
visas O
had O
made O
it O
out O
of O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
leaving O
78,000 O
behind O
. O
Four O
months O
after O
the O
Taliban O
took O
over O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
convened O
the O
“Summit O
for O
Democracy” O
in O
Washington O
consisting O
of O
the O
world’s O
democracies. O
Five O
months O
earlier O
Afghanistan B-LOC
would O
have O
warranted O
an O
invitation O
to O
this O
summit, O
but O
Biden B-PER
had O
enabled O
the O
Taliban O
to O
take O
over O
the O
country O
, O
which O
ended O
almost O
every O
shred O
of O
a O
liberal O
democracy O
that O
had O
once O
existed O
there O
. O
Following O
the O
Afghan O
debacle O
, O
Biden’s O
favorable O
ratings O
dropped O
to O
the O
lowest O
level O
of O
his O
presidency O
to O
that O
point O
to O
46% O
. O
They O
have O
never O
recovered O
. O
The O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
now O
faces O
a O
policy O
dilemma O
of O
its O
own O
making O
. O
Since O
so O
many O
millions O
of O
Afghans O
are O
on O
the O
brink O
of O
starvation, O
Biden B-PER
officials O
cannot O
completely O
turn O
their O
backs O
on O
Afghanistan B-LOC
. O
And O
yet, O
it’s O
hard O
to O
help O
Afghans O
without O
propping O
up O
the O
Taliban O
in O
some O
manner O
. O
The O
Biden B-PER
administration I-PER
has O
tried O
to O
ensure O
that O
all O
US O
aid O
to O
Afghanistan B-LOC
is O
administered O
in O
a O
way O
that O
it O
doesn’t O
end O
up O
in O
the O
hands O
of O
the O
Taliban O
, O
but O
realistically O
any O
help O
that O
the O
US O
sends O
to O
Afghanistan B-LOC
tends O
to O
help O
the O
Taliban O
remain O
in O
power O
. O
This O
is O
surely O
one O
of O
the O
most O
spectacular O
own O
goals O
the O
US O
has O
ever O
scored O
. O

articleBody O
House O
Speaker O
Nancy B-PER
Pelosi I-PER
said O
Thursday O
that O
a O
congressional O
delegation O
traveled O
to O
South B-LOC
Korea I-LOC
and O
visited O
the O
Korean B-LOC
Demilitarized O
Zone O
that O
divides O
North B-LOC
and O
South I-LOC
Korea I-LOC
. O
“It O
was O
a O
privilege O
to O
engage O
with O
American B-MISC
heroes O
in O
uniform O
on O
the O
ground O
in O
Korea B-LOC
, O
led O
by O
General B-PER
Paul B-PER
LaCamera I-PER
, O
Commander O
, O
U.S. B-ORG
Forces I-ORG
Korea I-LOC
. O
During O
visits O
to O
the O
Demilitarized O
Zone/Joint O
Security O
Area O
( O
DMZ/JSA O
) O
and O
Osan B-LOC
Air O
Base O
, O
we O
conveyed O
the O
gratitude O
of O
the O
Congress O
and O
the O
Country O
for O
the O
patriotic O
service O
of O
our O
Servicemembers O
, O
who O
stand O
as O
sentinels O
of O
Democracy O
on O
the O
Korean B-LOC
peninsula O
, O
” O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
in O
the O
statement O
. O
The O
DMZ O
is O
a O
160-mile-long O
no-man’s O
land O
about O
30 O
miles O
north O
of O
Seoul B-LOC
that O
was O
established O
in O
the O
1953 O
Korean B-LOC
War O
Armistice O
Agreement O
. O
It O
is O
often O
described O
as O
the O
world’s O
most O
heavily O
armed O
border O
. O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
the O
delegation O
also O
visited O
Seoul B-LOC
and O
praised O
what O
she O
described O
as O
“ O
a O
strong O
bond O
” O
between O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
South B-LOC
Korea I-LOC
. O
“ O
The O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
and O
South B-LOC
Korea I-LOC
share O
a O
strong O
bond O
formed O
for O
security O
and O
forged O
by O
decades O
of O
warm O
friendship O
. O
Our O
Congressional O
delegation O
traveled O
to O
Seoul B-LOC
to O
reaffirm O
our O
treasured O
ties O
and O
our O
shared O
commitment O
to O
advancing O
security O
and O
stability O
, O
economic O
growth O
and O
democratic O
governance O
, O
” O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
. O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
the O
delegation O
was O
“ O
honored O
to O
be O
hosted O
” O
at O
a O
parliamentary O
meeting O
“ O
where O
we O
reaffirmed O
our O
commitment O
to O
the O
U.S.-Korea B-ORG
alliance O
” O
and O
“ O
was O
pleased O
to O
engage O
in O
a O
phone O
meeting O
with O
Korea’s B-LOC
President O
Yoon B-PER
Suk-yeol I-PER
. O
Providing O
a O
readout O
of O
the O
call O
, O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
, O
“ O
we O
thanked O
the O
President O
for O
Korea’s B-LOC
hospitality O
of O
28,000 O
U.S. B-ORG
Servicemembers I-ORG
and O
their O
families O
. O
Each O
Member O
engaged O
in O
conversation O
with O
the O
President O
, O
highlighting O
areas O
of O
continued O
cooperation O
to O
advance O
a O
free O
and O
open O
Indo-Pacific O
. O
The O
announcement O
comes O
after O
Pelosi B-PER
recently O
visited O
Taiwan B-LOC
amid O
threats O
of O
Chinese B-MISC
retaliation O
. O
Pelosi B-PER
landed O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
on O
Tuesday O
, O
marking O
a O
significant O
show O
of O
support O
for O
Taiwan B-LOC
. O
Pelosi B-PER
’s O
stop O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
is O
the O
first O
time O
that O
a O
US B-ORG
House O
speaker O
has O
visited O
Taiwan B-LOC
in O
25 O
years O
. O
Her O
trip O
comes O
at O
a O
low O
point O
in O
US B-ORG
-China B-LOC
relations O
and O
despite O
warnings O
from O
the O
Biden B-PER
administration O
against O
a O
stop O
in O
Taiwan B-LOC
. O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Jeremy B-PER
Herb I-PER
and O
Sol B-PER
Han I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

أهم O
مجموعة O
ل O
ملك O
الروك O
آن O
رول O
.. O
مجوهرات O
إلفيس B-PER
بريسلي I-PER
المفقودة O
منذ O
عقود O
تتجه O
إلى O
المزاد O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

A B-MISC
version O
of O
this O
story O
first O
appeared O
in O
CNN B-ORG
Business’ I-ORG
Before B-MISC
the O
Bell O
newsletter O
. O
Not O
a O
subscriber O
? O
You O
can O
sign O
up O
right O
here O
. O
After O
the O
Federal B-ORG
Reserve I-ORG
’s O
July O
meeting O
, O
investors O
quickly O
reached O
a O
consensus O
: O
The O
central O
bank O
was O
turning O
slightly O
dovish O
. O
After O
embarking O
on O
an O
aggressive O
rate-hike O
spree O
this O
year O
in O
a O
bid O
to O
fight O
inflation O
, O
the O
Fed B-ORG
indicated O
it O
could O
downgrade O
the O
size O
of O
its O
hikes O
moving O
forward O
. O
“We’ve O
been O
front-end O
loading O
these O
very O
large O
rate O
increases O
, O
and O
now O
we’re O
getting O
closer O
to O
where O
we O
need O
to O
be O
,” O
Fed B-ORG
Chair O
Jerome B-PER
Powell I-PER
told O
reporters O
. O
Of O
course O
, O
Powell I-PER
said O
, O
another O
“unusually O
large O
” O
increase O
could O
be O
on O
the O
table O
too O
. O
But O
Wall B-MISC
Street I-MISC
looked O
past O
that O
. O
What O
came O
next O
: O
Investors O
cheered O
Powell I-PER
’s O
apparent O
pivot O
. O
The O
S&P B-MISC
500 I-MISC
rallied O
, O
notching O
its O
best O
month O
since O
November O
2020 O
, O
and O
financial O
conditions O
eased O
. O
Mortgage O
rates O
fell O
below O
5% O
for O
the O
first O
time O
since O
mid-April O
. O
Now O
, O
Fed B-ORG
officials O
are O
trying O
to O
set O
the O
record O
straight O
. O
Not O
wanting O
markets O
to O
change O
course O
too O
sharply O
, O
reversing O
the O
effects O
of O
their O
hard O
work O
thus O
far O
, O
they’ve O
been O
talking O
tough O
again O
. O
“[We’re O
] O
nowhere O
near O
almost O
done O
,” O
San B-LOC
Francisco I-LOC
Fed B-ORG
President O
Mary B-PER
Daly I-PER
said O
in O
an O
interview O
on O
LinkedIn B-ORG
last O
week O
. O
Loretta B-PER
Mester I-PER
, O
head O
of O
the O
Federal B-ORG
Reserve I-ORG
Bank I-ORG
of O
Cleveland I-LOC
, O
told O
the O
Washington B-LOC
Post I-LOC
that O
it O
“would O
be O
inappropriate O
… O
to O
cry O
victory O
too O
early O
” O
and O
risk O
letting O
high O
inflation O
become O
entrenched O
. O
“We O
need O
to O
see O
really O
compelling O
evidence O
that O
inflation O
is O
moving O
down O
, O
and O
my O
view O
is O
that O
we O
haven’t O
seen O
that O
yet O
,” O
Mester I-PER
said O
. O
As O
the O
Fed B-ORG
tries O
to O
bring O
demand O
back O
down O
so O
it O
stops O
running O
up O
against O
limited O
supply O
— O
pushing O
up O
prices O
— O
it’s O
closely O
watching O
the O
labor O
market O
, O
which O
has O
remained O
strong O
. O
While O
job O
openings O
fell O
in O
June O
, O
the O
US B-LOC
economy O
continues O
to O
add O
jobs O
at O
a O
healthy O
pace O
. O
A O
blowout O
July O
report O
released O
Friday O
showed O
a O
gain O
of O
528,000 O
positions O
last O
month O
. O
The O
unemployment O
rate O
ticked O
down O
to O
3.5% O
. O
The O
news O
poured O
cold O
water O
on O
the O
theory O
that O
the O
Fed B-ORG
would O
change O
its O
approach O
dramatically O
any O
time O
soon O
. O
The O
central O
bank O
actually O
wants O
to O
see O
some O
weakening O
in O
the O
job O
market O
. O
When O
there O
are O
too O
many O
open O
roles O
, O
wages O
rise O
quickly O
, O
which O
can O
make O
economy-wide O
inflation O
even O
worse O
. O
“This O
isn’t O
the O
news O
the O
Fed B-ORG
wanted O
to O
hear O
, O
and O
this O
will O
likely O
cause O
it O
to O
push O
rates O
higher O
, O
faster O
,” O
said O
Robert B-PER
Frick I-PER
, O
corporate O
economist O
with O
Navy B-ORG
Federal I-ORG
Credit I-ORG
Union I-ORG
. O
Investors O
have O
come O
back O
around O
: O
The O
stock O
market O
on O
Friday O
predicted O
a O
66% O
chance O
of O
a O
three-quarter-point O
rate O
hike O
in O
September O
, O
according O
to O
CME B-ORG
’s O
FedWatch I-ORG
tool O
. O
On O
Thursday O
, O
the O
market O
had O
priced O
in O
just O
a O
34% O
chance O
of O
a O
hike O
that O
high O
. O
Coming O
up O
: O
The O
next O
big O
data O
release O
is O
the O
Consumer B-MISC
Price I-MISC
Index I-MISC
, O
which O
is O
used O
to O
track O
US B-LOC
inflation O
. O
Economists O
polled O
by O
Refinitiv O
expect O
to O
learn O
that O
prices O
rose O
8.7% O
in O
the O
year O
to O
July O
, O
down O
slightly O
from O
June O
. O
But O
excluding O
volatile O
food O
and O
energy O
prices O
, O
inflation O
may O
have O
inched O
higher O
. O
America’s O
strong O
dollar O
is O
hurting O
everyone O
else O
The O
US B-LOC
dollar O
has O
been O
on O
a O
tear O
this O
year O
. O
That O
’s O
good O
news O
for O
American B-MISC
tourists O
gallivanting O
around O
Europe B-LOC
, O
but O
bad O
news O
for O
pretty O
much O
every O
other O
country O
in O
the O
world O
. O
The O
latest O
: O
The O
greenback O
is O
up O
more O
than O
10% O
in O
2022 O
compared O
to O
other O
top O
currencies O
— O
near O
its O
highest O
level O
in O
two O
decades O
— O
as O
investors O
worried O
about O
a O
global O
recession O
have O
rushed O
to O
scoop O
up O
dollars O
, O
which O
are O
considered O
a O
safe O
haven O
in O
turbulent O
times O
. O
Adding O
to O
the O
dollar’s O
appeal O
is O
the O
Federal B-ORG
Reserve I-ORG
’s O
aggressive O
campaign O
of O
interest O
rate O
hikes O
to O
tackle O
decades-high O
inflation O
. O
That O
’s O
made O
American B-MISC
investments O
more O
attractive O
, O
since O
they O
now O
offer O
higher O
returns O
. O
US B-LOC
travelers O
may O
be O
rejoicing O
that O
a O
night O
out O
in O
Rome B-LOC
that O
once O
cost O
$100 O
now O
costs O
about O
$80 O
, O
but O
it’s O
a O
more O
complicated O
picture O
for O
multinational O
companies O
and O
foreign O
governments O
. O
See O
here O
: O
About O
half O
of O
international O
trade O
is O
invoiced O
in O
dollars O
, O
running O
up O
bills O
for O
manufacturers O
and O
small O
businesses O
that O
rely O
on O
imported O
goods O
. O
Governments O
that O
need O
to O
repay O
their O
debts O
in O
dollars O
could O
also O
run O
into O
trouble O
, O
especially O
if O
reserves O
run O
low O
. O
The O
dollar’s O
gain O
is O
already O
hurting O
some O
vulnerable O
economies O
. O
A O
shortage O
of O
dollars O
in O
Sri B-LOC
Lanka I-LOC
contributed O
to O
the O
worst O
economic O
crisis O
in O
the O
country O
’s O
history O
, O
ultimately O
forcing O
the O
country O
’s O
president O
out O
of O
office O
last O
month O
. O
Pakistan B-LOC
’s O
rupee O
plunged O
to O
a O
record O
low O
against O
the O
dollar O
in O
late O
July O
, O
pushing O
it O
to O
the O
brink O
of O
default O
. O
And O
Egypt B-LOC
— O
battered O
by O
rising O
food O
prices O
— O
is O
dealing O
with O
a O
depleted O
store O
of O
dollars O
and O
an O
exodus O
of O
foreign O
investment O
. O
All O
three O
countries O
have O
had O
to O
turn O
to O
the O
International B-ORG
Monetary I-ORG
Fund I-ORG
for O
help O
. O
“It’s O
been O
a O
challenging O
environment O
,” O
William B-PER
Jackson I-PER
, O
chief O
emerging O
markets O
economist O
at O
Capital B-ORG
Economics I-ORG
, O
told O
me O
. O
Up O
next O
Monday O
: O
Earnings O
from O
BioNTech B-ORG
, O
Palantir B-ORG
, O
Tyson B-ORG
Foods I-ORG
, O
Novavax B-ORG
, O
News B-ORG
Corp I-ORG
. O
, O
Take-Two B-ORG
Interactive I-ORG
and O
SmileDirectClub B-ORG
Tuesday O
: O
Earnings O
from O
Dine B-ORG
Brands I-ORG
, O
Hyatt B-ORG
, O
Spirit B-ORG
Airlines I-ORG
, O
Coinbase B-ORG
, O
Roblox B-ORG
and O
Wynn B-ORG
Resorts I-ORG
Wednesday O
: O
US B-LOC
Consumer B-MISC
Price I-MISC
Index I-MISC
for O
July O
; O
Earnings O
from O
Disney B-ORG
, O
Fox B-ORG
Corporation I-ORG
, O
Wendy’s B-ORG
and O
Bumble B-ORG
Thursday O
: O
OPEC B-ORG
monthly O
report O
; O
US B-LOC
Producer B-MISC
Price I-MISC
Index I-MISC
for O
July O
; O
Earnings O
from O
Utz B-ORG
Brands I-ORG
, O
Warby B-ORG
Parker I-ORG
and O
Wheels B-ORG
Up I-ORG
Friday O
: O
UK B-LOC
GDP I-LOC
; O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Michigan I-ORG
consumer O
sentiment O
survey O
. O

China B-LOC
’s O
military O
exercises O
around O
Taiwan B-LOC
this O
week O
aim O
to O
send O
a O
pointed O
message O
to O
governments O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
, O
Tokyo B-LOC
and O
Washington B-LOC
that O
Beijing B-LOC
alone O
calls O
the O
shots O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
, O
analysts O
say O
. O
Experts O
also O
suggest O
the O
announcement O
of O
the O
drills O
shortly O
after O
US B-ORG
House O
Speaker O
Nancy B-PER
Pelosi I-PER
landed O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
on O
Tuesday O
was O
no O
snap O
reaction O
to O
her O
controversial O
visit O
– O
rather O
, O
the O
exercises O
are O
part O
of O
a O
relentless O
, O
years-long O
plan O
to O
bring O
Taiwan B-LOC
under O
Beijing’s O
control O
. O
Pelosi B-PER
’s O
trip O
to O
the O
island O
– O
a O
democracy O
of O
24 O
million O
that O
the O
Chinese B-ORG
Communist I-ORG
Party I-ORG
regards O
as O
its O
territory O
despite O
having O
never O
controlled O
it O
– O
has O
merely O
thrust O
the O
issue O
of O
Taiwan B-LOC
into O
news O
headlines O
, O
analysts O
said O
. O
“They O
do O
this O
every O
year O
,” O
Thompson B-PER
said O
of O
the O
Chinese O
exercises O
. O
“The O
difference O
this O
year O
is O
that O
we’re O
paying O
attention O
.” O
Reaction O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
, O
Tokyo B-LOC
and O
Washington B-LOC
The O
government O
in O
Taipei B-LOC
is O
certainly O
on O
alert O
, O
announcing O
Friday O
that O
multiple O
Chinese B-ORG
warships O
and O
jets O
had O
crossed O
the O
median O
line O
– O
the O
midway O
point O
between O
the O
mainland O
and O
Taiwan B-LOC
that O
Beijing B-LOC
says O
it O
does O
not O
recognize O
but O
usually O
respects O
. O
After O
China B-LOC
sent O
ballistic O
missiles O
over O
the O
island O
Thursday O
, O
Taiwan B-LOC
’s O
President O
Tsai B-PER
Ing-wen I-PER
vowed O
to O
“firmly O
defend O
our O
sovereignty O
and O
national O
security O
, O
and O
stick O
to O
the O
line O
of O
defense O
of O
democracy O
and O
freedom O
.” O
Those O
missiles O
got O
the O
attention O
of O
Japan B-LOC
, O
too O
. O
Five O
of O
them O
landed O
inside O
Japan B-LOC
’s O
Exclusive O
Economic O
Zone O
, O
an O
area O
of O
the O
ocean O
where O
a O
country O
enjoys O
special O
rights O
to O
resources O
like O
fishing O
and O
mining O
under O
the O
seabed O
. O
Japanese O
Prime O
Minister O
Fumio B-PER
Kishida I-PER
said O
the O
Chinese O
drills O
were O
“a O
serious O
issue O
concerning O
the O
security O
of O
our O
country O
and O
its O
people O
.” O
He O
called O
for O
an O
immediate O
halt O
to O
them O
and O
said O
Japan B-LOC
would O
work O
with O
its O
closest O
ally O
, O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
, O
“to O
maintain O
stability O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
.” O
Meanwhile O
, O
US B-ORG
Secretary O
of O
State O
Antony B-PER
Blinken I-PER
, O
speaking O
at O
the O
ASEAN-US B-ORG
Ministerial O
meeting O
in O
Cambodia B-LOC
, O
said O
, O
“I O
hope O
very O
much O
that O
Beijing B-LOC
will O
not O
manufacture O
a O
crisis O
or O
seek O
a O
pretense O
to O
increase O
its O
aggressive O
military O
action O
.” O
But O
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
the O
official O
line O
was O
that O
Beijing B-LOC
’s O
actions O
came O
as O
no O
surprise O
. O
“We O
anticipated O
that O
China B-LOC
might O
take O
steps O
like O
this O
– O
in O
fact O
, O
I O
described O
them O
for O
you O
in O
quite O
some O
detail O
just O
the O
other O
day O
,” O
John B-PER
Kirby I-PER
, O
a O
spokesperson O
for O
the O
US B-ORG
National I-ORG
Security I-ORG
Council I-ORG
, O
told O
reporters O
at O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
on O
Thursday O
. O
“We O
also O
expect O
that O
these O
actions O
will O
continue O
and O
that O
the O
Chinese O
will O
continue O
to O
react O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
.” O
Isolating O
Taiwan B-LOC
Visiting O
with O
Kishida B-PER
on O
Friday O
, O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
Beijing B-LOC
was O
trying O
to O
“isolate O
” O
Taiwan B-LOC
. O
China B-LOC
’s O
exercises O
were O
designed O
to O
practice O
doing O
exactly O
that O
, O
said O
Carl B-PER
Schuster I-PER
, O
a O
former O
director O
of O
operations O
at O
the O
US B-ORG
Pacific I-ORG
Command I-ORG
’s O
Joint I-ORG
Intelligence I-ORG
Center I-ORG
in O
Hawaii B-LOC
. O
“China O
(is O
showing O
) O
it O
can O
bombard O
Taiwan B-LOC
with O
missiles O
and O
isolate O
it O
from O
outside O
support O
and O
affect O
air O
and O
maritime O
trade O
through O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
and O
around O
Taiwan B-LOC
,” O
Schuster B-PER
said O
. O
That’s O
long O
been O
Beijing’s O
plan O
, O
and O
this O
week O
’s O
exercises O
are O
just O
the O
manifestation O
of O
at O
least O
months O
of O
planning O
and O
years O
of O
policy O
, O
the O
experts O
said O
. O
“An O
exercise O
of O
this O
size O
, O
scope O
and O
complexity O
cannot O
be O
planned O
and O
the O
forces O
prepared O
in O
two O
weeks O
,” O
Schuster B-PER
said O
, O
referring O
to O
the O
period O
following O
rumors O
of O
Pelosi B-PER
’s O
trip O
to O
the O
island O
. O
He O
said O
the O
outlines O
of O
the O
Chinese O
military O
exercises O
were O
likely O
decided O
a O
year O
ago O
and O
most O
of O
the O
actions O
set O
by O
April O
. O
Parts O
of O
the O
drills O
, O
like O
the O
multiple O
ballistic O
missile O
launches O
, O
could O
have O
been O
added O
in O
the O
past O
few O
weeks O
as O
the O
logistics O
of O
those O
are O
not O
as O
complicated O
as O
say O
, O
setting O
up O
a O
naval O
blockade O
, O
which O
Beijing B-LOC
said O
was O
one O
of O
its O
practice O
points O
for O
the O
exercises O
. O
Drills O
‘to O
intimidate O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
Japan B-LOC
’ O
Schuster B-PER
also O
noted O
that O
the O
exercises O
are O
larger O
than O
those O
China B-LOC
has O
organized O
in O
previous O
years O
. O
“This O
expanded O
exercise O
activity O
has O
a O
third O
purpose O
– O
to O
intimidate O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
Japan B-LOC
– O
both O
of O
which O
have O
indicated O
their O
support O
for O
Taiwan B-LOC
,” O
Schuster B-PER
said O
. O
“If O
you O
look O
at O
the O
rhetoric O
from O
January O
to O
April O
, O
(Chinese O
President O
Xi B-PER
Jinping I-PER
) O
and O
company O
were O
ramping O
up O
criticism O
of O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
Japan B-LOC
, O
the O
latter O
over O
recent O
statements O
of O
support O
for O
Taiwan B-LOC
and O
its O
increased O
defense O
spending O
.” O
Japan B-LOC
’s O
2022 O
Defense O
White O
Paper O
, O
an O
annual O
look O
at O
its O
security O
policy O
published O
in O
late O
July O
, O
called O
out O
Beijing B-LOC
in O
no O
uncertain O
terms O
. O
“China B-LOC
continues O
to O
unilaterally O
change O
or O
attempt O
to O
change O
the O
status O
quo O
by O
coercion O
in O
the O
East B-LOC
China I-LOC
Sea I-LOC
and O
South B-LOC
China I-LOC
Sea I-LOC
,” O
it O
says O
. O
“Furthermore O
, O
China B-LOC
has O
made O
clear O
that O
it O
would O
not O
hesitate O
to O
unify O
Taiwan B-LOC
by O
force O
, O
further O
increasing O
tensions O
in O
the O
region O
.” O
In O
a O
virtual O
speech O
to O
a O
Taiwanese O
think O
tank O
last O
December O
, O
the O
late O
former O
Japanese O
Prime O
Minister O
Shinzo B-PER
Abe I-PER
said O
an O
armed O
invasion O
of O
Taiwan B-LOC
would O
be O
a O
grave O
danger O
to O
Japan B-LOC
. O
“People O
in O
Beijing B-LOC
, O
President O
Xi B-PER
Jinping I-PER
in O
particular O
, O
should O
never O
have O
a O
misunderstanding O
in O
recognizing O
this O
,” O
Abe B-PER
said O
. O
Perhaps O
Beijing B-LOC
was O
n’t O
listening O
or O
just O
doesn’t O
care O
. O
The O
exercises O
– O
particularly O
the O
launching O
of O
missiles O
that O
landed O
in O
Japan B-LOC
’s O
EEZ O
– O
show O
that O
, O
experts O
said O
. O
“They O
have O
validated O
Shinzo B-PER
Abe I-PER
’s O
concerns O
that O
at O
a O
Taiwan O
emergency O
is O
a O
Japan B-LOC
emergency O
and O
an O
emergency O
for O
the O
US-Japan B-ORG
alliance O
,” O
Thompson B-PER
, O
of O
the O
National B-ORG
University I-ORG
of I-ORG
Singapore I-ORG
, O
said O
. O
And O
that O
emergency O
can O
be O
expected O
to O
continue O
. O
Bringing O
Taiwan B-LOC
into O
Beijing’s O
control O
is O
a O
bedrock O
of O
Chinese O
policy O
. O
On O
Friday O
, O
China B-LOC
continued O
its O
exercises O
and O
military O
intimidation O
unabated O
. O
Taiwanese O
Premier O
Su B-PER
Tseng-chang I-PER
acknowledged O
the O
exercises O
were O
having O
the O
effect O
Beijing O
desires O
, O
showing O
how O
it O
can O
control O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
. O
“The O
evil O
neighbor O
next O
door O
flexed O
its O
muscles O
on O
our O
doorstep O
and O
arbitrarily O
sabotaged O
one O
of O
the O
busiest O
waterways O
in O
the O
world O
with O
military O
exercises O
,” O
he O
said O
. O

At B-LOC
least O
28 O
people O
have O
died O
in O
last O
week’s O
flooding O
in O
Kentucky B-LOC
as O
rescuers O
continue O
to O
search O
for O
missing O
people O
and O
the O
region O
braces O
for O
yet O
more O
rain O
. O
“Our O
confirmed O
count O
of O
Kentuckians O
we’ve O
lost O
has O
now O
reached O
28 O
, O
and O
we O
expect O
that O
there O
will O
be O
more O
, O
and O
that O
that O
number O
will O
grow O
,” O
Gov. B-PER
Andy I-PER
Beshear I-PER
said O
Sunday O
. O
The O
devastating O
flooding O
Thursday O
was O
unprecedented O
, O
officials O
said O
, O
inundating O
houses O
and O
sweeping O
some O
from O
their O
foundations O
. O
“This O
is O
one O
of O
the O
most O
devastating O
deadly O
floods O
that O
we O
have O
seen O
in O
our O
history O
,” O
Beshear I-PER
said O
on O
NBC’s O
“Meet O
The O
Press O
” O
Sunday O
. O
“It O
wiped O
out O
areas O
where O
people O
didn’t O
have O
that O
much O
to O
begin O
with O
.” O
“We’re O
going O
to O
be O
finding O
bodies O
for O
weeks O
, O
many O
of O
them O
swept O
hundreds O
of O
yards O
, O
maybe O
a O
quarter-mile O
plus O
from O
where O
they O
were O
last O
,” O
the O
governor O
said O
. O
Now O
, O
more O
rainfall O
is O
in O
the O
forecast O
that O
threatens O
some O
areas O
hardest-hit O
by O
the O
deadly O
flooding O
. O
“The O
forecast O
is O
concerning O
, O
and O
we’re O
watching O
it O
very O
closely O
, O
obviously O
. O
We O
also O
are O
sending O
out O
warnings O
and O
making O
sure O
everyone O
knows O
,” O
said O
Col. B-PER
Jeremy I-PER
Slinker I-PER
, O
the O
Kentucky B-LOC
emergency O
management O
director O
. O
“We’re O
preparing O
for O
it O
and O
making O
sure O
all O
the O
residents O
there O
are O
prepared O
for O
it O
because O
we O
just O
don’t O
want O
to O
lose O
anyone O
else O
or O
have O
any O
more O
tragedy O
,” O
he O
told O
CNN’s O
Pamela B-PER
Brown I-PER
Saturday O
. O
A O
flood O
watch O
is O
in O
effect O
through O
at O
least O
Monday O
morning O
for O
parts O
of O
southern O
and O
eastern O
Kentucky B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
the O
National B-ORG
Weather I-ORG
Service I-ORG
, O
and O
there O
is O
a O
Level O
3 O
of O
4 O
moderate O
risk O
for O
excessive O
rainfall O
Sunday O
across O
southeastern O
Kentucky B-LOC
, O
per O
the O
Weather B-ORG
Prediction I-ORG
Center I-ORG
, O
escalating O
the O
concern O
of O
additional O
flooding O
. O
“The O
threat O
of O
flash O
flooding O
will O
be O
gradually O
increasing O
as O
showers O
and O
thunderstorms O
with O
very O
heavy O
rainfall O
rates O
develop O
and O
expand O
in O
coverage O
today O
,” O
the O
center O
said O
, O
deeming O
the O
atmospheric O
conditions O
in O
the O
area O
as O
“tropical O
in O
nature O
,” O
meaning O
it O
is O
warm O
, O
moist O
and O
can O
support O
an O
incredible O
amount O
of O
water O
. O
Widespread O
rainfall O
totals O
of O
1 O
to O
3 O
inches O
are O
forecast O
over O
the O
next O
24 O
to O
48 O
hours O
, O
but O
as O
much O
as O
4 O
or O
5 O
inches O
is O
possible O
in O
localized O
areas O
. O
As O
little O
as O
1 O
to O
2 O
inches O
can O
revive O
flooding O
concerns O
, O
particularly O
in O
areas O
already O
inundated O
with O
heavy O
rain O
where O
the O
soil O
is O
saturated O
. O
Some O
areas O
remain O
unreachable O
, O
governor O
says O
Officials O
believe O
thousands O
have O
been O
affected O
, O
and O
efforts O
to O
rebuild O
some O
areas O
may O
take O
years O
, O
the O
governor O
told O
CNN O
Saturday O
. O
The O
state’s O
estimated O
losses O
are O
potentially O
in O
the O
“tens O
if O
not O
the O
hundreds O
of O
millions O
of O
dollars O
.” O
In O
Perry B-LOC
County I-LOC
alone O
, O
approximately O
50 O
bridges O
were O
washed O
away O
, O
County O
Judge O
Executive O
Scott B-PER
Alexander I-PER
said O
at O
a O
news O
conference O
Sunday O
morning O
, O
calling O
it O
“the O
biggest O
event O
that O
I O
’m O
aware O
of O
that O
Perry B-LOC
County I-LOC
has O
ever O
faced O
.” O
State O
officials O
Sunday O
were O
working O
to O
open O
Buckhorn B-LOC
State I-LOC
Park I-LOC
to O
house O
a O
number O
of O
those O
who O
lost O
their O
homes O
, O
the O
governor O
said O
at O
the O
news O
conference O
, O
adding O
he O
hoped O
to O
announce O
the O
state O
park O
could O
be O
used O
as O
a O
shelter O
soon O
. O
“We O
recognize O
that O
the O
hotels O
and O
motels O
here O
are O
full O
, O
the O
shelters O
are O
full O
, O
that O
people O
are O
sleeping O
in O
their O
cars O
and O
trucks O
and O
we O
don’t O
need O
that O
,” O
Beshear I-PER
said O
. O
After O
the O
rain O
, O
excessive O
heat O
is O
expected O
to O
build O
over O
the O
region O
Tuesday O
as O
many O
people O
are O
currently O
struggling O
with O
no O
access O
to O
clean O
drinking O
water O
, O
power O
outages O
and O
cell O
service O
still O
out O
in O
some O
counties O
Sunday O
. O
“We O
have O
multiple O
Kentucky B-LOC
State I-LOC
Police I-LOC
posts O
that O
are O
taking O
calls O
from O
loved O
ones O
that O
can’t O
connect O
with O
those O
that O
they O
are O
worried O
about O
,” O
the O
governor O
told O
NBC O
Sunday O
. O
“But O
it’s O
going O
to O
take O
some O
time O
to O
get O
a O
firm O
grasp O
on O
that O
. O
We O
still O
can’t O
get O
into O
some O
areas O
to O
check O
on O
people O
.” O
More O
than O
13,000 O
homes O
and O
businesses O
in O
the O
region O
were O
in O
the O
dark O
early O
Sunday O
afternoon O
, O
according O
to O
PowerOutage.us O
; O
three O
drinking O
water O
systems O
were O
totally O
out O
of O
operation O
Saturday O
, O
the O
governor O
said O
, O
leaving O
residents O
without O
access O
to O
water O
, O
or O
only O
access O
to O
water O
which O
needed O
to O
be O
boiled O
before O
it O
could O
be O
safely O
consumed O
. O
The O
federal O
government O
sent O
tractor O
trailers O
of O
bottled O
water O
to O
the O
region O
, O
and O
more O
financial O
assistance O
is O
on O
the O
way O
. O
The O
flooding O
– O
as O
with O
other O
recent O
weather O
disasters O
– O
was O
further O
amplified O
by O
the O
climate O
crisis O
: O
As O
global O
temperatures O
climb O
as O
a O
result O
of O
human-caused O
fossil O
fuel O
emissions O
, O
the O
atmosphere O
is O
able O
to O
hold O
more O
water O
, O
making O
water O
vapor O
more O
abundantly O
available O
to O
fall O
as O
rain O
. O
Scientists O
are O
increasingly O
confident O
in O
the O
role O
the O
climate O
crisis O
plays O
in O
extreme O
weather O
, O
and O
have O
warned O
such O
events O
will O
become O
more O
intense O
and O
more O
dangerous O
with O
every O
fraction O
of O
a O
degree O
of O
warming O
. O
Officials O
have O
moved O
swiftly O
to O
approve O
financial O
assistance O
, O
given O
the O
scores O
of O
people O
in O
need O
of O
relief O
after O
losing O
everything O
. O
The O
federal O
government O
greenlighted O
funding O
for O
people O
in O
five O
counties O
“at O
a O
pace O
that O
we’ve O
never O
seen O
before O
,” O
Kentucky B-LOC
Lt. B-PER
Gov. I-PER
Jacqueline I-PER
Coleman I-PER
told O
CNN’s O
Pamela B-PER
Brown I-PER
Saturday O
. O
“Residents O
will O
actually O
receive O
direct O
payments O
, O
which O
is O
some O
really O
good O
news O
in O
what O
will O
be O
a O
very O
long O
tunnel O
to O
see O
the O
light O
,” O
Coleman I-PER
said O
. O
Coleman I-PER
did O
not O
provide O
an O
exact O
date O
on O
when O
those O
payments O
are O
expected O
to O
reach O
residents O
, O
though O
she O
said O
they O
will O
be O
dispersed O
as O
soon O
as O
the O
state O
receives O
the O
money O
. O
Nearly O
$700,000 O
has O
been O
raised O
for O
relief O
efforts O
, O
Beshear I-PER
said O
Saturday O
, O
noting O
funeral O
expenses O
for O
those O
killed O
in O
the O
flooding O
will O
be O
paid O
for O
. O
Additionally O
, O
the O
state O
is O
prioritizing O
placing O
generators O
at O
the O
shelters O
for O
flood O
survivors O
as O
temperatures O
are O
expected O
to O
soar O
Tuesday O
following O
the O
rain O
. O
‘Hero’ O
rescued O
family O
from O
flooded O
home O
Among O
the O
tales O
of O
heroism O
emerging O
from O
the O
disaster O
is O
an O
unidentified O
man O
who O
drifted O
through O
fast-moving O
water O
to O
get O
a O
98-year-old O
grandmother O
, O
her O
grandson O
and O
another O
family O
member O
out O
of O
their O
home O
as O
it O
was O
nearly O
swallowed O
by O
the O
flooding O
Thursday O
. O
Randy B-PER
Polly I-PER
, O
who O
witnessed O
the O
rescue O
in O
Whitesburg B-LOC
, O
Kentucky B-LOC
, O
and O
recorded O
parts O
of O
it O
on O
his O
cellphone O
, O
told O
CNN O
he O
got O
stuck O
a O
distance O
away O
from O
the O
home O
on O
his O
way O
to O
get O
gas O
Thursday O
morning O
. O
Polly I-PER
said O
he O
heard O
people O
yelling O
across O
the O
flooded O
road O
, O
“Get O
me O
help O
, O
get O
help O
.” O
He O
called O
911 O
, O
but O
first O
responders O
were O
overwhelmed O
and O
unresponsive O
to O
his O
calls O
. O
Around O
9 O
a.m. O
, O
he O
saw O
a O
man O
he O
described O
as O
a O
hero O
drift O
over O
to O
the O
house O
and O
start O
banging O
on O
the O
door O
and O
window O
. O
The O
man O
eventually O
helped O
get O
three O
people O
out O
of O
the O
home O
and O
guided O
them O
through O
rushing O
water O
, O
the O
videos O
show O
. O
The O
rescue O
took O
about O
30 O
minutes O
, O
Polly I-PER
said O
. O
Missy B-PER
Crovetti I-PER
, O
who O
lives O
in O
Green B-LOC
Oaks I-LOC
, O
Illinois B-LOC
, O
told O
CNN O
the O
people O
rescued O
in O
the O
video O
are O
her O
grandmother O
Mae B-PER
Amburgey I-PER
, O
uncle O
Larry B-PER
Amburgey I-PER
and O
brother O
Gregory B-PER
Amburgey I-PER
. O
They O
are O
safe O
and O
doing O
well O
, O
she O
said O
. O
Crovetti I-PER
said O
she O
does O
not O
know O
the O
name O
of O
the O
man O
who O
rescued O
her O
family O
. O
Polly I-PER
also O
said O
he O
does O
not O
know O
the O
man’s O
name O
. O
CNN O
’s O
Chris B-PER
Boyett I-PER
, O
Sharif B-PER
Paget I-PER
, O
Gene B-PER
Norman I-PER
, O
Derek B-PER
Van I-PER
Dam I-PER
, O
Haley B-PER
Brink I-PER
, O
Jalen B-PER
Beckford I-PER
, O
Angela B-PER
Fritz I-PER
, O
Chuck B-PER
Johnston I-PER
and O
Raja B-PER
Razek I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

articleBody O
Former O
Secretary O
of O
State O
Mike B-PER
Pompeo I-PER
met O
with O
the O
House O
January O
6 O
committee O
on O
Tuesday O
, O
according O
to O
panel O
member O
Rep. O
Zoe B-PER
Lofgren I-PER
. O
The O
California B-LOC
Democrat O
confirmed O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
earlier O
reporting O
that O
Pompeo B-PER
would O
be O
deposed O
by O
the O
committee O
, O
according O
to O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
. O
CNN B-ORG
has O
previously O
reported O
on O
Pompeo B-PER
’s O
negotiations O
with O
the O
committee O
about O
his O
testimony O
. O
The O
panel O
has O
shown O
an O
increased O
interest O
in O
members O
of O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
’s O
Cabinet O
, O
particularly O
regarding O
conversations O
among O
Cabinet O
members O
about O
invoking O
the O
25th O
Amendment O
after O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
and O
the O
committee O
’s O
focus O
in O
the O
Pompeo B-PER
interview O
was O
expected O
to O
be O
on O
the O
25th O
Amendment O
, O
the O
source O
said O
. O
A O
portion O
of O
the O
25th O
Amendment O
, O
which O
addresses O
presidential O
succession O
, O
allows O
a O
vice O
president O
and O
a O
majority O
of O
the O
Cabinet O
to O
vote O
to O
remove O
a O
president O
from O
office O
due O
to O
his O
inability O
to O
“discharge O
the O
powers O
and O
duties O
of O
his O
office O
.” O
Pompeo B-PER
served O
as O
CIA B-ORG
director O
for O
the O
first O
year O
of O
Trump B-PER
’s O
presidency O
, O
and O
led O
the O
State B-ORG
Department O
for O
Trump B-PER
’s O
final O
three O
years O
, O
where O
he O
was O
a O
stalwart O
Trump B-PER
ally O
and O
defender O
. O
Lofgren B-PER
refused O
to O
comment O
on O
the O
particulars O
of O
Pompeo B-PER
’s O
testimony O
in O
an O
interview O
on O
Tuesday O
, O
but O
told O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Wolf B-PER
Blitzer I-PER
on O
“The O
Situation O
Room O
” O
that O
“he O
came O
in O
willingly O
, O
and O
he O
did O
answer O
questions O
for O
quite O
some O
time O
.” O
When O
asked O
if O
the O
committee O
learned O
any O
new O
information O
from O
Pompeo B-PER
’s O
testimony O
, O
Lofgren B-PER
said O
, O
“I O
think O
we O
fill O
in O
a O
few O
pieces O
here O
and O
there O
each O
time O
we O
interview O
someone O
. O
Obviously O
, O
we O
’ve O
had O
testimony O
from O
others O
about O
what O
he O
said O
and O
did O
. O
And O
so O
, O
it O
’s O
just O
a O
matter O
of O
filling O
out O
the O
entire O
picture O
, O
especially O
on O
that O
day O
and O
the O
events O
subsequent O
to O
that O
day O
, O
where O
the O
Cabinet O
secretaries O
had O
concerns O
about O
the O
President O
.” O
The O
New B-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
was O
first O
to O
report O
Pompeo B-PER
’s O
expected O
appearance O
Tuesday O
. O
As O
discussions O
surrounding O
the O
25th O
Amendment O
come O
into O
focus O
, O
the O
committee O
had O
also O
hoped O
to O
hear O
from O
Doug B-PER
Mastriano I-PER
, O
the O
Trump-endorsed O
Republican O
nominee O
for O
governor O
in O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
, O
on O
Tuesday O
. O
However O
, O
Mastriano B-PER
’s O
virtual O
appearance O
Tuesday O
only O
lasted O
about O
15 O
minutes O
and O
“he O
didn’t O
answer O
a O
single O
question O
,” O
according O
to O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
. O
Mastriano B-PER
’s O
attorney O
cut O
off O
the O
virtual O
appearance O
soon O
after O
it O
began O
, O
the O
source O
said O
. O
His O
lawyer O
, O
Tim B-PER
Parlatore I-PER
, O
took O
issue O
with O
several O
procedural O
matters O
related O
to O
the O
deposition O
, O
and O
raised O
questions O
about O
the O
legality O
of O
the O
subpoena O
that O
Mastriano B-PER
received O
from O
the O
panel O
, O
the O
source O
added O
. O
Mastriano B-PER
, O
a O
key O
figure O
in O
Trump B-PER
’s O
effort O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 O
election O
, O
led O
a O
faux O
legislative O
“hearing O
” O
at O
a O
hotel O
in O
Gettysburg B-LOC
a O
few O
weeks O
after O
the O
2020 O
election O
, O
where O
Trump B-PER
and O
his O
then-lawyer O
Rudy B-PER
Giuliani I-PER
made O
false O
claims O
about O
election O
fraud O
. O
He O
also O
chartered O
buses O
to O
bring O
Trump B-PER
supporters O
to O
Washington B-LOC
on O
January O
6 O
, O
and O
he O
was O
briefly O
in O
charge O
of O
the O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
state O
Senate O
’s O
partisan O
“audit O
” O
of O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O
Last O
week O
, O
Mastriano B-PER
threatened O
to O
walk O
out O
of O
a O
scheduled O
deposition O
before O
the O
House B-ORG
select O
committee O
unless O
the O
panel O
agreed O
to O
his O
conditions O
, O
potentially O
setting O
up O
a O
court O
fight O
over O
his O
testimony O
. O
In O
a O
letter O
to O
the O
committee O
, O
his O
attorney O
, O
Parlatore B-PER
had O
said O
he O
would O
pull O
out O
of O
the O
scheduled O
deposition O
unless O
they O
could O
agree O
to O
certain O
accommodations O
. O
Parlatore B-PER
asked O
that O
he O
be O
able O
to O
videotape O
the O
deposition O
, O
keep O
the O
footage O
in O
escrow O
, O
and O
release O
portions O
of O
it O
later O
on O
, O
if O
the O
committee O
publicly O
releases O
clips O
that O
he O
believes O
would O
require O
additional O
context O
. O
Several O
Trump B-PER
Cabinet O
officials O
have O
already O
met O
with O
the O
committee O
, O
including O
Acting O
Defense O
Secretary O
Chris B-PER
Miller I-PER
, O
Acting O
Attorney O
General O
Jeffrey B-PER
Rosen I-PER
and O
Labor O
Secretary O
Eugene B-PER
Scalia I-PER
. O
Attorney O
General O
William B-PER
Barr I-PER
also O
met O
with O
the O
committee O
, O
but O
he O
had O
left O
the O
administration O
prior O
to O
the O
January O
6 O
insurrection O
. O
This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
background O
information O
. O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Marshall B-PER
Cohen I-PER
, O
Zachary B-PER
Cohen I-PER
, O
Chandelis B-PER
Duster I-PER
, O
Sara B-PER
Murray I-PER
and O
Shawna B-PER
Mizelle I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Since O
Beyoncé B-MISC
is O
editing O
lyrics O
, O
Monica B-PER
Lewinsky I-PER
has O
a O
request O
. O
Lewinsky B-PER
, O
the O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
intern O
who O
became O
embroiled O
in O
a O
sex O
scandal O
with O
then O
President O
Bill B-PER
Clinton I-PER
in O
the O
1990s O
, O
tweeted O
the O
news O
of O
Beyoncé B-MISC
removing O
an O
abelist O
slur O
from O
the O
song O
“Heated” B-MISC
on O
her O
new O
album O
“Renaissance” B-MISC
with O
a O
suggestion O
. O
“uhmm O
, O
while O
we O
’ O
re O
at O
it O
… O
#Partition B-MISC
,” O
Lewinsky B-PER
tweeted O
. O
“Partition” B-MISC
is O
a O
track O
from O
the O
singer’s O
2013 O
self-titled O
fifth O
studio O
album O
. O
In O
the O
song O
, O
Beyoncé B-MISC
sings O
that O
a O
man O
“Monica B-PER
Lewinsky’d I-PER
all O
on O
my O
gown O
.” O
The O
affair O
between O
Clinton B-PER
and O
then-22-year-old O
Lewinsky B-PER
ultimately O
led O
to O
Clinton’s B-PER
impeachment O
in O
1998 O
and O
much O
discussion O
about O
consent O
and O
abuse O
of O
power O
. O
In O
2021 O
, O
Lewinsky B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
Jake B-PER
Tapper I-PER
that O
“what O
’s O
really O
important O
to O
remember O
in O
today O
’s O
world O
is O
that O
we O
never O
should O
have O
even O
gotten O
to O
a O
place O
where O
consent O
was O
a O
question O
.” O
“So O
it O
was O
wholly O
inappropriate O
as O
the O
most O
powerful O
man O
, O
my O
boss O
, O
49 O
years O
old O
,” O
she O
said O
. O
“I O
was O
22 O
, O
literally O
just O
out O
of O
college O
. O
And O
I O
think O
that O
the O
power O
differentials O
there O
are O
something O
that O
I O
couldn’t O
ever O
fathom O
consequences O
at O
22 O
that O
I O
understand O
obviously O
so O
differently O
at O
48 O
.” O
This O
week O
, O
Beyoncé B-MISC
agreed O
to O
scrub O
from O
her O
track O
“Heated” B-MISC
a O
reference O
which O
is O
considered O
demeaning O
to O
people O
with O
spastic O
cerebral O
palsy O
after O
there O
was O
a O
public O
outcry O
. O
CNN B-ORG
has O
reached O
out O
to O
reps O
for O
the O
singer O
for O
comment O
about O
Lewinsky’s B-PER
request O
. O

New B-LOC
York I-LOC
City I-LOC
Police B-ORG
detectives O
shot O
and O
injured O
four O
men O
they O
say O
opened O
fire O
at O
a O
party O
in O
Queens B-LOC
, O
where O
around O
75 O
to O
100 O
people O
were O
gathered O
. O
Around O
11.35 O
p.m. O
Friday O
, O
plainclothes O
police O
from O
the O
violent O
crime O
squad O
were O
keeping O
watch O
on O
the O
party O
, O
being O
held O
in O
a O
residential O
area O
, O
from O
an O
unmarked O
car O
, O
NYPD O
Chief O
of O
Patrol O
Jeff B-PER
Maddrey I-PER
said O
during O
an O
overnight O
press O
conference O
. O
Police O
“ O
believed O
that O
there O
was O
a O
potential O
to O
be O
violence O
involving O
some O
of O
the O
local O
street O
crews O
, O
” O
Maddrey B-PER
said O
. O
The O
detectives O
saw O
a O
group O
of O
who O
men O
arrived O
at O
the O
house O
, O
pulled O
out O
at O
least O
three O
firearms O
and O
started O
firing O
at O
the O
party O
. O
Maddrey B-PER
said O
detectives O
exchanged O
gunfire O
with O
the O
group O
of O
men O
. O
Four O
were O
shot O
and O
taken O
to O
the O
hospital O
, O
where O
they O
were O
in O
stable O
condition O
as O
of O
Saturday O
morning O
, O
police O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Police O
said O
at O
least O
three O
firearms O
were O
recovered O
. O
None O
of O
the O
police O
officers O
were O
shot O
. O
“ O
There O
were O
a O
lot O
of O
people O
out O
here O
when O
this O
occurred O
, O
” O
Maddrey B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
They O
were O
basically O
firing O
into O
a O
crowd O
. O
” O
“ O
These O
details O
are O
going O
to O
illustrate O
how O
gun O
violence O
continues O
to O
beleaguer O
our O
communities O
, O
and O
again O
, O
I O
implore O
members O
of O
our O
community O
that O
it O
is O
so O
important O
to O
work O
together O
with O
your O
police O
so O
we O
can O
put O
an O
end O
to O
this O
gun O
violence O
, O
” O
Maddrey B-PER
said O
. O
Police O
have O
not O
yet O
named O
any O
of O
the O
injured O
men O
or O
detailed O
what O
charges O
they O
may O
be O
facing O
. O
Police O
said O
no O
one O
else O
was O
injured O
in O
the O
shooting O
. O

Issey B-PER
Miyake I-PER
, O
influential O
Japanese B-LOC
fashion O
designer O
, O
dies O
aged O
84 O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Style O
! O
[fwp_0] O
( O
https://ads.stickyadstv.com/user-matching?id=185&_fw_gdpr=0&_fw_gdpr_consent= O
) O
![fwp_1] O
( O
https://ads.stickyadstv.com/auto-user-sync O
) O
