[
  {
    "original_text": "Secretary of State Antony Blinken criticized the Russian legal system more broadly, saying the sentence “puts a spotlight on our significant concerns with Russia’s legal system and the Russian government’s use of wrongful detentions to advance its own agenda, using individuals as political pawns.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Secretary",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "State",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Antony",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Blinken",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "criticized",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "legal",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "system",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "more",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "broadly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "saying",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sentence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "puts",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "spotlight",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "our",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "significant",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "concerns",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia’s",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "legal",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "system",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "government’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "use",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wrongful",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "detentions",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "advance",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "its",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "own",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "agenda",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "using",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "individuals",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "as",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "political",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "pawns",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".”",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Antony Blinken"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "He said the US is working to bring home Griner and Paul Whelan, an American citizen who has been held by Russia for alleged espionage since 2018. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "He",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "working",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "bring",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Whelan",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "an",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "citizen",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "who",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "has",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "been",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "held",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "by",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "alleged",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "espionage",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "since",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "2018",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "US"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Griner"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Paul Whelan"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "This is an absolute priority of mine and the Department’s,” Blinken said.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "This",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "an",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "absolute",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "priority",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "mine",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Department’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Blinken",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Antony Blinken"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "It’s now “up to the Russian side” on whether Griner’s conviction opens new doors for negotiations of a prisoner swap, National Security Council spokesperson John Kirby said.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "It’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "now",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“up",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "side”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "whether",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "conviction",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "opens",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "new",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "doors",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "negotiations",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prisoner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "swap,",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "National",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Security",
        "I-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Council",
        "I-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "spokesperson",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "John",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Kirby",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said.",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "National Security Council"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "John Kirby"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "“We’re still open to having our proposal seriously and positively considered, and if on the Russian side that means they feel like they’re more empowered to do that, then so be it,” Kirby told reporters in Thursday’s White House briefing.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "We’re",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "still",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "open",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "having",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "our",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "proposal",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "seriously",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "positively",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "considered",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "if",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "side",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "means",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "they",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "feel",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "like",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "they’re",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "more",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "empowered",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "do",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "then",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "so",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "be",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Kirby",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "told",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "reporters",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Thursday’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "White",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "House",
        "I-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "briefing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Kirby"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "White House"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Kirby reiterated the US position remains that it wants Russia to “take the deal on the table because it’s a good one, it’s a fair one, and it’ll help bring Paul and Brittney home.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Kirby",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "reiterated",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "position",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "remains",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wants",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“take",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "deal",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "table",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "because",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "good",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "fair",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "one",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it’ll",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "help",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "bring",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Paul",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Brittney",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Kirby"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Paul"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Brittney"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "CNN National Security Analyst Steve Hall said the harsh sentence was not a surprise and argued that Russia’s court proceedings are not legitimate. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "CNN",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "National",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Security",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Analyst",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Steve",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Hall",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "harsh",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sentence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "surprise",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "argued",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia’s",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "court",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "proceedings",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "legitimate",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "CNN"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Steve Hall"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "This is all performance in Russia.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "This",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "all",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "performance",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "There was never any doubt as to what was going to happen,” he said. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "There",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "never",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "any",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "doubt",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "as",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "what",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "going",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "happen",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "he",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "What Vladimir Putin is trying to do is basically drive up the bargaining price of Ms. Griner.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "What",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Vladimir",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Putin",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "trying",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "do",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "basically",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "drive",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "up",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "bargaining",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "price",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Ms.",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Vladimir Putin"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Ms. Griner"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Last week, CNN reported that the Biden administration proposed a prisoner swap with Russia, offering to release a convicted Russian arms trafficker, Viktor Bout, in exchange for Griner and Whelan.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Last",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "week",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "CNN",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "reported",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Biden",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "administration",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "proposed",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prisoner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "swap",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "offering",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "release",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "convicted",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arms",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "trafficker",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Viktor",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Bout",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "exchange",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Whelan",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "CNN"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Viktor Bout"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Russian officials countered the US offer, multiple sources familiar with the discussions have said, but US officials did not accept the request as a legitimate counteroffer.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "officials",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "countered",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "offer",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "multiple",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sources",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "familiar",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "discussions",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "have",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "but",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "officials",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "did",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "accept",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "request",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "as",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "legitimate",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "counteroffer",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "US"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "US"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "The Kremlin warned Tuesday that US “megaphone diplomacy” will not help negotiations for a prisoner exchange involving Griner.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "The",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Kremlin",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "warned",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Tuesday",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "US",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“megaphone",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "diplomacy”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "will",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "help",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "negotiations",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prisoner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "exchange",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "involving",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Kremlin"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Griner"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Kremlin spokesperson Dmitry Peskov said Moscow believes these talks should be “discrete.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Kremlin",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "spokesperson",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Dmitry",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Peskov",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Moscow",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "believes",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "these",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "talks",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "should",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "be",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“discrete.”",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Kremlin"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Dmitry Peskov"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Moscow"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Griner’s WNBA team, the Phoenix Mercury, played the Connecticut Sun on Thursday night.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Griner’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "WNBA",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "team",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Phoenix",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Mercury",
        "I-ORG"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "played",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Connecticut",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Sun",
        "I-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Thursday",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "night",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Phoenix"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "Mercury"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Connecticut"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "Sun"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Before the game, the teams held a 42-second moment of silence as players linked arms.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Before",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "game",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "teams",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "held",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "42-second",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "moment",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "silence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "as",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "players",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "linked",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arms",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Near the end of the tribute, spectators started chanting, “Bring her home!",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Near",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "end",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "tribute",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "spectators",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "started",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "chanting",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Bring",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "!",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Bring her home!”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Bring",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "!",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Griner, a six-time WNBA all-star, wears No.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Griner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "six-time",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "WNBA",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "all-star",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wears",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "No",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "42 for the Mercury.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "42",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Mercury",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "The Mercury lost 77-64.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "The",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Mercury",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "lost",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "77-64",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "Mercury"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Point guard Skylar Diggins-Smith, wearing a “We Are BG” T-shirt,  said after the game the verdict was devastating. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Point",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "guard",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Skylar",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Diggins-Smith",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wearing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "We",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "BG",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "T-shirt",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "after",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "game",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "verdict",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "devastating",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Skylar Diggins-Smith"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Nobody wanted to even play today,” she told reporters. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Nobody",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wanted",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "even",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "play",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "today",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "told",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "reporters",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "How are you supposed to approach the game, approach the court and with a clear mind, and our whole group is crying before the game?",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "How",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "you",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "supposed",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "approach",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "game",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "approach",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "court",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "clear",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "mind",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "our",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "whole",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "group",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "crying",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "before",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "game",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "?",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Because you try to honor her and you try to come out and still play hard for her.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Because",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "you",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "try",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "honor",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "you",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "try",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "come",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "out",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "still",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "play",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "hard",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Earlier, the Mercury released a statement calling the verdict “a sobering milestone in the 168-day nightmare” of her detention. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Earlier,",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Mercury",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "released",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "statement",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "calling",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "verdict",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sobering",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "milestone",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "168-day",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "nightmare”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "detention.",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "We are inspired every day by BG’s strength and we are steadfastly committed to keeping her top-of-mind publicly until she is safely back on American soil.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "We",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "inspired",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "every",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "day",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "by",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "BG’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "strength",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "we",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "steadfastly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "committed",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "keeping",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "top-of-mind",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "publicly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "until",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "safely",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "back",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "on",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "American",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "soil",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "American"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "We will not allow her to be forgotten.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "We",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "will",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "allow",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "be",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "forgotten",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "We are BG,” the statement reads.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "We",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "BG",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "statement",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "reads",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Head coach Vanessa Nygaard told CNN the guilty verdict and Griner’s sentence is “unacceptable.” “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Head",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "coach",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Vanessa",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Nygaard",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "told",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "CNN",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "guilty",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "verdict",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sentence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“unacceptable.”",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Vanessa Nygaard"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "It’s just heartbreaking,” the coach said. “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "It’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "just",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "heartbreaking",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "coach",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".”",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "To hear her words and her apologies.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "To",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "hear",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "words",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "apologies",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Just trying to send love, prayers and strength to her.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Just",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "trying",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "send",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "love",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prayers",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "strength",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "original_text": "In a joint statement, WNBA Commissioner Cathy Engelbert and NBA Commissioner Adam Silver criticized the verdict and sentence as “unjustified and unfortunate, but not unexpected.” “",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "In",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "joint",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "statement",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "WNBA",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Commissioner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Cathy",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Engelbert",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "NBA",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Commissioner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Adam",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "Silver",
        "I-PER"
      ],
      [
        "criticized",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "verdict",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "sentence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "as",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“unjustified",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "unfortunate",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "but",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "unexpected",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Cathy Engelbert"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Adam Silver"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "The WNBA and NBA’s commitment to her safe return has not wavered and it is our hope that we are near the end of this process of finally bringing BG home to the United States,” they said.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "The",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "WNBA",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "NBA’s",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "commitment",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "safe",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "return",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "has",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "wavered",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "is",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "our",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "hope",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "we",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "near",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "end",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "this",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "process",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "finally",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "bringing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "BG",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "United",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "States",
        "I-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ",”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "they",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "WNBA"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "NBA"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "United States"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Defense asked for leniency in closing arguments  The court hearing Thursday began shortly after Griner arrived in handcuffs, escorted by Russian officers into the defendant’s cage.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Defense",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "asked",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "leniency",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "closing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arguments",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "The",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "court",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "hearing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Thursday",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "began",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "shortly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "after",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "arrived",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "handcuffs",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "escorted",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "by",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "officers",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "into",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "defendant’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "cage",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Brittney Griner"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Once uncuffed, she spoke with her legal team and then held up a photo of the UMMC Ekaterinburg basketball team, the Russian squad she played for during the WNBA offseason.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Once",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "uncuffed",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "spoke",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "legal",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "team",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "then",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "held",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "up",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "photo",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "UMMC",
        "B-ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Ekaterinburg",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "basketball",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "team",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "squad",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "played",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "during",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "WNBA",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "offseason",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "ORG",
        "entity_value": "UMMC"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Ekaterinburg"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "In closing arguments, Blagovolina argued that Griner never used marijuana in Russia and that she never had the intention of doing so.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "In",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "closing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arguments",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Blagovolina",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "argued",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "never",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "used",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "marijuana",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "never",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "had",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "intention",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "doing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "so",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Blagovolina"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Griner"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "She had no need to bring the vape cartridges to Russia, the lawyer added.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "She",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "had",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "no",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "need",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "bring",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "vape",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "cartridges",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "lawyer",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "added",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "All this confirms the complete absence of intent in her actions, Blagovolina argued.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "All",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "this",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "confirms",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "complete",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "absence",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "intent",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "actions",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Blagovolina",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "argued",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Blagovolina"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Even if Griner ever used medical marijuana, it was only at home back in Arizona, rare and only with a doctor’s prescription, she added.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Even",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "if",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "ever",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "used",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "medical",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "marijuana",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "only",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "at",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "home",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "back",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Arizona",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "rare",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "only",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "with",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "doctor’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prescription",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "added",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Arizona"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "She couldn’t have known how strict the laws were in Russia, Blagovolina said.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "She",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "couldn’t",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "have",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "known",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "how",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "strict",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "laws",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "were",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "in",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russia",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Blagovolina",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russia"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Blagovolina"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Boykov also argued Griner had no opportunity to properly examine the court documents.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Boykov",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "also",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "argued",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "had",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "no",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "opportunity",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "properly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "examine",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "court",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "documents",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Boykov"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Griner"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "He said that the Russian constitution guarantees everyone the right to use their native language and the free choice of the language of communication.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "He",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Russian",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "constitution",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "guarantees",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "everyone",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "right",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "use",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "their",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "native",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "language",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "free",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "choice",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "language",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "of",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "communication",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Russian"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Boykov cited an instance when a language interpreter provided to Griner flipped through a lengthy document offered by an investigator for translation and then told Griner, “Basically, it means that you are guilty.”",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Boykov",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "cited",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "an",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "instance",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "when",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "language",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "interpreter",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "provided",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "to",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "flipped",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "through",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "a",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "lengthy",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "document",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "offered",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "by",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "an",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "investigator",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "for",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "translation",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "then",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "told",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Basically",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "it",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "means",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "that",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "you",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "are",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "guilty",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "”",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Boykov"
      },
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Griner"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Throughout the trial, Griner’s attorneys have laid out arguments undermining the prosecution’s case and claiming her detention was not handled correctly after she was stopped February 17 by personnel at the Sheremetyevo International Airport.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Throughout",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "trial",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Griner’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "attorneys",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "have",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "laid",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "out",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arguments",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "undermining",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "prosecution’s",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "case",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "claiming",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "detention",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "not",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "handled",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "correctly",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "after",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "she",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "was",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "stopped",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "February",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "17",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "by",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "personnel",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "at",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "the",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Sheremetyevo",
        "B-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "International",
        "I-LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Airport",
        "I-LOC"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "LOC",
        "entity_value": "Sheremetyevo International Airport"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "original_text": "Her detention, search and arrest were “improper,” Boykov said last week, noting more details would be revealed during closing arguments.",
    "conll_annotations": [
      [
        "Her",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "detention",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "search",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "and",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arrest",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "were",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "“improper,”",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "Boykov",
        "B-PER"
      ],
      [
        "said",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "last",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "week",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ",",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "noting",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "more",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "details",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "would",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "be",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "revealed",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "during",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "closing",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        "arguments",
        "O"
      ],
      [
        ".",
        "O"
      ]
    ],
    "entities": [
      {
        "entity_type": "PER",
        "entity_value": "Alexander Boykov"
      }
    ]
  }
]