The O
results O
amazed O
the O
researchers O
involved O
in O
the O
project O

Check O
out O
the O
pig O
cells O
, O
shown O
at O
right O
in O
the O
side-by-side O
comparison O
above O
, O
revived O
by O
the O
OrganEx B-ORG
system O
, O
a O
new O
technology O
they O
developed O

The O
goal O
, O
though O
, O
isn’t O
to O
bring O
animals O
magically O
back O
to O
life O
– O
it’s O
to O
expand O
the O
window O
for O
much-needed O
human O
organ O
transplants O
. O

Force O
of O
nature O
The O
massive O
eruption O
of O
an O
undersea O
volcano O
near O
Tonga B-LOC
in O
January O
has O
defied O
easy O
explanation O
, O
consistently O
surprising O
the O
scientists O
who O
continue O
to O
study O
it O
. O

It O
created O
an O
unexpected O
type O
of O
tsunami O
, O
a O
sonic O
boom O
heard O
as O
far O
away O
as O
Alaska B-LOC
, O
hurricane-strength O
winds O
in O
space O
and O
unusual O
pressure O
waves O
. O

Now O
we O
know O
, O
thanks O
to O
detections O
from O
a O
NASA B-ORG
satellite O
, O
the O
volcano O
blasted O
such O
a O
massive O
amount O
of O
water O
vapor O
high O
into O
the O
atmosphere O
that O
it’s O
likely O
to O
temporarily O
warm O
Earth’s B-LOC
surface O
. O

The O
plume O
of O
vapor O
the O
eruption O
sent O
into O
the O
stratosphere O
– O
which O
is O
located O
between O
8 O
and O
33 O
miles O
( O
12 O
and O
53 O
kilometers O
) O
above O
Earth’s B-LOC
surface O
– O
included O
enough O
water O
to O
fill O
58,000 O
Olympic-size O
swimming O
pools O
. O

Fantastic O
creatures O
The O
NASA B-ORG
Artemis I-ORG
mission O
isn’t O
just O
about O
returning O
to O
the O
moon O
– O
it’s O
part O
of O
preparations O
for O
a O
bolder O
plan O
to O
go O
to O
Mars B-LOC

How O
astronauts O
will O
make O
the O
years-long O
trip O
to O
the O
red O
planet O
is O
uncertain O

One O
idea O
is O
to O
induce O
hibernation O
in O
the O
space O
travelers O
, O
and O
a O
tiny O
, O
mouselike O
creature O
that O
lives O
in O
the O
Patagonian B-LOC
forest O
may O
hold O
a O
key O
to O
unlocking O
this O
approach O
. O

Once O
the O
weather O
turns O
cold O
, O
the O
bug-eyed O
monito O
del O
monte O
builds O
a O
mossy O
nest O
in O
a O
tree O
hollow O
. O

There O
, O
the O
tiny O
marsupial O
enters O
a O
physiological O
state O
called O
torpor O
, O
and O
its O
heart O
rate O
drops O
from O
200 O
beats O
per O
minute O
down O
to O
two O
or O
three O
beats O
per O
minute O
. O

During O
this O
inactive O
period O
, O
the O
animal O
conserves O
energy O
, O
taking O
a O
breath O
once O
every O
three O
minutes O
. O

Understanding O
how O
it O
almost O
stops O
its O
metabolism O
and O
wakes O
up O
weeks O
later O
unscathed O
potentially O
could O
help O
scientists O
come O
up O
with O
a O
plan O
for O
human O
hibernation O
on O
long-haul O
space O
missions O

Learn O
more O
about O
the O
monito O
during O
Sunday’s O
episode O
of O
the O
CNN B-ORG
docuseries O
“Patagonia: O
Life O
on O
the O
Edge O
of O
the O
World” O
at O
9 O
. O
p.m. O
ET/PT O

Every O
new O
episode O
of O
the O
six-part O
series O
will O
be O
available O
on O
CNNgo B-ORG
the O
day O
after O
it O
airs O
on O
television O

You O
can O
also O
access O
CNNgo B-ORG
via O
our O
CNN B-ORG
app O

Across O
the O
universe O
Walking O
on O
Bennu B-LOC
, O
a O
near-Earth O
asteroid O
, O
would O
be O
a O
bit O
like O
wading O
through O
a O
ball O
pit O
, O
NASA B-ORG
scientists O
have O
found O
. O

Images O
and O
data O
from O
the O
agency’s O
OSIRIS-REx B-ORG
mission O
revealed O
the O
asteroid’s O
exterior O
is O
made O
of O
loosely O
packed O
particles O
that O
aren’t O
bound O
together O
securely O

The O
OSIRIS-REx B-ORG
spacecraft O
, O
which O
in O
2020 O
successfully O
collected O
a O
sample O
from O
the O
asteroid O
, O
encountered O
little O
resistance O
when O
it O
landed O
– O
about O
the O
same O
amount O
as O
someone O
might O
feel O
pushing O
the O
plunger O
on O
a O
French B-LOC
press O
coffee O
maker O
. O

If O
the O
spacecraft O
hadn’t O
fired O
its O
thruster O
to O
back O
away O
after O
its O
quick O
collection O
of O
dust O
and O
rocks O
, O
it O
might O
have O
sunk O
right O
into O
the O
asteroid O
. O

It’s O
just O
the O
latest O
unexpected O
finding O
about O
Bennu O
as O
OSIRIS-REx B-ORG
and O
the O
precious O
sample O
make O
their O
way O
toward O
Earth B-LOC

Ocean O
secrets O
Coins O
and O
priceless O
jewels O
once O
belonging O
to O
seafaring O
knights O
are O
among O
the O
treasures O
recently O
discovered O
on O
a O
Spanish B-LOC
shipwreck O

The O
Nuestra O
Señora O
de O
las O
Maravillas O
( O
or O
Our O
Lady O
of O
Wonders O
) O
sank O
in O
1656 O
after O
it O
collided O
with O
another O
boat O
from O
its O
fleet O
and O
crashed O
into O
a O
coral O
reef O
off O
the O
Bahamas B-LOC

The O
891-ton O
vessel O
was O
carrying O
a O
massive O
trove O
, O
some O
of O
which O
was O
reserved O
as O
royal O
tax O
for O
King B-PER
Philip I-PER
IV I-PER
, O
from O
Cuba B-LOC
to O
Seville B-LOC
, O
Spain B-LOC
. O

The O
cache O
was O
more O
significant O
than O
usual O
, O
as O
the O
Maravillas O
also O
had O
been O
transporting O
treasure O
retrieved O
from O
a O
ship O
that O
had O
sunk O
two O
years O
prior O
. O

Discoveries O
Escape O
to O
worlds O
beyond O
your O
own O
with O
these O
stories O
: O
– O
A O
paleontologist O
found O
an O
extremely O
cool O
fossil O
in O
his O
backyard O

It’s O
upending O
what O
we O
know O
about O
the O
first O
Americans B-LOC
. O
– O

Caves O
provided O
shelter O
to O
Earth’s B-LOC
earliest O
human O
inhabitants O
. O

Similar O
formations O
on O
the O
moon O
could O
provide O
pioneering O
astronauts O
with O
a O
lunar O
safe O
haven O
. O

The O
James B-ORG
Webb I-ORG
Space I-ORG
Telescope I-ORG
has O
captured O
a O
stunning O
image O
of O
a O
strange O
, O
cartwheel-shaped O
galaxy O
. O

Like O
what O
you’ve O
read O
? O

Oh, O
but O
there’s O
more. O

Sign O
up O
here O
to O
receive O
in O
your O
inbox O
the O
next O
edition O
of O
Wonder B-ORG
Theory I-ORG
, O
brought O
to O
you O
by O
CNN B-ORG
Space I-ORG
and O
Science I-ORG
writers O
Ashley B-PER
Strickland I-PER
and O
Katie B-PER
Hunt I-PER
, O
who O
find O
wonder O
in O
planets O
beyond O
our O
solar O
system O
and O
discoveries O
from O
the O
ancient O
world O
. O

The O
Senate B-ORG
on O
Sunday O
afternoon O
passed O
Democrats’ B-ORG
$750 O
billion O
health O
care O
, O
tax O
and O
climate O
bill O
, O
in O
a O
significant O
victory O
for O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
and O
his O
party O
. O

The O
final O
, O
party-line O
vote O
was O
51-50 O
, O
with O
Vice O
President O
Kamala B-PER
Harris I-PER
breaking O
the O
tie O
. O

The O
package O
is O
the O
product O
of O
painstaking O
negotiations O
, O
and O
its O
final O
passage O
would O
give O
Democrats B-ORG
a O
chance O
to O
achieve O
major O
policy O
objectives O
ahead O
of O
the O
upcoming O
midterm O
elections O
. O

The O
Democrat-controlled O
House O
, O
which O
is O
expected O
to O
take O
up O
the O
legislation O
on O
Friday O
, O
August O
12 O
, O
must O
approve O
the O
bill O
before O
Biden B-PER
can O
sign O
it O
into O
law O
. O

The O
sweeping O
bill O
– O
named O
the O
Inflation B-ORG
Reduction I-ORG
Act I-ORG
– O
would O
represent O
the O
largest O
climate O
investment O
in O
US B-LOC
history O
and O
make O
major O
changes O
to O
health O
policy O
by O
giving O
Medicare B-ORG
the O
power O
for O
the O
first O
time O
to O
negotiate O
the O
prices O
of O
certain O
prescription O
drugs O
and O
extending O
expiring O
health O
care O
subsidies O
for O
three O
years O
. O

The O
legislation O
would O
reduce O
the O
deficit O
, O
be O
paid O
for O
through O
new O
taxes O
– O
including O
a O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
on O
large O
corporations O
and O
a O
1% O
tax O
on O
stock O
buybacks O
– O
and O
boost O
the O
Internal B-ORG
Revenue I-ORG
Service’s I-ORG
ability O
to O
collect O
. O

It O
would O
raise O
over O
$700 O
billion O
in O
government O
revenue O
over O
10 O
years O
and O
spend O
over O
$430 O
billion O
to O
reduce O
carbon O
emissions O
and O
extend O
subsidies O
for O
health O
insurance O
under O
the O
Affordable B-ORG
Care I-ORG
Act I-ORG
and O
use O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
new O
revenue O
to O
reduce O
the O
deficit O

Senate B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
, O
with O
a O
narrow O
50-seat O
majority O
, O
stayed O
unified O
to O
pass O
the O
legislation O
, O
using O
a O
special O
, O
filibuster-proof O
process O
to O
approve O
the O
measure O
without O
Republican O
votes O
. O

Final O
passage O
came O
after O
a O
marathon O
series O
of O
contentious O
amendment O
votes O
known O
as O
a O
“vote-a-rama” O
that O
stretched O
nearly O
16 O
hours O
from O
late O
Saturday B-LOC
night O
until O
Sunday B-LOC
afternoon O

West B-LOC
Virginia I-LOC
Democratic O
Sen. O
Joe B-PER
Manchin I-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
that O
the O
legislation O
he O
helped O
write O
is O
“a O
good O
balanced O
bill.” O

I O
think O
we’ll O
all O
benefit O
from O
it O
; O
the O
country O
will O
, O
Manchin B-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

We O
have O
energy O
security O
, O
that’s O
what O
we O
were O
looking O
for O
. O

And O
we O
have O
the O
ability O
to O
invest O
in O
the O
energy O
of O
the O
future O
. O

Biden B-PER
praised O
the O
Senate B-ORG
for O
passing O
the O
bill O
in O
a O
statement O
Sunday O
, O
thanking O
Democrats B-ORG
in O
the O
chamber O
and O
touting O
the O
legislation’s O
climate O
investments O
and O
health O
care O
provisions O
. O

Today O
, O
Senate B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
sided O
with O
American O
families O
over O
special O
interests O
, O
voting O
to O
lower O
the O
cost O
of O
prescription O
drugs O
, O
health O
insurance O
, O
and O
everyday O
energy O
costs O
and O
reduce O
the O
deficit O
, O
while O
making O
the O
wealthiest O
corporations O
finally O
pay O
their O
fair O
share O
, O
” O
Biden B-PER
said O
. O

How O
Senate B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
passed O
the O
bill O
on O
a O
party-line O
vote O
Senate B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
have O
long O
hoped O
to O
pass O
a O
signature O
legislative O
package O
that O
would O
incorporate O
major O
agenda O
items O
for O
the O
party O
, O
but O
struggled O
for O
months O
to O
reach O
a O
deal O
that O
gained O
full O
support O
of O
their O
caucus O

Manchin O
played O
a O
key O
role O
in O
shaping O
the O
legislation O
– O
which O
only O
moved O
forward O
after O
the O
West B-LOC
Virginia I-LOC
Democrat O
and O
Senate O
Majority O
Leader O
Chuck B-PER
Schumer I-PER
announced O
a O
deal O
at O
the O
end O
of O
July O
, O
a O
major O
breakthrough O
for O
Democrats O
after O
earlier O
negotiations O
had O
stalled O
out O
. O

Arizona B-LOC
Sen. O
Kyrsten B-PER
Sinema I-PER
on O
Thursday O
night O
offered O
critical O
support O
after O
party O
leaders O
agreed O
to O
change O
new O
tax O
proposals O
, O
indicating O
she O
would O
“move O
forward” O
on O
the O
sweeping O
economic O
package O
. O

But O
Sinema B-PER
, O
Manchin B-PER
and O
other O
senators O
worked O
through O
the O
weekend O
making O
crucial O
alterations O
on O
the O
bill O

To O
avoid O
a O
last-minute O
collapse O
of O
the O
bill O
on O
Sunday B-LOC
, O
Democrats B-ORG
created O
a O
plan O
to O
win O
over O
Sinema B-PER
, O
who O
was O
concerned O
over O
the O
15% O
corporate O
minimum O
tax’s O
impact O
on O
subsidiaries O
owned O
by O
private O
equity O
. O

Senate B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
accepted O
a O
narrower O
tax O
proposal O
, O
but O
instead O
of O
paying O
for O
it O
through O
a O
change O
to O
the O
state O
and O
local O
tax O
( O
SALT O
) O
deduction O
, O
as O
Senate B-ORG
GOP I-ORG
Whip O
John B-PER
Thune I-PER
of O
South B-LOC
Dakota I-LOC
suggested O
, O
they O
instead O
extended O
the O
limitation O
on O
the O
amount O
of O
losses O
that O
businesses O
can O
deduct O
for O
another O
two O
years O
. O

The O
change O
was O
intended O
to O
prevent O
House B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
primarily O
from O
coastal O
districts O
, O
who O
have O
campaigned O
on O
repealing O
limits O
on O
the O
SALT O
deduction O
, O
from O
breaking O
from O
the O
bill O
, O
when O
they O
vote O
on O
it O
later O
this O
week O
. O

After O
the O
bill’s O
passage O
in O
the O
Senate B-ORG
, O
Sinema B-PER
said O
in O
a O
statement O
it O
would O
“help O
Arizonans O
build O
better O
lives O
for O
themselves O
and O
their O
families O
by O
lowering O
prices O
, O
making O
health O
care O
more O
affordable O
and O
accessible O
, O
and O
securing O
Arizona’s B-LOC
water O
and O
energy O
future O
, O
” O
while O
also O
“boosting O
innovation O
and O
spurring O
job O
creation O
. O

In O
a O
good O
sign O
for O
the O
bill O
becoming O
law O
, O
key O
House B-ORG
Democrats I-ORG
signaled O
later O
Sunday O
that O
they’ll O
vote O
for O
it O
despite O
previous O
demands O
over O
SALT O
. O

Rep. O
Josh B-PER
Gottheimer I-PER
of O
New B-LOC
Jersey I-LOC
had O
been O
part O
of O
the O
“No O
SALT, O
no O
deal” O
caucus. O

But O
he O
said O
the O
bill O
passes O
his O
test O
because O
it O
doesn’t O
raise O
individual O
income O
tax O
rates O

Rep. O
Mikie B-PER
Sherrill I-PER
of O
New B-LOC
Jersey I-LOC
, O
another O
member O
of O
that O
caucus O
, O
echoed O
his O
sentiment O
: O
“ O
I O
will O
also O
remain O
steadfast O
in O
my O
commitment O
to O
ensuring O
that O
any O
discussion O
of O
reforms O
to O
the O
2017 O
tax O
law O
begins O
with O
addressing O
SALT O
. O
” O

Because O
this O
legislation O
does O
not O
raise O
taxes O
on O
families O
in O
my O
district O
, O
but O
in O
fact O
significantly O
lowers O
their O
costs O
, O
I O
will O
be O
voting O
for O
it O
. O

Republicans B-ORG
used O
the O
weekend O
“vote-a-rama” O
to O
put O
Democrats B-ORG
on O
the O
spot O
and O
force O
politically O
tough O
votes O

They O
were O
also O
successful O
in O
removing O
a O
key O
insulin O
provision O
to O
cap O
the O
price O
of O
insulin O
to O
$35 O
per O
month O
on O
the O
private O
insurance O
market O
, O
which O
the O
Senate B-ORG
parliamentarian O
ruled O
was O
not O
compliant O
with O
the O
Senate’s B-ORG
reconciliation O
rules O
. O

The O
$35 O
insulin O
cap O
for O
Medicare B-ORG
beneficiaries O
remains O
in O
place O
. O

The O
Kentucky B-LOC
Republican O
said O
Democrats B-ORG
“do O
not O
care O
about O
middle-class O
families’ O
priorities.” O

And O
their O
response O
to O
the O
runaway O
inflation O
they’ve O
created O
is O
a O
bill O
that O
experts O
say O
will O
not O
meaningfully O
cut O
inflation O
at O
all O
, O
said O
McConnell B-PER
. O

The O
American O
people O
are O
clear O
about O
their O
priorities O

Environmental O
regulation O
is O
a O
3% O
issue O

Americans O
want O
solutions O
for O
inflation O
, O
crime O
, O
and O
the O
border O
. O

How O
the O
bill O
addresses O
the O
climate O
crisis O
While O
economists O
disagree O
over O
whether O
the O
package O
would O
, O
in O
fact O
, O
live O
up O
to O
its O
name O
and O
reduce O
inflation O
, O
particularly O
in O
the O
short O
term O
, O
the O
bill O
would O
have O
a O
crucial O
impact O
on O
reducing O
carbon O
emissions O
. O

The O
nearly O
$370 O
billion O
clean O
energy O
and O
climate O
package O
is O
the O
largest O
climate O
investment O
in O
US B-LOC
history O
, O
and O
the O
biggest O
victory O
for O
the O
environmental O
movement O
since O
the O
landmark O
Clean B-ORG
Air I-ORG
Act I-ORG
. O

It O
also O
comes O
at O
a O
critical O
time O
; O
this O
summer O
has O
seen O
punishing O
heat O
waves O
and O
deadly O
floods O
across O
the O
country O
, O
which O
scientists O
say O
are O
both O
linked O
to O
a O
warming O
planet O
. O

Analysis O
from O
Senate B-ORG
Majority I-ORG
Leader I-ORG
Chuck B-PER
Schumer’s I-PER
office O
– O
as O
well O
as O
multiple O
independent O
analyses O
– O
suggests O
the O
measure O
would O
reduce O
US B-LOC
carbon O
emissions O
by O
up O
to O
40% O
by O
2030 O

Strong O
climate O
regulations O
from O
the O
Biden B-ORG
administration I-ORG
and O
action O
from O
states O
would O
be O
needed O
to O
get O
to O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
’s O
goal O
of O
cutting O
emissions O
50% O
by O
2030 O

The O
bill O
also O
contains O
many O
tax O
incentives O
meant O
to O
bring O
down O
the O
cost O
of O
electricity O
with O
more O
renewables O
, O
and O
spur O
more O
American B-LOC
consumers O
to O
switch O
to O
electricity O
to O
power O
their O
homes O
and O
vehicles O
. O

Lawmakers O
said O
the O
bill O
represents O
a O
monumental O
victory O
and O
is O
also O
just O
the O
start O
of O
what’s O
needed O
to O
combat O
the O
climate O
crisis O
. O

This O
isn’t O
about O
the O
laws O
of O
politics O
, O
this O
is O
about O
the O
laws O
of O
physics O
, O
” O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Brian B-PER
Schatz I-PER
of O
Hawaii B-LOC
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O

We O
all O
knew O
coming O
into O
this O
effort O
that O
we O
had O
to O
do O
what O
the O
science O
tells O
us O
what O
we O
need O
to O
do O

Key O
health O
care O
and O
tax O
policy O
in O
the O
bill O
The O
bill O
would O
empower O
Medicare B-ORG
to O
negotiate O
prices O
of O
certain O
costly O
medications O
administered O
in O
doctors’ O
offices O
or O
purchased O
at O
the O
pharmacy O

The O
Health O
and O
Human O
Services O
secretary O
would O
negotiate O
the O
prices O
of O
10 O
drugs O
in O
2026 O
, O
and O
another O
15 O
drugs O
in O
2027 O
and O
again O
in O
2028 O

The O
number O
would O
rise O
to O
20 O
drugs O
a O
year O
for O
2029 O
and O
beyond O

This O
controversial O
provision O
is O
far O
more O
limited O
than O
the O
one O
House B-ORG
Democratic I-ORG
leaders O
have O
backed O
in O
the O
past O

But O
it O
would O
open O
the O
door O
to O
fulfilling O
a O
longstanding O
party O
goal O
of O
allowing O
Medicare B-ORG
to O
use O
its O
heft O
to O
lower O
drug O
costs O

Democrats B-ORG
are O
also O
planning O
to O
extend O
the O
enhanced O
federal O
premium O
subsidies O
for O
Obamacare B-ORG
coverage O
through O
2025 O
, O
a O
year O
later O
than O
lawmakers O
recently O
discussed O
. O

That O
way O
, O
they O
wouldn’t O
expire O
just O
after O
the O
2024 O
presidential O
election O
. O

To O
boost O
revenue O
, O
the O
bill O
would O
impose O
a O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
on O
the O
income O
large O
corporations O
report O
to O
shareholders O
, O
known O
as O
book O
income O
, O
as O
opposed O
to O
the O
Internal B-ORG
Revenue I-ORG
Service I-ORG
. O

The O
measure O
, O
which O
would O
raise O
$258 O
billion O
over O
a O
decade O
, O
would O
apply O
to O
companies O
with O
profits O
over O
$1 O
billion O
. O

Concerned O
about O
how O
this O
provision O
would O
affect O
certain O
businesses O
, O
particularly O
manufacturers O
, O
Sinema B-PER
has O
suggested O
that O
she O
won O
changes O
to O
the O
Democrats’ B-ORG
plan O
to O
pare O
back O
how O
companies O
can O
deduct O
depreciated O
assets O
from O
their O
taxes O
. O

The O
details O
remain O
unclear O

However O
, O
Sinema B-PER
nixed O
her O
party’s O
effort O
to O
tighten O
the O
carried O
interest O
loophole O
, O
which O
allows O
investment O
managers O
to O
treat O
much O
of O
their O
compensation O
as O
capital O
gains O
and O
pay O
a O
20% O
long-term O
capital O
gains O
tax O
rate O
instead O
of O
income O
tax O
rates O
of O
up O
to O
37 O
. O

The O
provision O
would O
have O
lengthened O
the O
amount O
of O
time O
investment O
managers’ O
profit O
interest O
must O
be O
held O
from O
three O
years O
to O
five O
years O
to O
take O
advantage O
of O
the O
lower O
tax O
rate O
. O

Addressing O
this O
loophole O
, O
which O
would O
have O
raised O
$14 O
billion O
over O
a O
decade O
, O
had O
been O
a O
longtime O
goal O
of O
congressional O
Democrats B-ORG

In O
its O
place O
, O
a O
1% O
excise O
tax O
on O
companies’ O
stock O
buybacks O
was O
added O
, O
raising O
another O
$74 O
billion O
, O
according O
to O
a O
Democratic O
aide O
. O

This O
story O
and O
headline O
have O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
developments O

CNN B-ORG
’s O
Ella B-PER
Nilsen I-PER
, O
Tami B-PER
Luhby I-PER
, O
Katie B-PER
Lobosco I-PER
, O
Matt B-PER
Egan I-PER
and O
Kristin B-PER
Wilson I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

With O
so O
many O
options O
to O
consider O
, O
choosing O
a O
new O
credit O
card O
can O
be O
daunting O
. O

But O
for O
most O
Americans B-LOC
, O
it’s O
a O
necessary O
step O
to O
establishing O
credit O
. O

About O
92 O
million O
Americans B-LOC
have O
little O
to O
no O
credit O
history O
, O
according O
to O
Equifax B-ORG
. O

With O
scant O
information O
to O
go O
on O
, O
it’s O
harder O
for O
credit O
bureaus O
to O
assess O
the O
likelihood O
that O
a O
person O
will O
be O
able O
to O
pay O
back O
a O
loan O
or O
line O
of O
credit O
. O

One O
way O
to O
build O
your O
credit O
history O
is O
by O
opening O
and O
using O
a O
credit O
card O

So O
how O
do O
you O
decide O
which O
card O
is O
right O
for O
you O
? O

Here O
are O
the O
most O
important O
factors O
to O
consider O
when O
shopping O
for O
a O
new O
card O
: O
Is O
your O
credit O
score O
high O
enough O
? O

Most O
cards O
have O
credit O
score O
requirements O
, O
among O
other O
criteria O
, O
so O
it’s O
important O
to O
figure O
out O
what O
your O
score O
is O
and O
whether O
it’s O
good O
enough O
for O
you O
to O
be O
approved O
. O

But O
what O
exactly O
constitutes O
a O
good O
credit O
score O
? O

Ted B-PER
Rossman I-PER
, O
senior O
industry O
analyst O
at O
Bankrate.com B-ORG
, O
explains O
that O
an O
excellent O
credit O
score O
is O
“ O
generally O
defined O
[ O
as O
 ] O
740 O
or O
higher O
on O
the O
FICO O
scale O
, O
which O
goes O
from O
300 O
to O
850 O
.” O

The O
FICO B-ORG
score O
represents O
how O
likely O
you O
are O
to O
pay O
back O
your O
credit O
card O
bill O
based O
off O
previous O
payments O

Although O
many O
credit O
cards O
have O
a O
FICO O
score O
cutoff O
of O
670 O
, O
it’s O
not O
a O
strict O
limit O
. O

“ O
The O
average O
FICO O
score O
is O
716 O
, O
so O
most O
people O
are O
in O
the O
right O
ballpark O
for O
most O
cards O
,” O
said O
Rossman B-PER
. O
“ O

If O
you O
want O
to O
raise O
your O
credit O
score O
, O
Rossman B-PER
said O
the O
key O
is O
paying O
your O
credit O
card O
bills O
on O
time O
, O
keeping O
your O
balance O
low O
and O
proving O
that O
you O
can O
successfully O
manage O
various O
types O
of O
credit O
over O
the O
long O
haul O
. O

And O
that O
can O
take O
time O

Much O
of O
this O
is O
a O
marathon O
, O
not O
a O
sprint O
, O
he O
noted O
. O

For O
those O
who O
are O
trying O
to O
improve O
a O
lower O
credit O
score O
or O
who O
are O
seeking O
to O
build O
credit O
, O
Rossman B-PER
suggests O
secured O
cards O
, O
which O
are O
backed O
by O
a O
security O
deposit O
and O
are O
often O
held O
in O
a O
linked O
bank O
account O
. O

This O
functions O
as O
collateral O
should O
you O
fail O
to O
pay O
your O
monthly O
bill O

These O
cards O
also O
have O
strict O
limits O
and O
do O
not O
allow O
cardholders O
to O
spend O
more O
money O
than O
they O
deposited O
upfront O

So O
if O
your O
security O
deposit O
was O
$500 O
, O
your O
spending O
limit O
will O
be O
$500 O
. O

What O
rewards O
does O
it O
offer O
? O

There O
are O
three O
main O
types O
of O
credit O
card O
rewards O
– O
cash O
back O
, O
points O
and O
miles O
. O

Cash O
back O
rewards O
pay O
cardholders O
a O
percentage O
of O
what O
they O
have O
spent O
on O
purchases O

The O
cash O
accumulated O
can O
typically O
be O
redeemed O
in O
the O
form O
of O
a O
check O
or O
direct O
deposit O
, O
applied O
to O
future O
balances O
as O
a O
statement O
credit O
, O
or O
sometimes O
used O
to O
make O
purchases O
. O

Points O
and O
miles O
rewards O
cards O
give O
cardholders O
the O
option O
to O
redeem O
their O
rewards O
for O
travel O
, O
and O
other O
products O
and O
services O
. O

Whichever O
form O
of O
rewards O
you O
choose O
, O
you’ll O
want O
to O
make O
sure O
it O
enables O
you O
to O
get O
the O
most O
out O
of O
your O
purchases O
. O

Start O
by O
considering O
how O
you O
spend O
your O
money O

While O
some O
cards O
offer O
more O
rewards O
for O
spending O
categories O
like O
travel O
and O
dining O
, O
others O
offer O
better O
benefits O
for O
grocery O
store O
purchases O
and O
gas O
. O

Others O
will O
rotate O
the O
categories O
that O
offer O
the O
highest O
rewards O
, O
or O
even O
let O
you O
choose O
. O

Many O
people O
prefer O
cash O
back O
rewards O
because O
they O
are O
easier O
to O
navigate O
and O
do O
not O
require O
tracking O
purchase O
categories O
, O
according O
to O
Rossman B-PER
. O

He O
suggests O
finding O
a O
card O
that O
gives O
2% O
cash O
back O
on O
every O
purchase O

If O
you’re O
willing O
to O
dabble O
with O
different O
cards O
in O
order O
to O
chase O
more O
rewards O
, O
Rossman B-PER
recommends O
having O
a O
cash O
back O
card O
for O
general O
purchases O
, O
and O
then O
layering O
in O
other O
cards O
for O
more O
specific O
categories O
. O

Use O
something O
like O
[ O
a O
general O
cash O
back O
card O
] O
as O
a O
floor O
, O
guaranteeing O
you’ll O
never O
get O
less O
than O
2% O
cash O
back O
on O
a O
given O
purchase O
, O
and O
lean O
into O
categories O
in O
which O
you O
spend O
a O
lot O
of O
money O
, O
” O
said O
Rossman B-PER
. O

Be O
mindful O
of O
fees O
While O
many O
banks O
won’t O
charge O
you O
anything O
just O
to O
have O
a O
credit O
card O
, O
some O
rewards O
cards O
will O
charge O
annual O
fees O
, O
typically O
ranging O
from O
$95 O
per O
year O
to O
as O
much O
as O
$695 O
. O

For O
the O
most O
part O
, O
the O
better O
the O
rewards O
, O
the O
more O
annual O
fees O
, O
” O
said O
David B-PER
Lord I-PER
, O
general O
manager O
at O
Credit.com B-ORG
. O

While O
some O
of O
those O
fees O
might O
seem O
high O
, O
they O
can O
be O
worth O
it O
if O
you O
know O
you O
will O
use O
all O
the O
benefits O
the O
card O
offers O
. O

“These O
are O
often O
travel O
cards O
with O
premium O
perks” O
said O
Rossman. B-PER

The O
annual O
fee O
might O
be O
well O
worth O
it O
if O
you’re O
going O
to O
make O
good O
use O
of O
the O
airport O
lounge O
, O
the O
free O
checked O
bags O
or O
other O
perks O
, O
but O
not O
if O
you O
rarely O
travel O
. O

Another O
common O
fee O
is O
the O
foreign O
transaction O
fee O
– O
which O
typically O
adds O
3% O
to O
the O
purchase O
price O
of O
products O
and O
services O
bought O
in O
other O
countries O

If O
you O
travel O
abroad O
often O
, O
you’ll O
want O
to O
avoid O
cards O
that O
charge O
such O
fees O
. O

Most O
cards O
will O
also O
charge O
late O
payment O
fees O
. O

Up O
to O
$30 O
for O
the O
first O
offense O
and O
up O
to O
$41 O
for O
subsequent O
offenses O
within O
six O
billing O
cycles,” O
said O
Rossman. B-PER

Another O
important O
fee O
to O
consider O
is O
a O
cash O
advance O
fee O
. O

But O
Rossman B-PER
advises O
against O
using O
a O
credit O
card O
to O
get O
cash O
. O

There’s O
a O
separate O
fee, O
plus O
interest O
starts O
accruing O
immediately O
at O
a O
higher O
rate O
than O
normal O
purchases. O

How O
high O
are O
the O
interest O
rates O
. O

While O
credit O
card O
interest O
rates O
can O
go O
as O
high O
as O
36% O
, O
the O
average O
credit O
card O
charges O
about O
17% O
, O
according O
to O
Bankrate B-ORG
. O

These O
fees O
can O
really O
add O
up O
if O
you O
don’t O
pay O
off O
your O
balance O
every O
month O
. O

For O
those O
who O
carry O
a O
balance O
, O
the O
accrued O
interest O
can O
easily O
cancel O
out O
any O
rewards O
the O
card O
offers O
. O

It O
doesn’t O
make O
sense O
to O
pursue O
1% O
, O
2% O
or O
even O
5% O
in O
cash O
back O
( O
or O
an O
equivalent O
amount O
of O
airline O
miles O
or O
hotel O
points O
) O
if O
you’re O
paying O
a O
high O
interest O
rate O
” O
said O
Rossman B-PER

But O
figuring O
out O
the O
interest O
rate O
might O
not O
be O
as O
simple O
as O
it O
sounds O

Cards O
often O
charge O
different O
rates O
on O
purchases O
versus O
balance O
transfers O
or O
cash O
advances O

And O
most O
credit O
card O
issuers O
offer O
variable O
rates O
, O
which O
means O
they O
can O
change O
over O
time O
. O

Many O
cards O
will O
also O
offer O
an O
introductory O
rate O
– O
some O
as O
low O
as O
0% O
– O
for O
a O
certain O
period O
of O
time O

But O
cardholders O
need O
to O
be O
aware O
that O
the O
rate O
can O
skyrocket O
when O
the O
period O
ends O

As O
long O
as O
you’re O
diligent O
about O
paying O
the O
card O
off O
before O
the O
introductory O
period O
expires O
, O
a O
0% O
rate O
on O
purchases O
can O
prove O
to O
be O
a O
big O
financial O
benefit O
. O

That’s O
especially O
true O
for O
people O
looking O
to O
make O
a O
few O
big O
purchases O
– O
like O
a O
vacation O
or O
wedding O
– O
early O
in O
the O
term O
but O
need O
a O
little O
more O
time O
to O
pay O
it O
off O

You O
can O
divide O
what O
you O
owe O
by O
the O
number O
of O
months O
remaining O
and O
try O
to O
stick O
to O
it O
, O
said O
Rossman B-PER
. O

I O
think O
this O
makes O
more O
sense O
than O
constantly O
making O
a O
series O
of O
purchases O
with O
the O
0% O
card O

Overall O
, O
when O
picking O
that O
new O
plastic O
, O
there O
is O
no O
such O
thing O
as O
one-size-fits-all O
. O

Instead, O
it’s O
about O
doing O
the O
research O
and O
finding O
what O
works O
best O
for O
you. O

The O
devil O
is O
in O
the O
details O
, O
review O
the O
fine O
print O
, O
” O
said O
Lord B-PER
. O

Four O
current O
and O
former O
Louisville B-LOC
police O
officers O
involved O
in O
the O
deadly O
raid O
on O
Breonna B-PER
Taylor’s I-PER
home O
– O
including O
detectives O
who O
worked O
on O
the O
search O
warrant O
and O
the O
ex-officer O
accused O
of O
firing O
blindly O
into O
her O
home O
– O
have O
been O
charged O
with O
civil O
rights O
violations O
and O
other O
counts O
, O
Attorney O
General O
Merrick B-PER
Garland I-PER
said O
Thursday O

The O
charges O
mark O
the O
first O
federal O
counts O
leveled O
against O
any O
of O
the O
officers O
involved O
in O
the O
botched O
March O
2020 O
raid O

In O
addition O
to O
civil O
rights O
offenses O
, O
federal O
authorities O
charged O
the O
four O
with O
unlawful O
conspiracies O
, O
unconstitutional O
use O
of O
force O
and O
obstruction O
, O
Garland B-PER
said O

Former O
Detective O
Joshua B-PER
Jaynes I-PER
, O
40 O
, O
Detective O
Kelly B-PER
Goodlett I-PER
and O
Sgt. O

Kyle B-PER
Meany I-PER
, O
35 O
, O
were O
charged O
with O
submitting O
a O
false O
affidavit O
to O
search O
Taylor’s B-PER
home O
ahead O
of O
the O
Louisville B-LOC
Metropolitan I-ORG
Police I-ORG
Department’s I-ORG
raid O
, O
and O
then O
working O
together O
to O
create O
a O
“false O
cover O
story O
in O
an O
attempt O
to O
escape O
responsibility O
for O
their O
roles O
in O
preparing O
the O
warrant O
affidavit O
that O
contained O
false O
information O
, O
according O
to O
court O
documents O
. O

Ex-detective O
Brett B-PER
Hankison I-PER
is O
alleged O
to O
have O
“willfully O
used O
unconstitutionally O
excessive O
force O
… O
when O
he O
fired O
his O
service O
weapon O
into O
Taylor’s B-PER
apartment O
through O
a O
covered O
window O
and O
covered O
glass O
door O
.” O

Hankison B-PER
, O
who O
fired O
10 O
shots O
into O
Taylor’s B-PER
home O
and O
was O
acquitted O
of O
state O
wanton O
endangerment O
charges O
earlier O
this O
year O
, O
has O
been O
indicted O
on O
two O
federal O
counts O
of O
deprivation O
of O
rights O
under O
color O
of O
law O
. O

Only O
Hankison B-PER
was O
charged O
at O
the O
state O
level O
. O

The O
death O
of O
26-year-old O
Taylor O
, O
an O
emergency O
room O
technician O
, O
along O
with O
that O
of O
George B-PER
Floyd I-PER
and O
others O
, O
sparked O
nationwide O
protests O
in O
2020 O
, O
leading O
to O
changes O
in O
policing O
policy O
and O
laws O
. O

Here’s O
a O
look O
at O
the O
raid O
, O
Taylor’s O
death O
and O
its O
aftermath O
. O

The O
botched O
raid O
On O
March O
12 O
, O
2020 O
, O
a O
Jefferson B-ORG
County I-ORG
Circuit I-ORG
Court I-ORG
judge O
approved O
five O
search O
warrants O
for O
locations O
linked O
to O
Taylor’s O
ex-boyfriend O
, O
a O
convicted O
felon O
suspected O
of O
supplying O
a O
local O
drug O
house O
. O

One O
of O
those O
locations O
was O
Taylor’s O
residence O
. O

In O
the O
early O
hours O
of O
March O
13 O
, O
Hankison B-PER
and O
other O
officers O
executed O
a O
warrant O
at O
Taylor’s B-PER
apartment O
. O

Taylor B-PER
was O
in O
bed O
with O
her O
boyfriend O
, O
Kenneth B-PER
Walker I-PER
III I-PER
, O
when O
the O
officers O
announced O
their O
presence O
and O
then O
battered O
down O
the O
front O
door O
. O

Taylor O
and O
Walker O
yelled O
to O
ask O
who O
was O
at O
the O
door O
but O
got O
no O
response O
, O
Walker O
said O
afterward O

Thinking O
they O
were O
intruders O
, O
Walker B-PER
grabbed O
a O
gun O
he O
legally O
owned O
and O
fired O
a O
shot O
when O
the O
officers O
broke O
through O
the O
door O
. O

That O
triggered O
a O
volley O
of O
fire O
from O
the O
officers O

Taylor, B-PER
who O
was O
standing O
in O
a O
hallway O
with O
Walker, B-PER
was O
shot O
multiple O
times. O

Walker O
was O
not O
injured O

Somebody O
kicked O
in O
the O
door O
and O
shot O
my O
girlfriend O
,” O
Walker B-PER
said O
in O
a O
911 O
call O
. O

Hankison B-PER
had O
been O
standing O
outside O
the O
apartment O
and O
is O
accused O
of O
blindly O
firing O
through O
a O
door O
and O
a O
window O

His O
bullets O
entered O
a O
neighboring O
apartment O
, O
where O
a O
pregnant O
woman O
, O
a O
man O
and O
a O
child O
were O
home O
, O
according O
to O
the O
state O
attorney O
general O
. O

Walker O
was O
at O
first O
charged O
with O
attempted O
murder O
of O
a O
police O
officer O
and O
first-degree O
assault O
– O
Sgt. O

Jonathan B-PER
Mattingly I-PER
was O
shot O
in O
the O
leg O
– O
but O
prosecutors O
later O
decided O
to O
drop O
the O
charges O
. O

None O
of O
the O
police O
officers O
at O
the O
raid O
were O
wearing O
body O
cameras O
, O
and O
there O
is O
no O
video O
of O
the O
night O
Taylor B-PER
bled O
to O
death O
in O
her O
hallway O
. O

Hankison O
was O
fired O
from O
the O
police O
department O
in O
late O
June O
2020 O

The O
two O
other O
officers O
who O
fired O
shots O
, O
Mattingly B-PER
and O
Detective O
Myles B-PER
Cosgrove I-PER
, O
were O
not O
indicted O
by O
the O
state O
or O
the O
federal O
government O
. O

Kentucky B-LOC
Attorney O
General O
Daniel B-PER
Cameron I-PER
has O
said O
they O
were O
justified O
in O
shooting O
in O
self-defense O
, O
because O
Taylor’s O
boyfriend O
fired O
first O
. O

No O
drugs O
were O
found O
in O
the O
apartment O
, O
and O
Taylor’s B-PER
family O
and O
their O
attorney O
have O
maintained O
she O
was O
not O
involved O
in O
her O
ex-boyfriend’s O
alleged O
drug O
deals O
. O

The O
protests O
Taylor’s O
death O
at O
first O
went O
largely O
unnoticed O
outside O
Louisville B-LOC
. O

CNN B-ORG
covered O
the O
story O
for O
the O
first O
time O
on O
May O
13 O
, O
2020 O
, O
about O
two O
weeks O
before O
Floyd B-PER
died O
. O

By O
the O
end O
of O
May O
, O
Walker’s O
distressed O
911 O
call O
from O
the O
night O
Taylor B-PER
died O
had O
been O
released O
, O
and O
Floyd B-PER
had O
died O
days O
earlier O
at O
the O
hands O
of O
police O
in O
Minneapolis B-LOC
. O

Protests O
In O
Louisville B-LOC
turned O
violent O
, O
with O
gunfire O
erupting O
during O
protests O
. O

Seven O
people O
were O
shot O
downtown O
overnight O
May O
28 O
. O

Louisville B-LOC
Mayor O
Greg B-PER
Fischer I-PER
said O
the O
shots O
were O
fired O
from O
within O
the O
crowd O
, O
not O
from O
the O
police O
. O

In O
July O
, O
protesters O
marched O
to O
Cameron’s B-PER
front O
lawn O
, O
and O
87 O
people O
were O
arrested O
for O
criminal O
trespass O
, O
among O
other O
charges O
. O

In O
September O
, O
protests O
began O
to O
take O
place O
nightly O
in O
Louisville B-LOC
after O
a O
grand O
jury O
didn’t O
charge O
the O
other O
police O
officers O
involved O
in O
Taylor’s B-PER
death O
, O
indicting O
only O
Hankison B-PER

By O
then O
, O
Taylor B-PER
’s O
name O
was O
known O
nationally O
and O
beyond O
, O
just O
as O
Floyd B-PER
’s O
was O
, O
and O
her O
death O
was O
a O
central O
part O
of O
the O
protests O
that O
rocked O
the O
country O
throughout O
much O
of O
2020 O
. O

Celebrities O
took O
up O
the O
subject O
of O
Taylor’s O
death O
, O
including O
NBA O
star O
LeBron B-PER
James I-PER
and O
Oprah B-PER
Winfrey I-PER
, O
who O
put O
Taylor O
on O
the O
cover O
of O
her O
magazine O
. O

The O
aftermath O
Those O
protests O
sparked O
a O
movement O
demanding O
a O
change O
in O
policing O
and O
even O
seeking O
to O
defund O
police O
departments O

Police O
and O
some O
witnesses O
gave O
conflicting O
reports O
on O
whether O
the O
officers O
announced O
themselves O
before O
battering O
down O
Taylor’s B-PER
door O
, O
but O
her O
death O
drew O
attention O
to O
no-knock O
search O
warrants O

The O
officer O
who O
rammed O
the O
door O
at O
Taylor’s B-PER
apartment O
testified O
at O
Hankison’s B-PER
state O
trial O
that O
police O
announced O
themselves O
four O
or O
five O
times O

In O
Louisville B-LOC
, O
the O
controversy O
led O
to O
the O
passing O
of O
“Breonna’s B-ORG
Law” I-ORG
in O
June O
2020 O
, O
which O
bans O
such O
warrants O
and O
requires O
officers O
to O
wear O
body O
cameras O
when O
carrying O
out O
search O
warrants O
. O

Almost O
a O
year O
later O
, O
in O
April O
2021 O
, O
the O
Kentucky B-LOC
state O
legislature O
passed O
a O
bill O
setting O
restrictions O
on O
no-knock O
warrants O
but O
did O
not O
outlaw O
them O
outright O
. O

In O
June O
2020 O
, O
the O
Louisville B-LOC
police O
chief O
was O
fired O
after O
it O
came O
to O
light O
officers O
involved O
in O
a O
fatal O
shooting O
during O
a O
protest O
were O
not O
wearing O
body O
cameras O
. O

In O
September O
2020 O
, O
the O
city O
of O
Louisville B-LOC
agreed O
to O
pay O
a O
historic O
$12 O
million O
in O
a O
settlement O
with O
Taylor’s O
family O
. O

It O
included O
an O
agreement O
for O
the O
city O
to O
introduce O
police O
reforms O

The O
settlement O
stipulated O
the O
city O
would O
establish O
a O
housing O
credit O
program O
as O
an O
incentive O
for O
officers O
to O
live O
in O
the O
areas O
they O
serve O
, O
use O
social O
workers O
to O
provide O
support O
on O
certain O
police O
runs O
and O
require O
commanders O
to O
review O
and O
approve O
search O
warrants O
before O
seeking O
judicial O
approval O
, O
among O
other O
changes O
. O

Justice O
for O
Breonna B-PER
means O
that O
we O
will O
continue O
to O
save O
lives O
in O
her O
honor O
, O
Tamika B-PER
Palmer I-PER
, O
Taylor’s O
mother O
, O
said O
at O
the O
time O
. O

No O
amount O
of O
money O
accomplishes O
that O
, O
but O
the O
police O
reform O
measures O
that O
we O
were O
able O
to O
get O
passed O
as O
a O
part O
of O
this O
settlement O
mean O
so O
much O
more O
to O
my O
family O
, O
our O
community O
, O
and O
to O
Breonna’s B-PER
legacy O
. O

In O
late O
June O
2020 O
, O
more O
than O
three O
months O
after O
Taylor’s B-PER
death O
, O
Hankison B-PER
was O
fired O
. O

Cosgrove B-PER
was O
fired O
in O
January O
2021 O
for O
use O
of O
deadly O
force O
for O
firing O
16 O
rounds O
into O
Taylor’s B-PER
home O
and O
failing O
to O
activate O
his O
body O
camera O
, O
according O
to O
a O
copy O
of O
his O
termination O
letter O
. O

Sgt. O

Mattingly O
retired O
in O
April O
2021 O

There’s O
nothing O
nice O
or O
dreamy O
about O
synthetic O
weed O
, O
sold O
under O
such O
catchy O
names O
as O
AK-47 O
, O
K2 O
, O
Spice O
, O
Scoobie O
Snacks O
, O
Mr. O
Nice O
Guy O
and O
24-Karat O
Dream O
. O

Sometimes O
packaged O
as O
e-juice O
for O
vaping O
or O
as O
edibles O
, O
most O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
are O
sold O
as O
dried O
plant O
materials O
sprayed O
with O
acetone O
, O
embalming O
fluid O
or O
other O
solvents O
laced O
with O
lab-made O
psychoactive O
substances O
. O

Between O
2010 O
and O
2015 O
, O
synthetic O
cannabis O
poisonings O
were O
on O
the O
rise O
, O
according O
to O
the O
ToxIC B-ORG
Case I-ORG
Registry I-ORG
, O
with O
more O
than O
42,000 O
cases O
of O
toxic O
exposure O
reported O
during O
that O
time O
. O

However O
, O
those O
numbers O
may O
now O
be O
declining O
in O
states O
in O
which O
the O
use O
of O
recreational O
marijuana O
is O
permitted O
, O
said O
Tracy B-PER
Klein I-PER
, O
assistant O
director O
for O
the O
Center B-ORG
for O
Cannabis B-ORG
Policy I-ORG
, O
Research I-ORG
and O
Outreach I-ORG
at O
Washington B-LOC
State I-LOC
University I-LOC
in O
Vancouver B-LOC
, O
Washington B-LOC
. O

She’s O
the O
lead O
author O
of O
a O
study O
that O
found O
calls O
to O
poison O
centers O
about O
synthetic O
cannabinoid O
fell O
by O
more O
than O
a O
third O
between O
2016 O
and O
2019 O
in O
states O
that O
have O
legalized O
marijuana O
for O
recreational O
use O
. O

These O
products O
are O
made O
in O
a O
powdered O
format O
and O
could O
be O
sprayed O
on O
or O
added O
to O
something O
that O
looks O
exactly O
like O
natural O
cannabis O

So, O
in O
a O
party O
situation, O
I O
could O
see O
that O
someone O
could O
use O
this O
unintentionally,” O
said O
Klein, B-PER
who O
is O
also O
an O
associate O
professor O
in O
the O
WSU B-ORG
College I-ORG
of O
Nursing. O

However O
, O
people O
may O
also O
use O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
“ O
to O
attempt O
to O
avoid O
positive O
drug O
screens O
performed O
as O
a O
condition O
of O
employment O
, O
in O
substance O
abuse O
treatment O
programs O
, O
or O
in O
the O
criminal O
justice O
system O
, O
” O
according O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Centers I-ORG
for O
Disease I-ORG
Control I-ORG
and O
Prevention I-ORG
. O

A O
deadly O
problem O
Marijuana O
copycats O
have O
sent O
thousands O
of O
people O
to O
emergency O
rooms O
over O
the O
past O
decade O

Some O
have O
even O
died O
, O
including O
a O
17-year-old O
boy O
“who O
suffered O
a O
cardiac O
arrest O
after O
reportedly O
taking O
a O
single O
‘hit’ O
of O
K2/Spice O
,” O
according O
to O
the O
CDC B-ORG
. O

There’s O
no O
way O
to O
know O
which O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
are O
actually O
in O
the O
purchased O
product O
or O
what O
else O
might O
be O
in O
the O
solvents O
used O
to O
soak O
the O
dried O
plants O
, O
experts O
say O
. O

In O
April O
2018 O
in O
Illinois B-LOC
, O
153 O
people O
fell O
ill O
and O
four O
died O
after O
using O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
laced O
with O
rat O
poison O
. O

Later O
that O
year O
in O
New B-LOC
Haven I-LOC
, O
Connecticut B-LOC
, O
a O
version O
of O
K2 O
sickened O
95 O
people O
in O
two O
days O
. O

They O
experienced O
symptoms O
such O
as O
nausea O
, O
vomiting O
, O
lethargy O
and O
a O
loss O
of O
consciousness O
. O

Officially O
known O
as O
“synthetic O
cannabinoid O
receptor O
agonists,” O
these O
artificial O
products O
are O
different O
from O
synthetically O
made O
cannabis O
products O
that O
have O
a O
medical O
use, O
Klein B-PER
said. O

They O
don’t O
show O
up O
on O
regular O
drug O
tests,” O
she O
said, O
“nor O
does O
the O
body O
recognize O
them O
in O
any O
way O
that O
has O
positive O
effects.” O

The O
study O
, O
published O
Tuesday O
in O
the O
Journal B-ORG
of O
Clinical I-ORG
Toxicology I-ORG
, O
analyzed O
data O
from O
the O
National B-ORG
Poison I-ORG
Data I-ORG
System I-ORG
between O
2016 O
and O
2019 O
. O

Researchers O
found O
there O
were O
7,600 O
calls O
related O
to O
synthetic O
cannabinoid O
use O
during O
those O
three O
years O

About O
65% O
of O
the O
calls O
to O
poisoning O
centers O
were O
for O
situations O
that O
required O
medical O
attention O
and O
61 O
people O
died O

Over O
half O
of O
those O
calls O
(56%) O
occurred O
in O
states O
with O
restrictive O
cannabis O
policies O
, O
the O
study O
found O
. O

Closer O
to O
a O
third O
(38.6%) O
occurred O
in O
states O
that O
allow O
medicinal O
use O
and O
5.5% O
occurred O
in O
“permissive” O
states O
, O
where O
recreational O
use O
is O
legal O
, O
according O
to O
the O
study O
. O

How O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
work O
Synthetic O
cannabinoids O
were O
first O
developed O
in O
the O
1980s O
as O
a O
way O
to O
study O
how O
tetrahydrocannabinol O
or O
THC O
, O
the O
psychoactive O
ingredient O
in O
cannabis O
, O
impacted O
the O
brain O
to O
produce O
a O
high O
, O
the O
CDC B-ORG
said O
. O

One O
particular O
synthetic O
cannabis O
was O
designed O
by O
a O
pharmaceutical O
company O
as O
a O
potential O
drug O
to O
ease O
pain O
, O
Klein B-PER
said O
. O

It O
was O
found O
to O
be O
so O
strong O
and O
so O
powerful O
, O
and O
have O
so O
many O
side O
effects O
, O
that O
it O
was O
not O
pursued O
. O

Today O
synthetics O
are O
mostly O
produced O
overseas O
and O
shipped O
to O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC

In O
fact O
, O
the O
first O
shipment O
“ O
recognized O
to O
contain O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
was O
seized O
at O
a O
U.S. O
border O
in O
2008 O
,” O
according O
to O
the O
CDC B-ORG
. O

It’s O
not O
just O
a O
US O
problem O

This O
has O
become O
an O
international O
problem O
,” O
said O
Klein B-PER
, O
pointing O
to O
data O
that O
lists O
at O
least O
320 O
different O
synthetic O
cannabinoids O
sold O
on O
the O
illegal O
market O
as O
of O
February O
2022 O
. O

And O
those O
are O
just O
the O
ones O
that O
have O
been O
reported O
and O
identified O
,” O
she O
added O
. O

While O
not O
the O
same O
as O
weed O
, O
synthetics O
do O
work O
on O
the O
same O
cannabinoid O
receptors O
as O
THC O
, O
but O
can O
be O
up O
to O
100 O
times O
more O
potent O
because O
of O
the O
way O
they O
bind O
with O
receptors O
in O
the O
brain O
, O
Klein B-PER
said O
. O

Exposure O
can O
cause O
mild O
to O
severe O
neurologic O
reactions O
, O
such O
as O
agitation O
and O
depression O
of O
the O
central O
nervous O
system O
, O
even O
to O
the O
point O
of O
coma O
. O

Other O
symptoms O
include O
“sleepiness O
, O
irritability O
, O
confusion O
, O
dizziness O
, O
incoordination O
, O
inability O
to O
concentrate O
, O
stroke O
, O
and O
seizures O
,” O
the O
CDC B-ORG
noted O
. O

Psychiatric O
symptoms O
include O
“hallucinations, O
delusions, O
psychosis, O
violent O
behavior, O
and O
suicidal O
thoughts,” O
the O
agency O
said. O

Other O
physical O
signs O
and O
symptoms O
, O
including O
tachypnea O
, O
tachycardia O
, O
hypertension O
, O
severe O
nausea O
and O
vomiting O
, O
chest O
pain O
and O
heart O
attack O
, O
rhabdomyolysis O
( O
breakdown O
of O
damaged O
muscle O
) O
, O
kidney O
failure O
, O
and O
death O
. O

There O
is O
no O
antidote O
for O
synthetic O
cannabinoid O
poisoning O
and O
long-term O
effects O
are O
unknown O
, O
the O
CDC B-ORG
stated O

Treatment O
is O
supportive O
, O
by O
using O
intravenous O
fluids O
, O
oxygen O
, O
and O
other O
airway O
protection O
and O
medications O
for O
agitation O
and O
combativeness O
. O

نانسي B-PER
بيلوسي I-PER
في O
تايوان B-LOC
.. O
الجيش O
الصيني O
يرفع O
"حالة O
التأهب O
القصوى" O
ويعلن O
عن O
عمليات O
عسكرية O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

US O
Marine O
Corps O
Lt. O

Gen. O
Michael B-PER
Langley I-PER
was O
promoted O
to O
the O
rank O
of O
general O
in O
a O
ceremony O
Saturday O
, O
becoming O
the O
first O
Black O
four-star O
general O
in O
the O
military O
branch’s O
246-year O
history O
. O

Langley B-PER
will O
take O
command O
of O
the O
US B-ORG
Africa I-ORG
Command I-ORG
, O
which O
oversees O
the O
nation’s O
military O
presence O
in O
Africa B-LOC
, O
in O
a O
change O
of O
command O
ceremony O
at O
its O
Germany B-LOC
headquarters O
on O
Monday O
. O

Speaking O
after O
the O
ceremony O
at O
Marine B-LOC
Barracks I-LOC
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
DC B-LOC
, O
Langley B-PER
said O
he O
was O
“humbled O
and O
honored O
for O
the O
opportunity O
to O
take O
on O
the O
stewardship O
of O
command O
of O
AFRICOM” O
as O
a O
four-star O
general O
. O

But O
the O
milestone O
and O
what O
it O
means O
to O
the O
Corps B-ORG
is O
quite O
essential O

Not O
just O
because O
the O
mark O
in O
history O
, O
but O
what O
it O
will O
affect O
going O
forward O
, O
especially O
for O
those O
younger O
across O
society O
that O
want O
to O
aspire O
and O
look O
at O
the O
Marine B-ORG
Corps I-ORG
as O
an O
opportunity O
, O
” O
he O
added O
. O

Langley O
was O
nominated O
by O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
for O
the O
promotion O
in O
June O

The O
US B-ORG
Senate I-ORG
confirmed O
his O
promotion O
to O
four-star O
general O
by O
a O
voice O
vote O
earlier O
this O
week O
. O

In O
remarks O
during O
Saturday’s O
ceremony O
, O
Langley B-PER
paid O
homage O
to O
“ O
those O
who O
have O
gone O
before O
, O
recognizing O
Frederick B-PER
C. O
Branch I-PER
, O
the O
first O
commissioned O
Black O
Marine O
, O
and O
the O
Montford B-LOC
Point I-LOC
Marines O
, O
the O
first O
African O
Americans O
to O
enlist O
in O
the O
Marines O
who O
trained O
at O
a O
segregated O
facility O
in O
Montford B-LOC
Point I-LOC
, O
North B-LOC
Carolina I-LOC
. O

He O
also O
spoke O
of O
the O
importance O
of O
diversity O
in O
the O
military O
to O
“maintain O
a O
decisive O
advantage O
over O
our O
strategic O
competitors.” O

The O
Marine B-ORG
Corps I-ORG
had O
refused O
to O
recruit O
African O
Americans O
and O
other O
minorities O
until O
a O
1941 O
executive O
order O
signed O
by O
President O
Franklin B-PER
D. I-PER
Roosevelt I-PER
that O
“forced O
the O
Corps, O
despite O
objections O
from O
its O
leadership,” O
to O
start O
recruiting O
Black O
Marines O
the O
following O
year. O

Born O
in O
Shreveport B-LOC
, O
Louisiana B-LOC
, O
Langley B-PER
graduated O
from O
the O
University B-ORG
of O
Texas B-LOC
at O
Arlington I-LOC
and O
has O
served O
with O
the O
Marine B-ORG
Corps I-ORG
since O
1985 O
. O

He O
has O
commanded O
at O
every O
level O
and O
served O
in O
multiple O
continents O
, O
being O
deployed O
to O
countries O
such O
as O
Japan B-LOC
and O
Afghanistan B-LOC
over O
the O
course O
of O
his O
career O
. O

He O
most O
recently O
served O
as O
commander O
of O
the O
US B-ORG
Marine I-ORG
Corps I-ORG
Forces I-ORG
Command I-ORG
and O
Marine B-ORG
Forces I-ORG
Northern I-ORG
Command I-ORG
and O
as O
commanding O
general O
of O
Fleet B-ORG
Marine I-ORG
Force I-ORG
Atlantic I-ORG

CNN’s O
Jacquelyne B-PER
Germain I-PER
and O
Ellie B-PER
Kaufman I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report. O

Editor’s O
Note: O
David B-PER
G. I-PER
Allan I-PER
is O
the O
editorial O
director O
for O
CNN B-ORG
Travel, I-ORG
Style, I-ORG
Science I-ORG
and O
Wellness. O

This O
essay O
is O
part O
of O
a O
column O
called O
The B-ORG
Wisdom I-ORG
Project I-ORG
, O
to O
which O
you O
can O
subscribe O
here O
. O

It O
has O
been O
my O
dream O
for O
years O
to O
host O
“Saturday B-ORG
Night I-ORG
Live.” I-ORG

Literally O

I’ve O
repeatedly O
had O
that O
dream O
, O
going O
back O
decades O
. O

I O
have O
traveled O
to O
space O
, O
back O
in O
time O
and O
turned O
into O
a O
superhero O
. O

I’ve O
been O
close O
friends O
with O
many O
celebrities O
. O

I’ve O
created O
new O
memories O
with O
friends O
and O
family O
, O
some O
deceased O
. O

I O
have O
committed O
terrible O
crimes O

And O
I’ve O
saved O
the O
day O
, O
repeatedly O
. O

Our O
sleeping O
mind O
is O
a O
private O
theater O
where O
you O
are O
the O
director O
and O
usually O
the O
star O
and O
there O
is O
no O
limit O
to O
the O
production O
budget O

Yes O
, O
some O
of O
them O
are O
boring O
( O
the O
majority O
of O
mine O
are O
about O
work O
) O
, O
but O
many O
are O
entertaining O
, O
incisive O
and O
occasionally O
problem-solving O
. O

That’s O
why O
you O
should O
consider O
turning O
a O
blank O
notebook O
into O
your O
first O
dream O
journal O

There O
is O
little O
scientific O
research O
into O
the O
benefits O
of O
dream O
journaling O
, O
but O
those O
who O
make O
it O
a O
practice O
find O
it O
useful O
or O
insightful O
at O
best O
, O
and O
interesting O
at O
the O
very O
least O
. O

Safely O
insane O
The O
first O
potential O
benefit O
of O
dream O
journaling O
is O
that O
it O
may O
lead O
to O
a O
creative O
breakthrough O

Your O
subconscious O
dreaming O
mind O
is O
by O
nature O
, O
more O
inventive O
. O

Your O
dreams O
jump O
around O
in O
time O
, O
make O
leaps O
in O
logic O
, O
accept O
contradictions O
and O
sometimes O
make O
no O
sense O
at O
all O
to O
our O
more O
conventional O
conscious O
mind O
. O

Dreaming O
permits O
each O
and O
every O
one O
of O
us O
to O
be O
quietly O
and O
safely O
insane O
every O
night O
of O
our O
lives” O
is O
how O
William B-PER
Dement I-PER
, O
founder O
of O
the O
Sleep B-ORG
Research I-ORG
Center I-ORG
at O
Stanford B-ORG
University I-ORG
, O
once O
put O
it O
. O

There O
are O
numerous O
anecdotes O
of O
creative O
and O
innovative O
people O
who O
found O
inspiration O
in O
dreams O
and O
nightmares O

James B-PER
Cameron I-PER
famously O
conjured O
the O
vision O
of O
a O
“Terminator” O
robot O
crawling O
after O
a O
woman O
; O
a O
dream O
that O
sparked O
a O
massive O
film O
franchise O
. O

E.B. O
White B-PER
came O
up O
with O
the O
character O
of O
Stuart O
Little B-PER
in O
a O
dream O

As O
did O
Mary B-PER
Shelley I-PER
of O
her O
monster O
in O
“Frankenstein.” O

Computer O
scientist O
Larry B-PER
Page I-PER
had O
a O
dream O
about O
downloading O
the O
entire O
internet O
and O
cataloging O
just O
the O
links O
before O
he O
did O
that O
with O
the O
company O
he O
helped O
start O
, O
Google B-ORG
. O

Paul B-PER
McCartney I-PER
got O
the O
inspiration O
to O
write O
“Let O
It O
Be” O
after O
his O
mother O
had O
said O
that O
phrase O
to O
him O
in O
a O
dream. O

The O
melody O
for O
“Yesterday” O
also O
came O
to O
him O
in O
a O
dream O
. O

I’m O
a O
great O
believer O
in O
dreams O
,” O
McCartney B-PER
said O
in O
a O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
Times B-ORG
Magazine I-ORG
interview O
. O

I’m O
a O
great O
rememberer O
of O
dreams O
. O

Inception O
In O
centuries O
past O
, O
people O
believed O
dreams O
were O
messages O
from O
the O
dead O
that O
contained O
clues O
for O
what O
the O
living O
should O
do O

Egyptian O
pharaohs O
believed O
gods O
sent O
messages O
to O
us O
in O
our O
dreams O
; O
they O
called O
them O
omina O
, O
the O
origin O
of O
the O
word O
omen O
. O

And O
the O
major O
faiths O
today O
contain O
stories O
in O
their O
sacred O
texts O
in O
which O
dreams O
are O
important O
riddles O
whose O
meaning O
must O
be O
worked O
out O

A O
more O
current O
theory O
about O
why O
we O
dream O
is O
that O
it O
helps O
sort O
, O
organize O
and O
process O
all O
the O
stimuli O
from O
our O
waking O
life O
, O
like O
clearing O
out O
cobwebs O
. O

But O
sometimes O
there’s O
silk O
to O
be O
made O
of O
the O
webs O
, O
when O
the O
answer O
to O
a O
problem O
you O
can’t O
solve O
in O
your O
waking O
life O
gets O
worked O
out O
in O
your O
more O
creative O
dreaming O
one O
. O

Dream O
solutions O
have O
the O
advantage O
of O
operating O
“ O
without O
the O
limits O
of O
time O
, O
logic O
, O
space O
or O
other O
real-world O
rules O
,” O
Dr. O
Allan B-PER
Peterkin I-PER
wrote O
in O
a O
guided O
dream O
journal O
published O
by O
National B-ORG
Geographic I-ORG
. O

Peterkin B-PER
is O
a O
professor O
of O
psychiatry O
and O
family O
medicine O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of O
Toronto I-LOC

There O
are O
historical O
examples O
of O
dream O
problem-solving O
, O
too O
. O

Elias B-PER
Howe I-PER
designed O
the O
modern O
sewing O
machine O
needle O
from O
a O
dream O
he O
had O
about O
cannibals O
waving O
spears O
at O
him O
, O
according O
to O
New B-LOC
England I-LOC
Historical B-ORG
Society I-ORG
. O

Jack B-PER
Nicklaus I-PER
dreamed O
about O
a O
new O
golf O
grip O
that O
improved O
his O
game O

Albert B-PER
Einstein I-PER
even O
traced O
the O
roots O
of O
his O
theory O
of O
relativity O
to O
a O
dream O
he O
had O
as O
a O
teen O
about O
traveling O
at O
the O
speed O
of O
light O

Sigmund B-PER
Freud I-PER
, O
who O
wrote O
the O
first O
scholarly O
research O
on O
interpreting O
dreams O
, O
thought O
they O
primarily O
reveal O
secrets O
and O
embarrassing O
moments O
from O
our O
past O
. O

But O
his O
mentee-turned-rival O
, O
Carl B-PER
Jung I-PER
, O
thought O
dreams O
tap O
into O
universal O
archetypes O
and O
contain O
clues O
from O
our O
subconscious O
life O
to O
help O
us O
find O
happiness O
and O
answers O
to O
problems O
. O

Another O
theory O
is O
that O
dreams O
act O
like O
a O
dress O
rehearsal O
for O
real O
life O
, O
a O
way O
to O
safely O
test O
out O
alternatives O
. O

That O
seems O
a O
likely O
explanation O
of O
nightmares O

Scary O
dreams O
originate O
in O
your O
brains’ O
amygdala O
, O
where O
intense O
negative O
emotions O
such O
as O
anger O
and O
fear O
reside O
, O
Peterkin B-PER
explained O

They O
are O
useful O
, O
according O
to O
researchers O
, O
because O
they O
can O
help O
train O
your O
brain O
to O
prepare O
for O
challenges O
and O
fears O
in O
your O
waking O
life O
. O

By O
the O
way O
, O
the O
word O
nightmare O
comes O
from O
an O
image O
that O
sounds O
like O
a O
nightmare O
itself O
: O
the O
Old B-LOC
English I-LOC
word O
for O
evil O
female O
spirits O
( O
maeres O
) O
believed O
to O
sit O
on O
your O
chest O
and O
suffocate O
you O
. O

‘The O
royal O
road’ O
Dreams O
are O
windows O
into O
your O
deepest O
self. O

By O
gazing O
into O
a O
cracked O
, O
fun O
house O
mirror O
of O
reality O
, O
it O
changes O
your O
perspective O
. O

And O
by O
writing O
them O
down O
and O
considering O
what O
they O
mean O
, O
you O
travel O
along O
“ O
the O
royal O
road O
,” O
as O
Freud B-PER
put O
it O
, O
leading O
to O
the O
knowledge O
of O
your O
mind’s O
unconscious O
. O

Trying O
to O
understand O
your O
dreams O
can O
become O
an O
important O
part O
of O
understanding O
yourself O
, O
your O
relationships O
, O
and O
your O
world O
, O
both O
inside O
and O
out O
, O
” O
Peterkin B-PER
wrote O
. O

Ellen B-PER
DeGeneres I-PER
came O
out O
publicly O
after O
having O
a O
dream O
about O
a O
bird O
flying O
out O
of O
its O
cage O
and O
setting O
itself O
free O

Brad B-PER
Pitt I-PER
said O
in O
a O
recent O
GQ B-ORG
interview O
that O
by O
studying O
his O
nightmares O
of O
being O
chased O
, O
trapped O
and O
stabbed O
he O
was O
able O
to O
understand O
and O
work O
through O
“deep O
scars” O
from O
childhood O
. O

No O
dream O
comes O
just O
to O
tell O
us O
what O
we O
already O
know O
. O

I O
’ve O
been O
paying O
attention O
to O
my O
dreams O
lately O
, O
wrote O
director O
and O
actor O
Sarah B-PER
Polley I-PER
in O
her O
new O
memoir O
, O
“Run O
Towards O
the O
Danger O
: O
” O

After O
20 O
years O
in O
psychoanalysis O
and O
psychotherapy O
I’m O
used O
to O
noticing O
them O

They’re O
smoke O
signals O
from O
the O
past O
, O
drawing O
my O
attention O
to O
burned O
out O
wreckage O
in O
a O
distant O
forest O
of O
the O
mind O
, O
packed O
and O
buried O
under O
years O
of O
debris O
, O
still O
smoldering O
. O

But O
lately O
I’ve O
also O
started O
to O
see O
dreams O
as O
guides O
, O
pointing O
the O
way O
forward O
. O

‘Poor O
man’s O
opera’ O
One O
more O
benefit O
of O
recounting O
and O
recording O
your O
dreams O
is O
simply O
escape. O

And O
who O
doesn’t O
need O
a O
vacation O
from O
life O
from O
time O
to O
time O
? O

In O
your O
dreams O
you O
can O
visit O
the O
past O
or O
future O
, O
go O
anywhere O
in O
the O
world O
or O
off O
it O
, O
and O
fly O
there O
with O
or O
without O
a O
plane O
. O

As O
Kahlil B-PER
Gibran I-PER
put O
it O
more O
poetically O
, O
“permit O
us O
to O
surrender O
ourselves O
to O
slumber O
and O
perhaps O
the O
beautiful O
bride O
of O
dreams O
will O
carry O
our O
souls O
into O
a O
world O
cleaner O
than O
this O
one O
. O
” O

The O
word O
dream O
comes O
from O
the O
Old O
English O
word O
for O
“joy, O
noise O
or O
music.” O

And O
there O
is O
joy O
in O
recording O
the O
music O
or O
deciphering O
the O
noise O

Bed O
is O
the O
poor O
man’s O
opera O
, O
an O
old O
Italian B-LOC
saying O
goes O
. O

And O
there O
is O
a O
new O
performance O
daily O

Dreams O
can O
be O
“an O
incredible O
virtual O
reality O
model O
of O
the O
world,” O
Peterkin B-PER
wrote, O
“updated O
with O
cool O
new O
content O
several O
times O
each O
night.” O

In O
some O
of O
my O
wildest O
dreams O
, O
I O
married O
Nicole B-PER
Kidman I-PER
, O
joined O
Laird B-PER
Hamilton I-PER
’s O
surfing O
crew O
, O
beat O
LL O
Cool B-PER
J I-PER
in O
a O
rap O
battle O
and O
drove O
Speed B-PER
Racer I-PER
’s O
car O
, O
the O
Mach O
5 O
. O

In O
still O
others O
, O
Sarah B-PER
Silverman I-PER
was O
my O
therapist O
, O
Ally B-PER
Sheedy I-PER
and O
I O
had O
a O
fling O
while O
we O
made O
an O
’80s O
movie O
together O
, O
and O
I O
played O
Han B-PER
Solo I-PER
in O
a O
version O
of O
“Hamlet,” O
using O
a O
script O
made O
out O
of O
graham O
crackers O
. O

I O
went O
to O
high O
school O
in O
the O
1800s O
, O
with O
Hulk B-PER
Hogan I-PER
, O
at O
which O
time O
I O
attended O
Gen. O
Robert B-PER
E. I-PER
Lee’s I-PER
funeral O
. O

And O
I O
was O
the O
Batman O

I O
can O
remember O
these O
dreams O
and O
hundreds O
more O
because O
I O
have O
been O
writing O
them O
down O
since O
high O
school O

It’s O
the O
simple O
act O
of O
recording O
dreams O
that O
keeps O
them O
from O
evaporating O
in O
the O
sunlight O
of O
day O

Total O
recall O
Of O
the O
many O
dream-themed O
movies O
, O
my O
two O
favorites O
are O
Christopher B-PER
Nolan’s I-PER
“Inception” O
and O
the O
lesser-known O
1991 O
Wim B-PER
Wenders’ I-PER
film O
, O
“Until O
the O
End O
of O
the O
World,” O
with O
William B-PER
Hurt I-PER
, O
Sam B-PER
Neill I-PER
and O
Max B-PER
von I-PER
Sydow I-PER
. O

As O
a O
subplot O
in O
“Until,” O
the O
main O
characters O
find O
a O
way O
to O
video-record O
their O
dreams O
and O
subsequently O
become O
narcissistically O
addicted O
to O
watching O
them O
( O
to O
the O
point O
of O
madness O
) O

You’re O
now O
looking O
at O
the O
human O
soul O
, O
singing O
to O
itself O
. O

To O
its O
own O
God O
! O

von O
Sydow B-PER
’s O
character O
says O

As O
fun O
as O
that O
sounds O
, O
present-day O
technology O
has O
not O
advanced O
us O
to O
the O
point O
of O
DVRing O
our O
dreams O
( O
yet O
) O

The O
closest O
thing O
available O
is O
writing O
them O
down O
. O

There’s O
little O
you O
need O
to O
get O
started O

Find O
a O
dream O
journal O
app O
or O
designate O
a O
notebook O
to O
keep O
next O
to O
your O
bed O

And O
the O
next O
time O
you O
recall O
a O
dream O
, O
even O
a O
hazy O
, O
half-remembered O
one O
, O
write O
it O
down O
. O

Even O
if O
it’s O
boring O
and O
doesn’t O
seem O
worth O
remembering O
, O
write O
it O
down O
. O

The O
more O
you O
get O
in O
the O
habit O
of O
recording O
them O
, O
the O
better O
your O
recall O
will O
get O
. O

I O
also O
leave O
a O
scrap O
of O
paper O
out O
in O
case O
I O
make O
some O
scribbled O
notes O
of O
key O
words O
and O
elements O
in O
the O
middle O
of O
the O
night O

Even O
a O
single O
detail O
can O
bring O
back O
the O
memory O
of O
an O
entire O
dream O

Telling O
someone O
your O
dream O
soon O
after O
you O
wake O
up O
can O
also O
help O
hold O
on O
to O
it O
until O
you O
write O
it O
down O

My O
dream O
journals O
have O
evolved O
over O
the O
years O
to O
include O
headlines O
for O
them O
, O
tracking O
themes O
, O
people O
and O
locations O
, O
as O
well O
as O
noting O
how O
many O
were O
“good” O
“bad” O
or O
“neutral/in O
between.” O

I O
do O
that O
to O
look O
for O
trends O
, O
but O
don’t O
make O
the O
bar O
too O
high O
for O
yourself O
, O
especially O
when O
you’re O
starting O
. O

I O
also O
, O
on O
occasion O
, O
will O
write O
a O
note O
at O
the O
end O
of O
the O
dream O
if O
I O
feel O
I O
have O
some O
insight O
into O
its O
meaning O
. O

I O
may O
instantly O
recognize O
that O
a O
dream O
about O
being O
lost O
in O
a O
city B-LOC
is O
really O
about O
losing O
a O
work O
file O
, O
for O
example O
. O

Dream O
dictionaries O
compile O
mythology O
, O
psychology O
and O
cultural O
symbolism O
and O
can O
be O
interesting O
to O
look O
up O
reoccurring O
themes O
in O
, O
even O
if O
there O
is O
little O
that O
is O
scientific O
about O
them O
, O
except O
in O
a O
Jungian B-PER
collective O
, O
unconscious O
way O
. O

Just O
remember O
always O
to O
interpret O
a O
dream O
through O
your O
personal O
experience O
. O

For O
example O
, O
a O
dream O
dictionary O
may O
suggest O
a O
dog O
in O
a O
dream O
means O
loyalty O
. O

But O
if O
you’re O
scared O
of O
dogs O
, O
it O
more O
likely O
represents O
something O
else O
you’re O
afraid O
of O
. O

Or O
if O
your O
mom O
owns O
five O
dogs O
, O
your O
dream O
dog O
may O
be O
standing O
in O
for O
her O
. O

As O
the O
great O
myth O
expert O
Joseph B-PER
Campbell I-PER
put O
it O
, O
“Myths O
are O
public O
dreams O
, O
dreams O
are O
private O
myths O
. O
” O

Kansas B-LOC
voters O
handed O
abortion-rights O
advocates O
a O
massive O
victory O
Tuesday O
, O
surging O
to O
the O
polls O
to O
defeat O
a O
measure O
that O
would O
have O
allowed O
the O
GOP-led O
legislature O
to O
impose O
new O
restrictions O
. O

The O
vote O
in O
Kansas B-LOC
was O
one O
of O
the O
first O
tests O
of O
the O
potency O
of O
abortion O
rights O
at O
the O
ballot O
box O
since O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court’s I-ORG
decision O
to O
reverse O
Roe B-PER
v. O
Wade I-PER
and O
end O
the O
federal O
protection O
of O
abortion O
access O

Catch O
up O
on O
the O
night’s O
news O
here O
Meanwhile O
, O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
, O
one O
of O
the O
10 O
House O
Republicans O
who O
voted O
to O
impeach O
Trump B-PER
was O
ousted O
, O
while O
the O
matchup O
was O
set O
for O
what O
will O
be O
one O
of O
the O
key O
gubernatorial O
races O
this O
fall O
. O

And O
in O
Missouri B-LOC
, O
the O
political O
comeback O
of O
a O
former O
governor O
was O
shut O
down O
. O

In O
Arizona B-LOC
, O
local O
elections O
officials O
were O
still O
counting O
votes O
, O
but O
some O
of O
the O
slate O
of O
statewide O
candidates O
who O
were O
endorsed O
by O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
and O
promoted O
his O
lies O
about O
election O
fraud O
won O
their O
Republican O
primaries O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O

Here O
are O
six O
takeaways O
from O
Tuesday O
night’s O
primaries O
: O
Kansas B-LOC
maintains O
constitutional O
right O
to O
abortion O
Kansas B-LOC
voters O
sent O
a O
dramatic O
message O
on O
Tuesday O
, O
opting O
to O
maintain O
the O
right O
to O
an O
abortion O
in O
their O
state’s O
constitution O
just O
weeks O
after O
the O
US B-ORG
Supreme I-ORG
Court I-ORG
decided O
to O
overturn O
Roe B-PER
v. O
Wade I-PER
. O

Polls O
have O
long O
shown O
that O
voters O
overwhelmingly O
support O
protecting O
abortions O
rights O

But O
the O
win O
for O
the O
“no” O
vote O
in O
Kansas B-LOC
is O
proof O
of O
that O
and O
signals O
that O
the O
Supreme B-ORG
Court I-ORG
decision O
has O
further O
angered O
voters O
and O
possibly O
shifted O
the O
politics O
of O
the O
issue O
ahead O
of O
the O
November B-LOC
elections O

The O
“no” O
leaves O
the O
state O
constitution O
unchanged O

While O
lawmakers O
in O
the O
state O
can O
still O
try O
to O
pass O
restrictive O
abortion O
laws O
, O
courts O
in O
Kansas B-LOC
have O
recognized O
a O
right O
to O
abortion O
under O
the O
state O
constitution O
. O

The O
biggest O
warning O
to O
Republicans B-ORG
, O
many O
of O
whom O
have O
trumpeted O
the O
overturning O
of O
Roe O
and O
backed O
pushes O
to O
pass O
stricter O
abortions O
laws O
, O
is O
perhaps O
the O
turnout O
in O
Kansas B-LOC
. O

With O
78% O
of O
the O
vote O
in O
on O
Tuesday O
night O
, O
nearly O
700,000 O
people O
have O
cast O
ballots O
in O
the O
primary O
, O
a O
figure O
that O
already O
dwarfs O
the O
turnout O
in O
the O
2020 O
presidential O
primary O
election O
. O

This O
is O
further O
proof O
of O
what O
poll O
after O
poll O
has O
told O
us O
: O
Americans O
support O
abortion O
rights O
, O
said O
Christina B-PER
Reynolds I-PER
, O
a O
top O
operative O
for O
Emily’s B-ORG
List I-ORG
, O
an O
organization O
that O
looks O
to O
elect O
women O
who O
support O
abortion O
rights O
. O

They O
believe O
we O
should O
be O
able O
to O
make O
our O
own O
health O
care O
decisions O
, O
and O
they O
will O
vote O
accordingly O
, O
even O
in O
the O
face O
of O
misleading O
campaigns O
. O

A O
member O
of O
the O
‘impeachment O
10’ O
is O
defeated O
Rep. O
Peter B-PER
Meijer I-PER
became O
the O
second O
of O
the O
10 O
Republicans O
who O
voted O
to O
impeach O
Trump O
to O
be O
ousted O
in O
a O
primary O
Tuesday O
, O
losing O
to O
Trump-endorsed O
conservative O
challenger O
John B-PER
Gibbs I-PER
, O
CNN B-ORG
projected O

Democrats O
played O
a O
role O
in O
boosting O
Gibbs B-PER
– O
a O
calculated O
decision O
that O
has O
become O
a O
flashpoint O
, O
angering O
some O
Democrats O
and O
anti-Trump O
Republicans O
. O

Meijer B-ORG
, O
a O
freshman O
, O
voted O
to O
impeach O
Trump B-PER
just O
days O
after O
taking O
office O
, O
after O
the O
insurrection O
of O
January B-LOC
6 O
, O
2021 O
. O

Gibbs O
, O
meanwhile O
, O
backed O
Trump’s B-PER
lies O
about O
widespread O
fraud O
in O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O

Meijer’s O
loss O
means O
the O
Grand B-LOC
Rapids-based I-LOC
3rd O
District O
seat O
will O
be O
one O
of O
the O
most O
competitive O
House O
contests O
in O
November’s O
midterm O
elections O

The O
Democratic B-ORG
Congressional I-ORG
Campaign I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
, O
eyeing O
the O
seat O
as O
a O
possible O
pick-up O
opportunity O
, O
spent O
more O
than O
$300,000 O
on O
television O
ads O
seeking O
to O
bolster O
Gibbs B-PER
with O
pro-Trump O
GOP O
primary O
voters O
by O
portraying O
him O
as O
a O
Trump-aligned O
conservative O
. O

In O
Washington B-LOC
, O
two O
more O
Republicans O
who O
voted O
to O
impeach O
Trump B-PER
, O
Reps O
. O

Jaime B-PER
Herrera I-PER
Beutler I-PER
and O
Dan B-PER
Newhouse I-PER
, O
were O
attempting O
to O
survive O
their O
own O
primaries O
. O

The O
state’s O
open O
, O
non-partisan O
primary O
system O
in O
which O
the O
top O
two O
finishers O
regardless O
of O
party O
advance O
to O
November’s O
general O
election O
made O
them O
more O
difficult O
targets O
for O
Trump B-PER
and O
his O
supporters O
. O

Unknowns O
in O
Arizona B-LOC
Arizona’s B-LOC
race O
for O
the O
Republican O
nomination O
for O
governor O
could O
depend O
on O
whether O
Trump’s B-PER
supporters O
turned O
out O
in O
force O
on O
election O
day O
in O
a O
state O
that O
conducts O
its O
contests O
largely O
by O
mail O

Karrin B-PER
Taylor I-PER
Robson I-PER
, O
a O
former O
member O
of O
the O
Arizona B-LOC
Board O
of O
Regents O
who O
is O
backed O
by O
former O
Vice O
President O
Mike B-PER
Pence I-PER
and O
outgoing O
Gov. O
Doug B-PER
Ducey I-PER
, O
led O
former O
television O
journalist O
Kari B-PER
Lake I-PER
, O
a O
Trump-endorsed O
election O
denier O
, O
in O
the O
early O
returns O
Wednesday O
morning O
. O

But O
the O
early O
results O
were O
largely O
mail-in O
ballots O

Votes O
cast O
on O
election O
day O
were O
expected O
to O
favor O
Lake B-LOC
– O
a O
result O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
years-long O
effort O
to O
undermine O
faith O
in O
mail-in O
voting O

The O
Arizona B-LOC
gubernatorial O
primary O
was O
the O
most O
significant O
contest O
in O
a O
set O
of O
primaries O
that O
tested O
Trump’s B-PER
influence O
over O
the O
GOP B-ORG

If O
Trump’s B-PER
slate O
of O
statewide O
candidates O
in O
Arizona B-LOC
advances O
to O
the O
general O
election O
, O
they’d O
be O
positioned O
to O
take O
over O
the O
election O
machinery O
of O
one O
of O
the O
nation’s O
most O
important O
presidential O
battleground O
states O
if O
they O
win O
in O
November O
. O

Blake B-PER
Masters I-PER
, O
the O
venture O
capitalist O
endorsed O
by O
Trump B-PER
and O
backed O
by O
millions O
in O
spending O
from O
GOP O
megadonor O
Peter B-PER
Thiel I-PER
, O
won O
the O
state’s O
GOP O
primary O
to O
take O
on O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Mark B-PER
Kelly I-PER
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O

State O
Rep. O
Mark B-PER
Finchem I-PER
, O
a O
Trump-endorsed O
“Stop O
the O
Steal” O
activist O
who O
has O
said O
the O
state O
legislature O
should O
be O
able O
to O
overturn O
voters’ O
will O
in O
presidential O
elections O
, O
won O
the O
GOP O
primary O
for O
secretary O
of O
state O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O

Democrats O
saw O
a O
tight O
race O
between O
Maricopa B-LOC
County I-LOC
recorder O
Adrian B-PER
Fontes I-PER
and O
state O
Rep. O
Reginald B-PER
Bolding I-PER
. O

And O
in O
the O
attorney O
general’s O
race O
, O
Trump’s B-PER
preferred O
candidate O
, O
election O
denier O
Abraham B-PER
Hamadeh I-PER
, O
won O
the O
Republican O
nomination O
, O
CNN B-ORG
projects O
. O

There O
was O
also O
one O
person O
who O
had O
defied O
Trump B-PER
and O
his O
election O
lies O
ousted O
on O
Tuesday O
, O
according O
to O
a O
CNN B-ORG
projection O
: O
Rusty B-PER
Bowers I-PER
, O
the O
Arizona B-LOC
House O
speaker O
. O

Bowers O
testified O
in O
June O
about O
the O
pressure O
he O
faced O
to O
overturn O
the O
state’s O
2020 O
election O
results O
from O
Trump B-PER
and O
others O

In O
return O
, O
he O
was O
censured O
by O
his O
party O
, O
called O
“unfit O
to O
serve” O
– O
and O
now O
has O
lost O
his O
primary O
for O
a O
state O
Senate O
seat O
. O

Greitens’ O
attempted O
comeback O
falls O
flat O
Republicans O
in O
Missouri B-LOC
breathed O
a O
sigh O
of O
relief O
after O
state O
Attorney O
General O
Eric B-PER
Schmitt I-PER
won O
the O
wide-open O
Senate O
primary O
, O
according O
to O
a O
CNN B-ORG
projection O

Perhaps O
more O
significant O
than O
who O
won O
, O
though O
, O
in O
the O
deep-red O
state O
, O
is O
who O
lost O
: O
disgraced O
former O
Gov. O
Eric B-PER
Greitens I-PER
, O
who O
was O
attempting O
a O
political O
comeback O
. O

Greitens B-PER
resigned O
in O
2018 O
amid O
a O
sex O
scandal O
and O
accusation O
of O
campaign O
misconduct O
, O
and O
subsequently O
faced O
abuse O
allegations O
from O
his O
ex-wife O
, O
which O
he O
has O
denied O
Schmitt B-PER
, O
the O
attorney O
general O
, O
emerged O
from O
a O
crowded O
field O
that O
included O
two O
members O
of O
Congress O
, O
Reps O
. O

Vicky B-PER
Hartzler I-PER
and O
Billy B-PER
Long I-PER
. O

Trump B-PER
stayed O
out O
of O
the O
race O
, O
issuing O
a O
tongue-in-cheek O
statement O
supporting O
“ O
Eric O
” O
on O
the O
eve O
of O
the O
primary O
– O
leaving O
it O
up O
to O
voters’ O
interpretation O
whether O
that O
meant O
Schmitt B-PER
or O
Greitens B-PER
. O

Dixon O
victory O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
governor’s O
race O
sets O
up O
referendum O
on O
Covid O
policies O
Tudor B-PER
Dixon I-PER
, O
the O
conservative O
commentator O
endorsed O
by O
Trump B-PER
in O
the O
final O
days O
of O
the O
race O
and O
backed O
by O
large O
factions O
of O
the O
Michigan B-LOC
Republican O
establishment O
, O
won O
the O
state’s O
GOP O
primary O
to O
take O
on O
Democratic O
Gov O
. O
Gretchen B-PER
Whitmer I-PER
, O
CNN B-ORG
projected O

The O
clash O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
could O
be O
one O
of O
the O
nation’s O
most O
competitive O
governor’s O
races O
. O

Whitmer B-PER
has O
cast O
herself O
as O
a O
bulwark O
for O
abortion O
rights O
in O
a O
state O
where O
Republicans B-ORG
have O
sought O
to O
enforce O
a O
1931 O
law O
that O
would O
impose O
a O
near-total O
ban O
on O
abortion O

Dixon B-PER
, O
meanwhile O
, O
framed O
the O
race O
in O
her O
victory O
speech O
Tuesday O
night O
as O
a O
referendum O
on O
restrictions O
Whitmer B-PER
imposed O
during O
the O
Covid-19 O
pandemic O
. O

Dixon O
, O
a O
mother O
of O
four O
who O
is O
backed O
by O
former O
Education O
Secretary O
Betsy B-PER
DeVos I-PER
’s O
family O
, O
is O
also O
an O
advocate O
of O
school O
choice O
— O
potentially O
positioning O
education O
as O
a O
marquee O
issue O
in O
November’s O
midterm O
election O
. O

Progressives O
suffer O
another O
defeat O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
Rep. O
Haley B-PER
Stevens’ I-PER
projected O
Democratic O
primary O
victory O
in O
Michigan’s B-LOC
newly O
drawn O
11th O
Congressional O
District O
over O
fellow O
Rep. O
Andy B-PER
Levin I-PER
marks O
another O
blow O
against O
progressives O
in O
what O
has O
been O
a O
mostly O
disappointing O
primary O
season O

It’s O
also O
a O
resounding O
victory O
for O
the O
American B-LOC
Israel I-LOC
Public B-ORG
Affairs I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
, O
or O
AIPAC B-ORG
, O
and O
its O
super O
PAC O
, O
United B-ORG
Democracy I-ORG
Project I-ORG
, O
which O
has O
spent O
millions O
backing O
moderate O
, O
more O
staunchly O
pro-Israel O
candidates O
in O
Democratic B-ORG
primaries O
. O

Stevens O
and O
Levin O
are O
both O
supportive O
of O
Israel B-LOC
, O
but O
Levin O
– O
who O
is O
Jewish O
– O
has O
been O
more O
willing O
to O
criticize O
its O
government’s O
treatment O
of O
Palestinians O
and O
is O
the O
lead O
sponsor O
of O
the O
Two-State O
Solution O
Act O
. O

Progressive O
Democrats B-ORG
, O
frequently O
targeted O
by O
AIPAC B-ORG
spending O
this O
primary O
season O
, O
have O
fumed O
at O
fellow O
Democrats B-ORG
for O
accepting O
or O
courting O
support O
from O
the O
group O
, O
which O
has O
also O
contributed O
to O
Republican O
election O
deniers O
. O

AIPAC B-ORG
has O
defended O
the O
practice O
, O
arguing O
that O
its O
policy O
goals O
need O
bipartisan O
support O
. O

J B-ORG
Street I-ORG
, O
a O
liberal O
pro-Israel O
group O
that O
has O
clashed O
with O
AIPAC B-ORG
, O
tried O
to O
boost O
Levin B-PER
with O
a O
$700,000 O
July O
ad O
buy O
, O
but O
that O
sum O
paled O
in O
comparison O
to O
the O
millions O
bundled O
by O
AIPAC B-ORG
and O
more O
than O
$4 O
million O
spend O
by O
UDP B-ORG
. O

This O
is O
the O
weekly O
edition O
of O
CNN B-ORG
’s O
coronavirus O
newsletter O

Look O
out O
for O
your O
roundup O
every O
Wednesday O

If O
you O
haven’t O
subscribed O
yet O
, O
sign O
up O
here O
. O

If O
we’ve O
learned O
anything O
over O
the O
past O
two O
and O
a O
half O
years O
, O
it’s O
that O
Covid-19 O
is O
one O
strange O
disease O
. O

The O
latest O
case O
in O
point: O
the O
coronavirus O
rebound. O

The O
condition O
grabbed O
international O
attention O
last O
week O
when O
US O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
tested O
positive O
for O
the O
virus O
six O
days O
after O
testing O
negative O
following O
his O
first O
bout O
of O
the O
illness O

The O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
said O
Biden B-PER
, O
who O
is O
back O
in O
isolation O
, O
was O
experiencing O
a O
bit O
of O
a O
“loose O
cough” O
but O
did O
not O
have O
a O
fever O
and O
his O
lungs O
were O
“clear.” O

The O
President O
tested O
positive O
again O
after O
being O
treated O
with O
the O
antiviral O
Paxlovid O
. O

White B-ORG
House I-ORG
officials O
had O
previously O
suggested O
a O
rebound O
case O
of O
Covid O
was O
unlikely O
, O
based O
on O
reports O
of O
cases O
around O
the O
country O
, O
but O
Biden’s B-PER
doctors O
continued O
to O
monitor O
his O
health O
and O
test O
him O
. O

Dr. O
Ashish B-PER
Jha I-PER
, O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
Covid O
response O
coordinator O
, O
said O
clinical O
data O
shows O
the O
rate O
of O
rebound O
infections O
is O
low O
and O
noted O
that O
even O
those O
who O
suffer O
them O
are O
still O
generally O
protected O
from O
serious O
illness O
. O

Biden B-PER
is O
not O
the O
only O
high-profile O
patient O
to O
develop O
the O
condition O

Unlike O
Biden’s B-PER
, O
his O
symptoms O
got O
worse O
when O
they O
returned O
after O
treatment O
with O
Paxlovid O
, O
and O
his O
doctors O
prescribed O
another O
course O
of O
the O
drug O
. O

Experts O
have O
been O
calling O
for O
more O
systematic O
research O
into O
the O
instances O
of O
rebound O
to O
understand O
who O
is O
most O
at O
risk O
and O
whether O
the O
standard O
five-day O
course O
of O
Paxlovid O
should O
be O
lengthened O
to O
prevent O
it O

Studies O
have O
shown O
that O
people O
can O
pass O
the O
infection O
to O
others O
during O
a O
rebound O
, O
which O
is O
another O
reason O
to O
try O
to O
understand O
it O
better O
. O

The O
United B-LOC
States’ I-LOC
Centers B-ORG
for O
Disease I-ORG
Control I-ORG
and O
Prevention I-ORG
( O
CDC O
) O
issued O
a O
health O
alert O
to O
doctors O
in O
May O
about O
the O
potential O
for O
Covid-19 O
rebound O
, O
saying O
symptoms O
sometimes O
come O
back O
, O
and O
that O
may O
just O
be O
how O
the O
infection O
plays O
out O
in O
some O
people O
, O
regardless O
of O
whether O
they’re O
vaccinated O
or O
treated O
with O
medications O
like O
Paxlovid O
. O

The O
CDC B-ORG
said O
most O
cases O
of O
rebound O
involve O
mild O
disease O
and O
that O
Paxlovid B-ORG
“continues O
to O
be O
recommended O
for O
early-stage O
treatment O
of O
mild O
to O
moderate O
COVID-19 O
among O
persons O
at O
high O
risk O
for O
progression O
to O
severe O
disease O
.” O

Pfizer B-ORG
, O
the O
company O
that O
makes O
Paxlovid O
, O
has O
said O
its O
studies O
showed O
rebounds O
were O
rare O
, O
and O
that O
they O
happened O
in O
both O
people O
who O
took O
the O
drug O
and O
those O
who O
took O
a O
placebo O
pill O
. O

Because O
investigators O
noted O
the O
phenomenon O
in O
both O
groups O
, O
the O
company O
doesn’t O
believe O
it O
is O
tied O
to O
the O
medication O
. O

YOU O
ASKED O

WE O
ANSWERED O

Q: O
How O
does O
Paxlovid O
work? O

A: O
Considered O
a O
game-changer O
when O
it O
was O
authorized O
in O
December O
because O
of O
its O
strong O
performance O
in O
lowering O
the O
risk O
of O
severe O
Covid-19 O
, O
Paxlovid O
– O
in O
combination O
with O
vaccines O
and O
boosters O
– O
is O
thought O
to O
be O
one O
of O
the O
best O
ways O
to O
protect O
people O
at O
high O
risk O
for O
severe O
illness O
. O

The O
drug O
suppresses O
the O
coronavirus O
, O
blocking O
an O
enzyme O
that O
helps O
it O
reproduce O
inside O
the O
body O
. O

As O
with O
all O
antivirals O
, O
the O
treatment O
is O
thought O
to O
work O
best O
if O
started O
within O
five O
days O
of O
the O
first O
symptoms O
appearing O
. O

Clinical O
trials O
of O
Paxlovid B-ORG
showed O
that O
it O
reduced O
the O
risk O
of O
hospitalization O
and O
death O
by O
88% O
when O
given O
within O
five O
days O
of O
the O
start O
of O
symptoms O

Send O
your O
questions O
here O

Are O
you O
a O
health O
care O
worker O
fighting O
Covid-19 O
? O

Message O
us O
on O
WhatsApp B-ORG
about O
the O
challenges O
you’re O
facing O
: O
+1 O
347-322-0415 O
. O

READS O
OF O
THE O
WEEK O
Most O
US B-LOC
public O
schools O
plan O
to O
keep O
masks O
optional O
for O
start O
of O
classes O
Students O
are O
heading O
to O
another O
school O
year O
amid O
the O
Covid-19 O
pandemic O
, O
but O
this O
time O
, O
there O
seem O
to O
be O
fewer O
discussions O
and O
less O
fretting O
about O
masks O
and O
other O
mitigation O
measures O
– O
despite O
a O
rise O
in O
infections O
across O
the O
country O

Most O
of O
the O
largest O
public O
school O
districts O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
are O
not O
requiring O
masks O
for O
the O
new O
school O
year O
, O
making O
masking O
optional O
as O
students O
return O
to O
classes O
and O
the O
highly O
transmissible O
BA.5 O
subvariant O
spreads O
. O

Dr. O
Sanjay B-PER
Gupta I-PER
: O
Are O
we O
making O
the O
same O
mistakes O
? O

The O
pandemic O
, O
which O
has O
held O
the O
US B-LOC
and O
almost O
every O
other O
country O
in O
its O
grip O
, O
should O
have O
taught O
us O
valuable O
lessons O
about O
how O
to O
manage O
a O
public O
health O
emergency O
. O

But O
it O
seems O
we O
are O
making O
some O
of O
the O
same O
mistakes O
with O
the O
monkeypox O
virus O
that O
we O
made O
not O
even O
three O
years O
ago O
when O
the O
SARS-CoV-2 O
virus O
started O
to O
spread O

Testing O
for O
monkeypox O
, O
once O
very O
limited O
, O
is O
now O
more O
available O
, O
but O
underused O
. O

The O
demand O
for O
vaccines O
is O
outpacing O
the O
supply O

There O
are O
nearly O
2 O
million O
courses O
of O
the O
highly O
effective O
TPOXX O
antiviral O
sitting O
in O
the O
Strategic B-ORG
National I-ORG
Stockpile I-ORG
, O
but O
many O
health O
care O
providers O
are O
still O
having O
a O
hard O
time O
getting O
the O
medication O
for O
their O
patients O
. O

At O
this O
time O
, O
only O
336,710 O
doses O
have O
been O
shipped O
to O
states O
. O

Ordering O
only O
just O
began O
for O
about O
800,000 O
more O
doses O

This O
scarcity O
has O
created O
long O
lines O
in O
monkeypox O
hotspots O
like O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
City I-LOC
, O
which O
has O
the O
highest O
number O
of O
cases O
in O
the O
country O
. O

Updated O
Covid-19 O
booster O
shots O
could O
be O
available O
in O
September O
Moderna B-ORG
and O
Pfizer B-ORG
booster O
shots O
updated O
to O
target O
Omicron O
coronavirus O
subvariants O
could O
be O
available O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
in O
the O
early O
fall O
, O
pending O
signoff O
by O
federal O
health O
agencies O
, O
the O
US B-LOC
Department B-ORG
of O
Health I-ORG
and O
Human O
Services I-ORG
said O
Friday O
. O

The O
US B-LOC
Food B-ORG
and O
Drug I-ORG
Administration I-ORG
advised O
vaccine O
makers O
in O
June O
to O
update O
the O
boosters O
to O
add O
an O
Omicron O
BA.4/5 O
component O
and O
create O
a O
bivalent O
booster O
that O
would O
work O
for O
two O
different O
strains O

Pfizer B-ORG
and O
Moderna B-ORG
have O
indicated O
that O
they O
anticipate O
the O
modified O
vaccines O
being O
available O
as O
early O
as O
September B-LOC
,” O
an O
FDA B-ORG
spokesperson O
said O
. O

TOP O
TIP O
Many O
children O
will O
soon O
be O
returning O
to O
schools O
– O
while O
coronavirus O
cases O
are O
still O
high O

Parents O
and O
caregivers O
have O
a O
lot O
of O
questions O
about O
what O
precautions O
they O
should O
take O

Do O
kids O
need O
to O
wear O
masks O
again O
? O

How O
often O
should O
families O
test O
kids O
. O

What O
happens O
if O
their O
kids O
contract O
Covid-19 O
. O

How O
long O
should O
they O
stay O
out O
of O
school O
? O

CNN B-ORG
Medical O
Analyst O
Dr. O
Leana B-PER
Wen I-PER
answers O
the O
most O
pressing O
questions O
. O

Democrats’ O
new O
party-line O
tax O
and O
clean O
energy O
bill O
is O
a O
big O
deal O
for O
climate O
and O
energy O
savings. O

With O
nearly O
$370 O
billion O
for O
energy O
programs O
and O
tax O
incentives O
, O
it O
represents O
the O
largest O
climate O
investment O
in O
US B-LOC
history O
. O

In O
addition O
to O
the O
US B-LOC
emissions O
reductions O
these O
will O
bring O
, O
there’s O
a O
lot O
in O
the O
bill O
that O
could O
change O
both O
how O
Americans B-LOC
power O
their O
homes O
and O
what O
kinds O
of O
vehicles O
they O
drive O
. O

The O
bill O
contains O
a O
bevy O
of O
tax O
incentives O
aimed O
at O
pushing O
consumers O
, O
developers O
, O
small O
businesses O
and O
others O
towards O
clean O
energy O
and O
more O
efficient O
energy O
usage O
– O
helping O
bring O
down O
the O
cost O
of O
buying O
electric O
vehicles O
, O
heat O
pumps O
, O
water O
heaters O
, O
rooftop O
solar O
panels O
and O
more O
. O

These O
measures O
would O
be O
more O
comprehensive O
than O
existing O
weatherization O
programs O
, O
and O
several O
would O
be O
available O
to O
all O
households O
, O
not O
just O
low-income O
ones O
” O
said O
Mark B-PER
Wolfe I-PER
, O
executive O
director O
of O
the O
National B-ORG
Energy I-ORG
Assistance I-ORG
Directors I-ORG
Association I-ORG
. O

Clean O
electricity O
nonprofit O
Rewiring B-ORG
America I-ORG
recently O
estimated O
a O
US B-LOC
household O
would O
save O
$1,800 O
per O
year O
if O
they O
installed O
electric O
heat O
pumps O
to O
heat O
their O
water O
and O
heat O
and O
cool O
their O
air O
replaced O
a O
gas O
car O
with O
an O
EV O
and O
installed O
solar O

The O
tax O
credits O
work O
in O
another O
way O
to O
bring O
down O
costs O
: O
incentivizing O
cheaper O
clean O
electricity O
powered O
by O
renewables O

There O
are O
people O
who O
are O
really O
on O
the O
front O
lines O
of O
the O
inflation O
crisis O
and O
how O
expensive O
fossil O
fuels O
are O
because O
of O
Putin’s B-PER
invasion O
of O
Ukraine B-LOC
, O
and O
this O
bill O
will O
be O
delivering O
big O
energy O
savings O
for O
those O
people O
, O
” O
Leah B-PER
Stokes I-PER
, O
a O
senior O
policy O
advisor O
at O
Evergreen B-ORG
and O
associate O
professor O
of O
political O
science O
at O
the O
University B-ORG
of O
California I-ORG
, O
Santa B-LOC
Barbara I-LOC
, O
told O
reporters O
recently O
. O

Here O
are O
the O
main O
pieces O
of O
the O
bill O
that O
help O
consumers O
save O
money O

Savings O
on O
buying O
an O
electric O
vehicle O
: O
The O
bill O
extends O
the O
current O
$7,500 O
tax O
credit O
for O
a O
new O
vehicle O
, O
as O
well O
as O
a O
$4,000 O
tax O
credit O
off O
a O
used O
EV O
. O

It O
also O
gets O
rid O
of O
the O
current O
cap O
that O
cuts O
automakers O
off O
tax O
credits O
after O
they’ve O
sold O
200,000 O
EVs O
, O
and O
it O
is O
written O
so O
buyers O
can O
get O
an O
immediate O
discount O
at O
the O
dealership O
, O
instead O
of O
waiting O
weeks O
or O
months O
for O
their O
tax O
credit O
to O
come O
through O
. O

Still O
, O
there’s O
a O
significant O
caveat O
: O
Automakers O
and O
consumers O
likely O
won’t O
be O
able O
to O
take O
advantage O
of O
this O
tax O
credit O
over O
the O
next O
few O
years O
. O

At O
the O
insistence O
of O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Joe B-PER
Manchin I-PER
, O
the O
tax O
credit O
was O
written O
in O
a O
way O
so O
that O
automakers O
are O
forced O
to O
move O
their O
EV O
supply O
chains O
away O
from O
China B-LOC
and O
to O
the O
US B-LOC
and O
countries O
where O
the O
US B-LOC
has O
free O
trade O
agreements O
. O

Vehicles O
must O
be O
built O
in O
North B-LOC
America I-LOC
, O
and O
EV O
batteries O
must O
also O
not O
come O
from O
countries O
like O
China B-LOC
. O

As O
a O
result O
, O
US O
automakers O
likely O
won’t O
be O
able O
to O
offer O
the O
credit O
in O
the O
next O
few O
years O
as O
they O
try O
to O
build O
up O
their O
domestic O
supply O
chains O
, O
Democratic O
Sen. O
Debbie B-PER
Stabenow I-PER
of O
Michigan B-LOC
said O

The O
tax O
credit O
is O
also O
limited O
to O
trucks O
, O
vans O
and O
SUVs O
under O
$80,000 O
, O
and O
other O
vehicles O
under O
$55,000 O
, O
and O
has O
an O
income O
threshold O
for O
consumers O
. O

Help O
installing O
more O
efficient O
air O
conditioning O
and O
heating O
equipment O
: O
The O
bill O
would O
provide O
Americans B-LOC
with O
tax O
credits O
to O
cover O
30% O
of O
the O
costs O
of O
installing O
highly O
efficient O
ACs O
, O
water O
heaters O
, O
furnaces O
and O
other O
cooling O
and O
heating O
equipment O

Households O
would O
be O
able O
to O
receive O
up O
to O
$600 O
for O
each O
piece O
of O
equipment O
, O
up O
to O
$1,200 O
total O
per O
year O
. O

There O
would O
also O
be O
a O
special O
credit O
of O
up O
to O
$2,000 O
for O
electric O
heat O
pumps O
. O

And O
credits O
could O
be O
used O
to O
upgrade O
breaker O
boxes O
, O
if O
needed O
, O
to O
handle O
additional O
electric O
load O
. O

This O
measure O
replaces O
a O
similar O
tax O
credit O
that O
expired O
at O
the O
end O
of O
last O
year O
and O
came O
with O
a O
lifetime O
cap O
of O
$500 O

Aid O
for O
low- O
and O
moderate- O
income O
Americans B-LOC
to O
purchase O
electric O
appliances O
: O
The O
legislation O
calls O
for O
providing O
low- O
and O
moderate- O
income O
households O
with O
rebates O
of O
up O
to O
$14,000 O
to O
buy O
electric O
appliances O
. O

The O
rebates O
could O
cover O
between O
half O
and O
all O
the O
typical O
$14,000 O
cost O
of O
installing O
an O
electric O
heat O
pump O
, O
as O
well O
as O
much O
of O
the O
cost O
of O
electric O
water O
heaters O
, O
stoves O
and O
ovens O
and O
clothes O
dryers O
, O
as O
well O
as O
upgrading O
the O
home’s O
breaker O
boxes O
and O
electric O
wiring O
. O

The O
legislation O
sets O
aside O
$4.5 O
billion O
over O
10 O
years O
for O
this O
provision O

To O
alleviate O
concerns O
that O
low-income O
households O
would O
have O
to O
pay O
for O
the O
items O
up O
front O
, O
rebates O
could O
be O
provided O
at O
the O
point O
of O
sale O
or O
contractors O
could O
claim O
them O
, O
for O
example O
. O

It O
would O
depend O
on O
how O
state O
energy O
offices O
, O
which O
would O
administer O
the O
rebates O
, O
would O
set O
up O
their O
programs O
. O

Rebates O
for O
retrofitting O
homes O
: O
Households O
could O
receive O
rebates O
of O
up O
to O
$4,000 O
to O
install O
energy-saving O
measures O
throughout O
their O
homes O
, O
under O
the O
bill O
. O

Low- O
and O
moderate-income O
Americans B-LOC
could O
receive O
up O
to O
$8,000 O

The O
rebate O
amount O
would O
depend O
on O
the O
estimated O
savings O
that O
would O
be O
achieved O
. O

The O
legislation O
would O
provide O
a O
total O
of O
$4.3 O
billion O
in O
funding O
over O
10 O
years O
. O

Tax O
credits O
to O
reduce O
energy O
leakage O
: O
Americans B-LOC
could O
receive O
tax O
credits O
to O
cover O
30% O
of O
the O
costs O
of O
home O
improvements O
that O
reduce O
energy O
leakage O
, O
such O
as O
updated O
windows O
, O
doors O
, O
insulation O
and O
other O
weatherization O
measures O
, O
under O
the O
bill O
. O

They O
could O
get O
a O
credit O
of O
up O
to O
$600 O
per O
improvement O
and O
a O
total O
of O
$1,200 O
per O
year O

Plus, O
they O
could O
receive O
a O
$150 O
credit O
to O
have O
a O
home O
energy O
audit O
conducted. O

The O
credit O
would O
be O
expanded O
so O
families O
could O
use O
it O
multiple O
times O
to O
make O
upgrades O
over O
time O

Boosting O
efficiency O
in O
HUD O
housing: O
The O
bill O
would O
provide O
$1 O
billion O
in O
grants O
and O
loans O
to O
affordable O
housing O
units O
administered O
by O
the O
Department B-ORG
of O
Housing I-ORG
and O
Urban I-ORG
Development I-ORG
to O
increase O
energy O
or O
water O
efficiency, O
improve O
indoor O
air O
quality, O
make O
clean O
energy O
or O
electrification O
upgrades O
or O
address O
climate O
resilience O
needs. O

The O
improvements O
could O
include O
insulation O
, O
HVAC O
upgrades O
, O
flood-proofing O
, O
storm O
resistance O
, O
water-saving O
changes O
and O
the O
installation O
of O
solar O
or O
other O
renewable O
energy O
systems O
Tax O
credits O
for O
developers O
to O
build O
energy O
efficient O
homes O
: O
Builders O
could O
receive O
tax O
credits O
of O
$2,500 O
for O
single-family O
or O
manufactured O
homes O
and O
$500 O
for O
units O
in O
multi-family O
buildings O
for O
constructing O
Energy B-ORG
Star-certified I-ORG
housing O

Developers O
could O
get O
$2,500 O
for O
each O
multifamily O
unit O
if O
prevailing O
wage O
requirements O
are O
met O

The O
credits O
would O
double O
if O
the O
homes O
or O
units O
are O
also O
certified O
under O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Energy’s I-ORG
zero-energy O
ready O
home O
program O
. O

A O
credit O
of O
up O
to O
$2,000 O
for O
building O
energy O
efficient O
homes O
expired O
at O
the O
end O
of O
last O
year O

Installing O
solar O
panels O
on O
homes O
: O
Tax O
credits O
in O
the O
bill O
will O
cover O
30% O
of O
the O
cost O
of O
buying O
a O
rooftop O
solar O
system O
and O
home O
battery O
storage O

But O
that O
upfront O
cost O
will O
result O
in O
energy O
bill O
savings O
every O
year O
and O
add O
value O
to O
a O
home O

For O
those O
who O
live O
in O
apartments O
or O
can’t O
install O
solar O
on O
their O
roofs O
, O
there O
are O
other O
ways O
to O
get O
solar O
energy O
and O
lower O
energy O
bills O
, O
including O
leasing O
a O
rooftop O
solar O
system O
or O
joining O
a O
community O
solar O
farm O
to O
get O
power O
delivered O
. O

Tax O
credits O
in O
the O
bill O
increase O
for O
solar O
projects O
in O
low-income O
communities O
as O
well O

Small O
business O
incentives: O
Small O
businesses O
can O
get O
tax O
deductions O
of O
up O
to O
$1 O
per O
square O
foot O
of O
their O
business O
to O
make O
the O
space O
more O
energy O
efficient. O

They O
can O
get O
tax O
credits O
that O
cover O
up O
to O
30% O
of O
the O
cost O
to O
replace O
fleets O
of O
cars O
and O
trucks O
with O
clean O
vehicles O
, O
as O
well O
as O
incentives O
to O
power O
their O
businesses O
with O
solar O
. O

سلاح O
الجو O
الصيني O
يؤكد O
قدرته O
على O
حماية O
" O
السيادة O
" O
ويعلق O
على O
تحليق O
مقاتلاته O
حول O
تايوان B-LOC
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

George B-PER
Takei I-PER
and O
J.J. O
Abrams B-PER
paid O
tribute O
to O
the O
late O
“Star O
Trek” O
actress O
Nichelle B-PER
Nichols I-PER
, O
who O
died O
Saturday O
at O
the O
age O
of O
89 O
. O

Nichols O
had O
played O
Enterprise O
crew O
member O
Nyota B-PER
Uhura I-PER
on O
the O
series O
and O
multiple O
“Trek” O
films O

I O
shall O
have O
more O
to O
say O
about O
the O
trailblazing O
, O
incomparable O
Nichelle B-PER
Nichols I-PER
, O
who O
shared O
the O
bridge O
with O
us O
as O
Lt O
. O

Uhura O
of O
the O
USS O
Enterprise B-ORG
,” O
Takei B-PER
wrote O
on O
social O
media O
. O
“ O

For O
today O
, O
my O
heart O
is O
heavy O
, O
my O
eyes O
shining O
like O
the O
stars O
you O
now O
rest O
among O
, O
my O
dearest O
friend O
. O

Abrams B-PER
, O
who O
directed O
the O
2009 O
“Star O
Trek” O
reboot O
and O
2013’s O
“Star O
Trek O
Into O
Darkness,” O
called O
Nichols B-PER
“a O
remarkable O
woman O
in O
a O
remarkable O
role.” O

A O
remarkable O
woman O
in O
a O
remarkable O
role O

Nichelle B-PER
, O
you O
will O
be O
deeply O
missed O
. O

Sending O
much O
love O
and O
respect O
he O
wrote O
on O
Twitter B-ORG
. O

Star O
Trek” O
star O
William B-PER
Shatner I-PER
also O
paid O
tribute O
, O
writing O
, O
“ O
She O
was O
a O
beautiful O
woman O
and O
played O
an O
admirable O
character O
that O
did O
so O
much O
for O
redefining O
social O
issues O
both O
here O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
and O
throughout O
the O
world O
. O
” O

Georgia B-LOC
politician O
and O
“Trek” O
fan O
Stacey B-PER
Abrams I-PER
posted O
a O
photograph O
of O
herself O
with O
Nichols O
, O
captioning O
it O
, O
“One O
of O
my O
most O
treasured O
photos O
- O
Godspeed O
to O
Nichelle B-PER
Nichols I-PER
, O
champion O
, O
warrior O
and O
tremendous O
actor O
. O

Her O
kindness O
and O
bravery O
lit O
the O
path O
for O
many O

May O
she O
forever O
dwell O
among O
the O
stars O
. O

Actor O
Colman B-PER
Domingo I-PER
wrote O
“Nichelle B-PER
Nichols I-PER
told O
us O
that O
we O
belonged O
in O
outer O
space O
.” O

We O
are O
limitless O

The O
heavens O
have O
gained O
an O
Uhura B-PER
today O

The O
official O
NASA B-ORG
Twitter B-ORG
account O
posted O
a O
tribute O
saying O
: O
“ O
We O
celebrate O
the O
life O
of O
Nichelle B-PER
Nichols I-PER
, O
Star O
Trek O
actor O
, O
trailblazer O
, O
and O
role O
model O
, O
who O
symbolized O
to O
so O
many O
what O
was O
possible O
. O
” O
