The O
US B-ORG
Army I-ORG
is O
developing O
a O
tactical O
bra O
for O
its O
female O
soldiers O
. O
The O
bra O
, O
known O
as O
the O
Army B-ORG
Tactical I-ORG
Brassiere I-ORG
, O
is O
still O
in O
development O
at O
the O
US B-ORG
Army I-ORG
Combat B-ORG
Capabilities I-ORG
Development I-ORG
Command I-ORG
Solider B-ORG
Center I-ORG
, O
also O
known O
as O
DEVCOM B-ORG
, O
in O
Natick B-LOC
, O
Massachusetts I-LOC
. O
If O
approved O
by O
the O
Army B-ORG
Uniform I-ORG
Board I-ORG
, O
it O
will O
be O
the O
first O
official O
uniform O
bra O
the O
Army B-ORG
has O
offered O
its O
female O
soldiers O
in O
its O
history O
. O
The O
Army B-ORG
Times I-ORG
was O
first O
to O
report O
the O
US B-ORG
Army I-ORG
is O
developing O
this O
bra O
. O
Soldier B-ORG
Center’s I-ORG
Design B-ORG
, O
Pattern B-ORG
and O
Prototype B-ORG
Team I-ORG
will O
present O
final O
concepts O
and O
designs O
for O
the O
bra O
to O
the O
Army B-ORG
Uniform I-ORG
Board I-ORG
in O
the O
fall O
of O
2022 O
, O
David B-PER
Accetta I-PER
, O
US B-ORG
Army I-ORG
Combat B-ORG
Capabilities I-ORG
Development I-ORG
Command I-ORG
Soldier B-ORG
Center I-ORG
spokesperson O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
If O
the O
Army B-ORG
Uniform I-ORG
Board I-ORG
approves O
the O
prototype O
and O
makes O
it O
a O
Program B-ORG
of I-ORG
Record I-ORG
, O
it O
will O
be O
added O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
Army I-ORG
uniform O
. O
In O
order O
to O
develop O
the O
bra O
, O
DEVCOM B-ORG
surveyed O
“hundreds O
of O
female O
soldiers O
across O
the O
Army B-ORG
in O
different O
places O
and O
in O
different O
jobs O
, O
to O
gather O
information O
about O
the O
“proper O
fit O
, O
function O
, O
support O
and O
performance,” O
Accetta B-PER
said O
. O

Prototypes O
were O
developed O
at O
DEVCOM’s B-ORG
headquarters O
in O
Natick B-LOC
, O
MA B-LOC
. O

Possible O
design O
concepts O
from O
industry O
partners O
were O
also O
evaluated O
at O
DEVCOM’s B-ORG
headquarters O
. O
Because O
the O
bra O
is O
considered O
a O
tactical O
piece O
not O
just O
a O
sportswear O
item O
, O
thorough O
tests O
were O
conducted O
in O
developing O
the O
current O
prototype O
, O
including O
flame O
testing O
at O
DEVCOM’s B-ORG
Thermal B-ORG
Test I-ORG
Facility I-ORG
. O
Findings O
from O
these O
tests O
will O
be O
presented O
by O
the O
development O
team O
when O
the O
bra O
is O
presented O
to O
the B-ORG
Army I-ORG
Uniform I-ORG
Board I-ORG
later O
this O
year O
. O
If O
the O
bra O
“ O
becomes O
an O
official O
Program B-ORG
of O
Record I-ORG
as O
a O
result O
of O
the O
upcoming O
Army B-ORG
Uniform I-ORG
Board I-ORG
, O
we O
would O
see O
that O
as O
a O
win O
for O
female O
soldiers O
across O
the O
Army B-ORG
, O
who O
would O
then O
likely O
be O
issued O
the O
ATB O
upon O
initial O
entry O
to O
the O
Army B-ORG
, O
” O
Accetta B-PER
said O
. O

Axios B-ORG
, O
the O
buzzy O
digital O
media O
venture O
founded O
in O
in O
2017 O
, O
will O
sell O
itself O
to O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
, O
the O
two O
companies O
announced O
on O
Monday O
. O
The O
deal O
, O
which O
is O
expected O
to O
close O
this O
month O
, O
values O
Axios B-ORG
at O
$525 O
million O
, O
a O
person O
familiar O
with O
the O
matter O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Axios B-ORG
is O
known O
for O
delivering O
news O
in O
brief O
stories O
that O
are O
comprised O
of O
bite-sized O
pieces O
of O
information O
. O

The O
publication O
is O
also O
known O
for O
its O
popular O
newsletters O
that O
often O
drive O
the O
national O
conversation O
, O
especially O
in O
Washington B-LOC
, O
DC B-LOC
. O

News O
of O
the O
deal O
was O
first O
reported O
by O
The B-ORG
New I-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
. O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
, O
which O
was O
already O
a O
top O
investor O
in O
Axios B-ORG
, O
said O
that O
Axios B-ORG
co-founders O
Jim B-PER
VandeHei I-PER
, O
Mike B-PER
Allen I-PER
, O
and O
Roy B-PER
Schwartz I-PER
will O
continue O
to O
lead O
the O
outlet’s O
day-to-day O
editorial O
and O
business O
decisions O
. O
VandeHei B-PER
, O
Allen B-PER
, O
and O
Schwartz B-PER
will O
also O
continue O
to O
hold O
“substantial O
stakes O
in O
the O
company O
, O
” O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
said O
. O
While O
the O
three O
co-founders O
will O
remain O
on O
the O
board O
, O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
will O
control O
it O
with O
four O
board O
seats O
. O
“We O
have O
found O
our O
kindred O
spirit O
for O
creating O
a O
great O
, O
trusted O
, O
consequential O
media O
company O
that O
can O
outlast O
us O
all O
, O
” O
VandeHei B-PER
said O
. O
“Our O
shared O
ambitions O
should O
be O
clear O
: O
to O
spread O
clinical O
, O
nonpartisan O
, O
trusted O
journalism O
to O
as O
many O
cities O
and O
as O
many O
topics O
as O
fast O
as O
possible O
. O
” O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
chief O
executive O
Alex B-PER
Taylor I-PER
praised O
Axios B-ORG
as O
a O
“forward-thinking O
organization O
.” O
Taylor B-PER
said O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
looks O
forward O
“to O
helping O
them O
continue O
to O
scale O
and O
grow O
. O
“With O
so O
much O
happening O
in O
the O
world O
, O
Axios B-ORG
plays O
a O
critical O
role O
in O
delivering O
balanced O
, O
trusted O
news O
that O
people O
need O
, O
” O
Taylor B-PER
said O
. O
“Our O
company O
started O
in O
the O
media O
business O
, O
and O
we O
have O
always O
had O
a O
passion O
for O
journalism O
. O

Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
said O
that O
its O
other O
media O
companies O
, O
such O
as O
the O
Atlanta B-LOC
Journal-Constitution I-LOC
and O
Dayton B-LOC
Daily I-LOC
News I-LOC
, O
will O
not O
be O
impacted O
by O
the O
deal O
. O
Axios B-ORG
HQ I-ORG
, O
the O
company’s O
software O
arm O
, O
will O
not O
be O
sold O
to O
Cox B-ORG
Enterprises I-ORG
as O
part O
of O
the O
transaction O
. O
It O
will O
instead O
be O
spun O
off O
into O
a O
separate O
company O
led O
by O
VandeHei B-PER
as O
chairman O
and O
Schwartz B-PER
as O
chief O
executive O
. O
“ O
We O
are O
excited O
about O
entering O
into O
this O
new O
chapter O
with O
Cox B-ORG
and O
the O
opportunities O
we O
can O
explore O
with O
Axios B-ORG
HQ I-ORG
as O
a O
separate O
business O
, O
” O
Schwartz B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
For O
both O
companies O
, O
our O
mission O
is O
to O
help O
as O
many O
people O
and O
companies O
get O
smarter O
, O
faster O
on O
what O
matters O
. O

We O
bought O
a O
cheap O
Italian B-LOC
home O
and O
added O
an O
elevator O
| O
CNN B-ORG
Travel I-ORG
![fwp_0] O
(https://ads.stickyadstv.com/user-matching?id=185&_fw_gdpr=0&_fw_gdpr_consent=) O
![fwp_1] O
(https://ads.stickyadstv.com/auto-user-sync) O
![Quantcast] O
(//pixel.quantserve.com/pixel/p-D1yc5zQgjmqr5.gif) O

The O
suspect O
in O
a O
quadruple O
homicide O
in O
which O
the O
victims O
were O
found O
dead O
in O
two O
separate O
house O
fires O
has O
been O
hospitalized O
with O
burns O
over O
much O
of O
his O
body O
and O
lived O
across O
the O
street O
from O
one O
of O
the O
blazes O
, O
police O
in O
Nebraska B-LOC
said O
Friday O
. O
According O
to O
court O
documents O
obtained O
by O
CNN B-ORG
affiliate O
KTIV B-ORG
, O
a O
gas O
station O
receipt O
left O
in O
a O
backpack O
at O
one O
of O
the O
murder O
scenes O
led O
authorities O
to O
Jason B-PER
A. I-PER
Jones I-PER
, O
42 O
. O

He O
was O
taken O
into O
custody O
early O
Friday O
, O
Nebraska B-LOC
State I-LOC
Police I-ORG
Col. O
John B-PER
Bolduc I-PER
said O
. O
Jones O
had O
serious O
burns O
and O
was O
airlifted O
to O
a O
hospital O
in O
Lincoln B-LOC
, O
Bolduc B-PER
said O
. O
Jones O
is O
charged O
with O
four O
counts O
of O
first-degree O
murder O
, O
four O
counts O
of O
use O
of O
a O
firearm O
to O
commit O
a O
felony O
and O
two O
counts O
of O
first-degree O
arson O
, O
according O
to O
the O
documents O
. O
It O
could O
not O
immediately O
be O
determined O
whether O
he O
had O
legal O
representation O
. O

Crime O
scene O
investigators O
obtained O
physical O
evidence O
at O
the O
two O
fire O
scenes O
that O
pointed O
to O
a O
suspect O
who O
lived O
right O
across O
the O
street O
from O
one O
of O
the O
fires O
. O
Bolduc B-PER
credited O
firefighters O
for O
putting O
out O
the O
fires O
while O
preserving O
the O
evidence O
of O
the O
crimes O
, O
which O
led O
police O
to O
the O
suspect O
. O
Bolduc B-PER
said O
it O
was O
premature O
to O
talk O
about O
motive O
. O
“ O
I O
want O
to O
acknowledge O
the O
indescribable O
grief O
that O
this O
community O
is O
experiencing O
right O
now O
. O

And O
that’s O
going O
to O
be O
compounded O
by O
the O
betrayal O
of O
trust O
that O
they’re O
going O
to O
feel O
because O
a O
community O
member O
here O
is O
alleged O
to O
have O
committed O
these O
crimes O
,” O
Bolduc B-PER
said O
. O
According O
to O
the O
affidavit O
and O
application O
for O
the O
issuance O
of O
an O
arrest O
warrant O
, O
a O
black O
backpack O
was O
located O
inside O
a O
home O
on O
209 O
Elm B-LOC
Street I-LOC
where O
an O
explosion O
was O
reported O
, O
and O
a O
woman O
“ O
who O
appears O
to O
have O
suffered O
two O
gunshot O
wounds O
” O
was O
found O
unresponsive O
and O
later O
pronounced O
dead O
on O
the O
scene O
. O
“ O
Upon O
execution O
of O
the O
search O
warrant O
, O
located O
in O
the O
kitchen O
was O
a O
black O
backpack O
,” O
the O
document O
read O
. O
“ O
In O
the O
black O
backpack O
was O
several O
receipts O
.” O
One O
receipt O
dated O
August O
3 O
led O
investigators O
to O
a O
gas O
station O
where O
Jones B-PER
allegedly O
used O
a O
credit O
card O
to O
purchase O
a O
6-gallon O
auto O
shutoff O
gas O
, O
a O
fuel O
tank O
, O
and O
a O
camping O
backpack O
, O
according O
to O
the O
document O
. O
Security O
cameras O
also O
allegedly O
showed O
Jones B-PER
at O
a O
mini O
mart O
“ O
pumping O
gas O
into O
two O
red O
gas O
cans O
.” O
In O
the O
second O
home O
on O
503 O
Elm B-LOC
Street I-LOC
, O
where O
three O
individuals O
were O
found O
deceased O
with O
gunshot O
wounds O
, O
a O
“Molotov B-MISC
cocktail I-MISC
was O
found O
indicating O
the O
fire O
to O
have O
been O
intentional O
.” O
When O
executing O
a O
search O
warrant O
in O
that O
home O
, O
authorities O
found O
a O
pistol O
that O
was O
traced O
showing O
it O
was O
purchased O
by O
Jason B-PER
Alan I-PER
Jones I-PER
of O
“206 O
Elm B-LOC
Street I-LOC
.” O
The O
four O
victims O
have O
been O
identified O
as O
a O
family O
of O
three O
adults O
, O
85-year-old O
Janet B-PER
Twiford I-PER
, O
86-year-old O
Gene B-PER
Twiford I-PER
, O
and O
55-year-old O
Dana B-PER
Twiford I-PER
; O
and O
the O
woman O
who O
was O
found O
in O
the O
first O
house O
, O
53-year-old O
Michele B-PER
Ebeling I-PER
. O
James B-PER
Roberts I-PER
, O
who O
has O
owned O
Laurel’s B-ORG
Hometown I-ORG
Market I-ORG
for O
more O
than O
a O
year O
, O
said O
that O
news O
of O
the O
deaths O
had O
shocked O
the O
small O
town O
. O

Laurel B-LOC
has O
a O
population O
of O
around O
1,000 O
people O
and O
is O
located O
in O
Cedar B-LOC
County I-LOC
in O
the O
northeast O
of O
the O
state O
. O
“ O
Stuff O
like O
this O
doesn’t O
happen O
in O
this O
town O
, O
” O
Roberts B-PER
said O
. O

“ O
Everybody O
here O
knows O
everybody O
.” O
He O
said O
the O
grocery O
store O
has O
delivered O
food O
to O
the O
state O
troopers O
and O
firefighters O
who O
responded O
to O
the O
scene O
and O
are O
stationed O
at O
a O
nearby O
church O
. O
Staff O
packed O
up O
hamburgers O
and O
sandwiches O
including O
sloppy O
joes O
in O
addition O
to O
some O
water O
to O
show O
their O
support O
. O
“ O
It’s O
a O
tight-knit O
town O
,” O
Roberts B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
Everybody O
here O
is O
family O
.” O

A O
Russian B-LOC
national O
accused O
of O
running O
a O
multibillion-dollar O
cryptocurrency O
exchange O
that O
allegedly O
profited O
from O
various O
hacking O
and O
extortion O
schemes O
has O
been O
extradited O
from O
Greece B-LOC
and O
is O
on O
his O
way O
to O
the O
US B-LOC
, O
according O
to O
the O
suspect’s O
lawyer O
. O
Alexander B-PER
Vinnik I-PER
, O
who O
is O
in O
his O
early O
40s O
, O
is O
accused O
of O
operating O
a O
cryptocurrency O
exchange O
known O
as O
BTC-e B-ORG
that O
allegedly O
did O
business O
with O
ransomware O
gangs O
, O
drug O
dealers O
and O
identity O
thieves O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
. O
He O
faces O
charges O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
Northern B-ORG
District I-ORG
Court I-ORG
of O
California B-LOC
of O
money O
laundering O
and O
operating O
an O
unlicensed O
money O
service O
business O
in O
the O
US B-LOC
, O
among O
other O
charges O
. O

Vinnik B-PER
’s O
extradition O
is O
a O
significant O
win O
for O
US B-ORG
law O
enforcement O
officials O
, O
who O
had O
been O
in O
a O
high-stakes O
extradition O
fight O
with O
Russia B-LOC
to O
gain O
custody O
of O
Vinnik B-PER
. O
Frédéric B-PER
Bélot I-PER
, O
Vinnik B-PER
’s O
lawyer O
in O
France B-LOC
, O
told O
CNN B-ORG
Thursday O
afternoon O
that O
his O
client O
was O
on O
a O
plane O
from O
Athens B-LOC
, O
Greece B-LOC
, O
to O
the O
US B-ORG
, O
where O
he O
is O
expected O
to O
make O
an O
initial O
court O
appearance O
in O
the O
US B-ORG
Northern B-ORG
District I-ORG
of O
California B-LOC
. O
Bélot B-PER
said O
that O
Vinnik B-PER
maintains O
his O
innocence O
. O
Vinnik B-PER
’s O
extradition O
shows O
how O
US B-ORG
prosecutors O
have O
continued O
to O
pursue O
high-profile O
Russian B-MISC
cybercrime O
suspects O
at O
a O
time O
when O
any O
faint O
hopes O
of O
cooperation O
with O
Moscow B-LOC
on O
the O
issue O
have O
dimmed O
. O
Vinnik B-PER
was O
arrested O
in O
2017 O
in O
Greece B-LOC
and O
subsequently O
extradited O
to O
France B-LOC
, O
where O
he O
was O
sentenced O
to O
five O
years O
in O
prison O
in O
2020 O
for O
money O
laundering O
. O
But O
Vinnik B-PER
has O
also O
been O
under O
indictment O
in O
US B-ORG
since O
2017 O
, O
and O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
Russia B-LOC
filed O
dueling O
extradition O
requests O
from O
Greece B-LOC
. O
BTC-e B-ORG
, O
which O
shut O
down O
in O
2017 O
, O
received O
more O
than O
$4 O
billion O
worth O
of O
bitcoin O
while O
it O
was O
operating O
, O
according O
to O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
. O
The O
Treasury B-ORG
Department I-ORG
in O
2017 O
assessed O
a O
$110 O
million O
civil O
money O
penalty O
against O
the O
cryptocurrency O
exchange O
“for O
willfully O
violating O
U.S. B-MISC

anti-money O
laundering O
laws” O
and O
a O
$12 O
million O
fee O
against O
Vinnik. B-PER

Kevin B-PER
Spacey I-PER
will O
have O
to O
pay O
almost O
$31 O
million O
to O
Media B-ORG
Rights I-ORG
Capital I-ORG
, O
the O
production O
company O
behind O
“House B-MISC
of O
Cards,” I-MISC
a O
judge O
has O
ruled O
. O
The O
actor O
starred O
in O
the O
Netflix B-ORG
series O
for O
five O
seasons O
before O
he O
was O
fired O
in O
2017 O
. O

Los B-LOC
Angeles I-LOC
Superior O
Court O
Judge O
Mel B-PER
Red I-PER
Recana I-PER
made O
the O
ruling O
earlier O
this O
week O
, O
confirming O
an O
award O
that O
had O
been O
decided O
by O
an O
arbitrator O
last O
year O
. O
CNN B-ORG
has O
obtained O
the O
court O
documents O
. O
Spacey B-PER
and O
MRC B-ORG
have O
been O
battling O
in O
the O
years O
since O
the O
actor O
was O
dismissed O
from O
the O
production O
over O
allegations O
of O
misconduct O
on O
and O
off O
the O
set O
. O
Spacey B-PER
starred O
as O
Frank B-PER
Underwood I-PER
on O
the O
Emmy-winning O
show O
, O
and O
MRC B-ORG
claims O
that O
having O
to O
cut O
him O
out O
of O
the O
sixth O
season O
of O
the O
show O
cost O
them O
millions O
of O
dollars O
and O
“ O
rendered O
him O
( O
and O
his O
affiliated O
entities O
) O
liable O
.” O
Spacey B-PER
was O
fired O
from O
the O
TV O
show O
the O
day O
after O
CNN B-ORG
published O
its O
report O
in O
2017 O
, O
in O
which O
several O
current O
and O
former O
members O
of O
the O
“ O
House B-MISC
of I-MISC
Cards I-MISC
” O
production O
staff O
came O
forward O
with O
allegations O
of O
sexual O
harassment O
. O
One O
person O
also O
accused O
Spacey B-PER
, O
who O
was O
an O
executive O
producer O
on O
the O
series O
, O
of O
sexual O
assault O
. O
Shortly O
before O
CNN’s B-ORG
report O
, O
actor O
Anthony B-PER
Rapp I-PER
told O
BuzzFeed B-ORG
News I-ORG
that O
the O
actor O
made O
a O
sexual O
advance O
toward O
him O
at O
a O
party O
in O
1986 O
when O
he O
was O
14 O
years O
old O
. O
MRC B-ORG
says O
it O
halted O
the O
production O
“ O
to O
address O
any O
concerns O
of O
the O
show’s O
cast O
and O
crew O
” O
in O
wake O
of O
the O
allegations O
, O
according O
to O
a O
2021 O
filing O
and O
previously O
reported O
by O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Following O
Rapp’s O
claims O
, O
Spacey B-PER
issued O
a O
statement O
claiming O
he O
did O
not O
recall O
the O
incident O
and O
apologized O
for O
what O
he O
said O
would O
have O
been O
“ O
deeply O
inappropriate O
drunken O
behavior O
.” O
The O
Oscar O
winner O
is O
facing O
a O
criminal O
trial O
in O
London B-LOC
next O
year O
after O
being O
accused O
of O
sexually O
assaulting O
three O
men O
between O
2005 O
and O
2013 O
. O
Spacey B-PER
pleaded O
not O
guilty O
in O
July O
. O

CNN B-ORG
has O
reached O
out O
to O
Spacey’s B-PER
attorneys O
for O
comment O
. O

The O
US B-LOC
and O
Russia B-LOC
have O
indicated O
they O
are O
ready O
to O
hold O
talks O
over O
a O
prisoner O
swap O
, O
a O
day O
after O
basketball O
star O
Brittney B-PER
Griner I-PER
was O
convicted O
of O
drug O
smuggling O
and O
sentenced O
to O
nine O
years O
in O
prison O
for O
carrying O
less O
than O
a O
gram O
of O
cannabis O
oil O
through O
a O
Moscow B-LOC
airport O
. O
Russia’s B-LOC
foreign O
minister O
Sergey B-PER
Lavrov I-PER
told O
reporters O
in O
Cambodia B-LOC
that O
the O
Kremlin B-LOC
is O
“ O
ready O
to O
discuss O
this O
topic O
, O
but O
within O
the O
framework O
of O
the O
channel O
that O
has O
been O
agreed O
by O
the O
presidents O
, O
” O
state O
news O
agency O
RIA B-ORG
Novosti I-ORG
reported O
. O

There O
is O
a O
specified O
channel O
that O
has O
been O
agreed O
upon O
by O
[ O
Russian B-LOC
President O
Vladimir B-PER
Putin I-PER
and O
US B-ORG
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
] O
, O
and O
no O
matter O
what O
anyone O
says O
publicly O
, O
this O
channel O
will O
remain O
in O
effect O
, O
” O
Lavrov B-PER
reportedly O
said O
Friday O
at O
the O
Association B-ORG
of O
Southeast I-ORG
Asian I-ORG
Nations I-ORG
summit O
. O
Shortly O
later O
, O
US B-ORG
Secretary O
of O
State O
Antony B-PER
Blinken I-PER
said O
at O
the O
same O
summit O
that O
the O
US B-ORG
will O
“ O
pursue O
” O
talks O
with O
Russia B-LOC
. O
“ O
We O
put O
forward O
, O
as O
you O
know O
, O
a O
substantial O
proposal O
that O
Russia B-LOC
should O
engage O
with O
us O
on O
. O
And O
what O
Foreign O
Minister O
Lavrov B-PER
said O
this O
morning O
and O
said O
publicly O
is O
that O
they O
are O
prepared O
to O
engage O
through O
channels O
we’ve O
established O
to O
do O
just O
that O
. O
And O
we’ll O
be O
pursuing O
that O
, O
” O
Blinken B-PER
told O
reporters O
at O
a O
press O
briefing O
. O
President O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
said O
later O
on O
Friday O
that O
he’s O
hopeful O
about O
efforts O
to O
secure O
Griner B-PER
. O
“ O
I’m O
hopeful O
. O
We’re O
working O
hard O
, O
” O
Biden B-PER
told O
reporters O
outside O
the O
White B-LOC
House I-LOC
after O
a O
bill O
signing O
. O

The O
comments O
from O
each O
side O
suggest O
that O
a O
negotiation O
process O
, O
which O
has O
already O
proven O
complex O
, O
could O
accelerate O
in O
the O
coming O
days O
. O
Russian B-LOC
government O
officials O
requested O
last O
month O
that O
a O
former O
colonel O
from O
the O
country’s O
domestic O
spy O
agency O
, O
who O
was O
convicted O
of O
murder O
in O
Germany B-LOC
last O
year O
, O
be O
included O
in O
the O
US’ B-ORG
proposed O
swap O
of O
notorious O
arms O
dealer O
Viktor B-PER
Bout I-PER
for O
Griner B-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Whelan I-PER
, O
multiple O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
discussions O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Whelan B-PER
, O
a O
US B-ORG
citizen O
, O
has O
been O
held O
by O
Russia B-LOC
since O
2018 O
and O
was O
convicted O
by O
a O
Russian B-LOC
court O
in O
2020 O
on O
espionage O
charges O
that O
he O
has O
strenuously O
denied O
. O
Griner’s B-PER
conviction O
has O
raised O
similar O
concerns O
that O
she O
is O
being O
used O
as O
a O
political O
pawn O
in O
Russia’s B-LOC
war O
against O
Ukraine B-LOC
. O
The O
US B-ORG
State I-ORG
Department I-ORG
classifies O
the O
pair O
as O
wrongfully O
detained O
. O
Griner B-PER
, O
a O
Women’s B-ORG
National I-ORG
Basketball I-ORG
Association I-ORG
star O
, O
pleaded O
guilty O
to O
carrying O
cannabis O
oil O
in O
her O
luggage O
as O
she O
traveled O
through O
a O
Moscow B-LOC
airport O
on O
February O
17 O
. O
She O
testified O
in O
court O
that O
she O
was O
aware O
of O
Russia’s B-LOC
strict O
drug O
laws O
and O
had O
no O
intention O
of O
bringing O
cannabis O
into O
the O
country O
, O
saying O
she O
was O
in O
a O
rush O
and O
“stress O
packing O
.” O
Prior O
to O
the O
verdict O
on O
Thursday O
, O
Griner B-PER
apologized O
to O
the O
court O
and O
asked O
for O
leniency O
in O
an O
emotional O
speech O
. O
“I O
never O
meant O
to O
hurt O
anybody O
, O
I O
never O
meant O
to O
put O
in O
jeopardy O
the O
Russian B-LOC
population O
, O
I O
never O
meant O
to O
break O
any O
laws O
here O
, O
” O
she O
said O
. O

I O
made O
an O
honest O
mistake O
and O
I O
hope O
that O
in O
your O
ruling O
that O
it O
doesn’t O
end O
my O
life O
here O
. O
I O
know O
everybody O
keeps O
talking O
about O
political O
pawn O
and O
politics O
, O
but O
I O
hope O
that O
, O
that O
is O
far O
from O
this O
courtroom O
, O
” O
she O
continued O
. O
Griner’s B-PER
lawyers O
had O
hoped O
that O
her O
guilty O
plea O
and O
statements O
of O
remorse O
would O
result O
in O
a O
more O
lenient O
sentence O
. O
Her O
conviction O
, O
Blinken B-PER
told O
reporters O
, O
“ O
puts O
a O
spotlight O
on O
[ O
Washington’s B-LOC
] O
very O
significant O
concern O
with O
Russia’s B-LOC
legal O
system O
and O
the O
Russian B-LOC
government’s O
use O
of O
wrongful O
detentions O
to O
advance O
its O
own O
agenda O
using O
individuals O
as O
political O
pawn O
. O
“ O
The O
same O
goes O
for O
Paul B-PER
Whelan I-PER
, O
” O
Blinken B-PER
added O
. O
Earlier O
Friday O
, O
a O
US B-ORG
State I-ORG
Department I-ORG
official O
told O
reporters O
there O
had O
been O
no O
“ O
serious O
response O
” O
from O
Russia B-LOC
on O
a O
proposed O
swap O
. O
The O
same O
official O
said O
Blinken B-PER
and I-PER
Lavrov I-PER
had O
not O
met O
while O
at O
the O
Cambodia B-LOC
summit O
, O
and O
that O
Blinken B-PER
had O
no O
plans O
to O
do O
so O
. O
Kremlin B-LOC
spokesman O
Dmitry B-PER
Peskov I-PER
told O
reporters O
Russia B-LOC
would O
not O
discuss O
the O
prospect O
of O
a O
transfer O
publicly O
. O
“ O
If O
we O
discuss O
through O
the O
press O
some O
exchange-related O
nuances O
, O
then O
these O
exchanges O
will O
never O
take O
place O
. O

The O
Americans B-MISC
have O
already O
made O
this O
mistake O
, O
he O
said O
Friday O
. O
Peskov B-PER
, O
asked O
whether O
Putin B-PER
could O
pardon O
Griner B-PER
, O
said O
that O
“ O
there O
is O
a O
certain O
[ O
legal O
] O
procedure O
that O
the O
convicted O
can O
resort O
to O
, O
in O
accordance O
with O
the O
law O
. O
According O
to O
the B-LOC
Russian I-LOC
law O
, O
to O
start O
the O
clemency O
procedure O
, O
a O
convict O
needs O
to O
write O
a O
petition O
to O
the B-LOC
Russian I-LOC
president O
. O
Before O
the O
start O
of O
Thursday’s O
WNBA B-ORG
game O
between O
Griner’s B-PER
Phoenix B-ORG
Mercury I-ORG
and O
the O
Connecticut B-LOC
Sun I-ORG
, O
members O
of O
both O
teams O
linked O
arms O
around O
center O
court O
, O
and O
a O
42-second O
moment O
of O
silence O
was O
held O
for O
Brittney B-PER
Griner I-PER
. O

Near O
the O
end O
of O
those O
42 O
seconds O
, O
members O
of O
the O
crowd O
started O
chanting O
, O
“ O
Bring O
her O
home O
! O
” O

Bring O
her O
home O
! O
This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
developments O
. O
CNN’s B-ORG
Martin B-PER
Goillandeau I-PER
, O
Anna B-PER
Chernova I-PER
and O
Daniel B-PER
Allman I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Democratic O
Sen. O
Joe B-PER
Manchin I-PER
argued O
Sunday O
that O
Republicans O
would O
in O
“normal O
times” O
support O
an O
energy O
and O
health O
care O
bill O
he O
recently O
negotiated O
with O
leaders O
of O
his O
party, O
saying O
the O
major O
piece O
of O
legislation O
addresses O
key O
areas O
the O
GOP O
has O
long O
championed. O
“I O
think O
it’s O
a O
great O
piece O
of O
legislation O
and O
on O
normal O
times, O
my O
Republican O
colleagues O
would O
be O
for O
something O
such O
as O
this. O

We’ve O
basically O
paid O
down O
debt O
, O
(which) O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

We’ve O
accelerated O
permitting O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O

And O
we’ve O
increased O
production O
of O
energy O
, O
which O
is O
what O
they O
want O
. O
We’ve O
done O
things O
that O
we O
should O
be O
doing O
together O
, O
” O
Manchin B-PER
, O
who O
represents O
West B-LOC
Virginia I-LOC
, O
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Jake B-PER
Tapper I-PER
on O
“State B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Union I-ORG
.” O
Manchin B-PER
said O
the O
bill O
he O
negotiated O
with O
Senate B-ORG
Majority I-ORG
Leader I-ORG
Chuck B-PER
Schumer I-PER
is O
not O
“inflammatory O
” O
despite O
some O
reports O
promoted O
by O
Republicans B-MISC
that O
show O
it O
could O
add O
to O
inflation O
and O
raise O
taxes O
. O
“Well O
, O
we O
found O
that O
they O
were O
wrong O
. O
And O
people O
can O
be O
wrong O
, O
but O
how O
in O
the O
world O
can O
it O
be O
inflammatory O
?” O
Manchin B-PER
told O
Tapper B-PER
. O
“How O
can O
it O
add O
flames O
to O
inflation O
fires O
right O
now O
if O
you’re O
paying O
down O
debt O
?” O
He O
added O
: O
“We’re O
doing O
everything O
we O
can O
to O
make O
sure O
we O
attack O
the O
problem O
. O
And O
these O
are O
solutions O
to O
the O
problems O
we O
have O
. O
So O
I O
know O
the O
ones O
playing O
politics O
with O
it O
.” O
When O
Manchin B-PER
and O
Schumer B-PER
, O
a O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
Democrat O
, O
announced O
the O
deal O
last O
week O
, O
it O
represented O
a O
breakthrough O
after O
more O
than O
a O
year O
of O
negotiations O
that O
have O
collapsed O
time O
and O
again O
. O
Though O
many O
details O
have O
not O
been O
disclosed O
, O
the O
measure O
would O
invest O
$369 O
billion O
into O
energy O
and O
climate O
change O
programs O
, O
with O
the O
goal O
of O
reducing O
carbon O
emissions O
by O
40% O
by O
2030 O
, O
according O
to O
a O
one-page O
fact O
sheet O
. O
It O
would O
also O
address O
the O
permitting O
of O
energy O
infrastructure O
, O
which O
could O
ease O
the O
path O
for O
a O
shale O
gas O
pipeline O
in O
West B-LOC
Virginia I-LOC
. O
Manchin B-PER
on O
Sunday O
was O
asked O
about O
getting O
fellow O
moderate O
Democratic O
Sen B-ORG

Kyrsten B-PER
Sinema’s I-PER
support O
for O
the O
legislation O

Sen. O
Sinema B-PER
is O
my O
dear O
friend O
. O
We O
work O
very O
close O
together O
on O
so O
many O
things O
, O
and O
she O
has O
so O
much O
in O
this O
piece O
of O
legislation O
. O
She’s O
formed O
quite O
a O
bit O
of O
and O
worked O
on O
it O
very O
hard O
. O
And O
with O
that O
, O
she’s O
brought O
down O
drug O
prices O
, O
she’s O
been O
very O
instrumental O
in O
letting O
Medicare B-ORG
go O
ahead O
and O
negotiate O
for O
lower O
drug O
prices O
, O
” O
Manchin B-PER
said O
of O
the O
Arizona B-LOC
senator O
. O
He O
added O
: O
“ O
I O
think O
that O
basically O
when O
she O
looks O
at O
the O
bill O
and O
sees O
the O
whole O
spectrum O
of O
what O
we’re O
doing O
… O
hopefully O
she O
will O
be O
positive O
about O
it O
, O
but O
she’ll O
make O
her O
decision O
and O
I O
respect O
that O
. O
” O
Manchin B-PER
also O
defended O
a O
provision O
in O
the O
bill O
that O
would O
impose O
a O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
on O
certain O
corporations O
. O
“ O
People O
should O
be O
paying O
their O
fair O
share O
, O
especially O
the O
largest O
corporations O
in O
America B-LOC
that O
have O
a O
billion O
dollars O
of O
value O
or O
greater O
. O
Can’t O
they O
pay O
at O
least O
15% O
, O
so O
that O
we O
can O
move O
forward O
and O
be O
the O
leader O
of O
the O
world O
and O
the O
superpower O
that O
we O
are O
?” O
he O
told O
Tapper B-ORG
, O
adding O
that O
the O
bill O
“ O
was O
not O
putting O
a O
burden O
on O
any O
taxpayers O
whatsoever O
.” O
Republicans B-ORG
on O
the O
Senate B-ORG
Finance I-ORG
Committee I-ORG
on O
Saturday O
released O
data O
from O
the O
nonpartisan O
Joint B-ORG
Committee I-ORG
on O
Taxation B-ORG
that O
showed O
that O
Americans B-MISC
of O
all O
incomes O
would O
see O
their O
federal O
taxes O
rise O
under O
the O
climate O
and O
health O
care O
package O
. O
That O
analysis O
, O
however O
, O
looked O
at O
the O
indirect O
effect O
of O
the O
15% O
minimum O
tax O
provision O
on O
corporations O
. O

Economists O
assume O
companies O
would O
then O
pass O
along O
part O
of O
their O
tax O
increase O
to O
employees O
by O
reducing O
their O
after-tax O
wages O
and O
job O
opportunities O
. O
Also O
, O
shareholders O
would O
take O
a O
hit O
since O
the O
value O
of O
their O
stock O
holdings O
, O
including O
those O
held O
in O
pensions O
and O
mutual O
funds O
, O
would O
likely O
decline O
. O
Manchin B-PER
said O
Sunday O
he O
hopes O
the O
legislation O
passes O
before O
the O
August B-LOC
recess O
, O
which O
is O
what O
Democratic B-MISC
leadership O
is O
hoping O
for O
. O
The O
senator’s O
support O
is O
notable O
given O
his O
stance O
earlier O
this O
month O
that O
he O
“ O
unequivocally O
” O
wouldn’t O
support O
the O
climate O
or O
tax O
provisions O
of O
the O
Democratic B-MISC
economic O
package O
, O
which O
appeared O
to O
torpedo O
any O
hope O
Democrats B-MISC
had O
of O
passing O
legislation O
to O
fight O
climate O
change O
in O
the O
near O
future O
. O
But O
he O
told O
Tapper B-PER
on O
Sunday O
that O
he O
“ O
never O
did O
walk O
away O
” O
from O
negotiations O
with O
Schumer B-PER
. O
“ O
I O
never O
did O
walk O
away O
, O
but O
we O
reorganized O
the O
bill O
, O
if O
you O
will O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O

What O
we O
had O
before O
that O
, O
there O
were O
things O
in O
there O
that O
I O
considered O
and O
thought O
could O
be O
considered O
to O
be O
inflammatory O
. O
… O
Inflation O
is O
the O
greatest O
challenge O
we O
have O
in O
our O
country O
right O
now O
– O
around O
in O
my O
state O
and O
around O
the O
country O
. O
So O
that’s O
what O
we’re O
fighting O
. O
Republican O
Sen. O
Pat B-PER
Toomey I-PER
of O
Pennsylvania B-LOC
slammed O
the O
deal O
in O
a O
separate O
appearance O
later O
on O
“State B-ORG
of I-ORG
the I-ORG
Union,” I-ORG
arguing O
that O
it O
would O
negatively O
impact O
the O
US B-ORG
economy O
at O
a O
critical O
time O
. O
“We O
haven’t O
seen O
any O
text O
, O
we O
don’t O
even O
know O
what O
it O
looks O
like O
. O

So O
this O
is O
a O
disaster O
. O
This O
is O
going O
to O
make O
our O
recession O
worse O
. O
It’s O
going O
to O
make O
inflation O
worse O
. O
It’s O
not O
gonna O
do O
any O
good O
. O
I O
am O
really O
surprised O
that O
Joe B-PER
agreed O
to O
this O
, O
” O
he O
told O
Tapper B-ORG
. O
This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
to O
include O
additional O
information O
from O
the O
interview O
. O

Amazon B-ORG
(AMZN) O
has O
agreed O
to O
buy O
iRobot B-ORG
, O
the O
maker O
of O
the O
popular O
Roomba B-MISC
vacuum O
, O
in O
an O
all-cash O
deal O
valued O
at O
about O
$1.7 O
billion O
, O
including O
debt O
, O
the O
two O
companies O
announced O
Friday O
. O
The O
deal O
, O
which O
is O
pending O
approval O
from O
shareholders O
and O
regulators O
, O
has O
the O
potential O
to O
expand O
Amazon’s B-ORG
robotics O
lineup O
and O
deepen O
its O
presence O
in O
consumers’ O
homes O
. O

Last O
year O
, O
Amazon B-ORG
introduced O
a O
home O
robot O
called O
Astro O
. O
The O
$999 O
20-pound O
dog-like O
robot O
zooms O
from O
room O
to O
room O
, O
capturing O
live O
video O
and O
learning O
your O
habits O
. O
“ O
Over O
many O
years O
, O
the O
iRobot B-ORG
team O
has O
proven O
its O
ability O
to O
reinvent O
how O
people O
clean O
with O
products O
that O
are O
incredibly O
practical O
and O
inventive O
, O
said O
Dave B-PER
Limp I-PER
, O
SVP O
of O
Amazon B-ORG
Devices O
. O
“ O
I’m O
excited O
to O
work O
with O
the O
iRobot B-ORG
team O
to O
invent O
in O
ways O
that O
make O
customers’ O
lives O
easier O
and O
more O
enjoyable O
.” O
After O
launching O
the O
first O
Roomba B-ORG
in O
2002 O
, O
iRobot B-ORG
went O
on O
to O
develop O
multiple O
generations O
of O
robot O
vacuums O
, O
mops O
and O
air O
purifiers O
that O
will O
now O
fall O
under O
Amazon’s B-ORG
product O
catalog O
. O
For O
Amazon B-ORG
, O
the O
acquisition O
represents O
“ O
a O
further O
foray O
into O
the O
market O
of O
home O
automation O
, O
according O
to O
Neil B-PER
Saunders I-PER
, O
Managing O
Director O
of O
GlobalData B-ORG
, O
a O
data O
analytics O
and O
consulting O
firm O
. O
“ O
It O
is O
easy O
to O
see O
how O
Amazon B-ORG
will O
integrate O
products O
like O
Roomba B-ORG
into O
the O
Alexa B-ORG
and O
Prime B-ORG
ecosystems O
, O
so O
that O
people O
have O
one O
central O
point O
of O
monitoring O
and O
control O
for O
many O
tasks O
and O
activities O
, O
he O
said O
. O
The O
deal O
also O
represents O
the O
second O
notable O
billion-dollar O
acquisition O
from O
Amazon B-ORG
in O
as O
many O
weeks O
. O
The O
e-commerce O
giant O
entered O
into O
an O
agreement O
last O
month O
to O
buy O
primary O
healthcare O
provider O
One B-ORG
Medical I-ORG
in O
an O
all-cash O
deal O
valued O
at O
approximately O
$3.9 O
billion O
. O
Shares O
of O
iRobot B-ORG
surged O
nearly O
20% O
in O
pre-market O
trading O
Friday O
following O
the O
announcement O
. O

خبر O
سار O
للراغبين O
بالسفر O
لأوروبا B-LOC
.. O
لن O
يفرض O
الاتحاد B-ORG
الأوروبي I-ORG
رسوم O
دخول O
لزيارته O
بعد O
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

Judith B-PER
Durham I-PER
, O
an O
Australian B-LOC
folk O
music O
star O
and O
lead O
singer O
of O
The B-ORG
Seekers I-ORG
, O
has O
died O
, O
according O
to O
a O
statement O
from O
her O
record O
label O
. O
She O
was O
79 O
. O

After O
a O
brief O
stay O
in O
the O
Alfred B-LOC
Hospital I-LOC
, O
Judith B-PER
was O
admitted O
to O
Palliative B-MISC
Care I-MISC
on O
Friday O
5 O
August O
, O
where O
she O
passed O
away O
peacefully O
that O
evening O
. O
Her O
death O
was O
a O
result O
of O
complications O
from O
a O
long-standing O
chronic O
lung O
disease O
, O
” O
Musicoast B-ORG
and O
Universal B-ORG
Music I-ORG
Australia I-ORG
said O
in O
a O
statement O
shared O
on O
the O
verified O
Facebook B-ORG
page O
for O
The B-ORG
Seekers I-ORG
. O
“ O
Our O
lives O
are O
changed O
forever O
losing O
our O
treasured O
lifelong O
friend O
and O
shining O
star O
. O

Her O
struggle O
was O
intense O
and O
heroic O
– O
never O
complaining O
of O
her O
destiny O
and O
fully O
accepting O
its O
conclusion O
. O
Her O
magnificent O
musical O
legacy O
Keith B-PER
, O
Bruce B-PER
and O
I O
are O
so O
blessed O
to O
share O
, O
” O
her O
former O
bandmates O
Keith B-PER
Potger I-PER
, O
Bruce B-PER
Woodley I-PER
and O
Athol B-PER
Guy I-PER
added O
in O
the O
post O
. O
Durham B-PER
helped O
open O
the O
door O
for O
Australian B-LOC
artists O
to O
achieve O
international O
fame O
. O
The O
Seekers B-ORG
, O
formed O
in O
1962 O
, O
were O
considered O
the O
first O
Australian B-LOC
pop O
band O
to O
achieve O
mainstream O
success O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
Kingdom I-LOC
and O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O
The O
group’s O
hits O
included O
“ O
Georgy B-MISC
Girl I-MISC
” O
and O
“ O
A O
World B-MISC
of O
Our O
Own I-MISC
.” O
Durham B-PER
left O
The O
Seekers B-ORG
to O
pursue O
a O
solo O
career O
in O
1968 O
and O
released O
several O
solo O
albums O
but O
continued O
to O
reunite O
and O
tour O
with O
the O
band O
in O
the O
decades O
after O
. O
Several O
prominent O
Australians B-LOC
posted O
tributes O
Saturday O
. O

A O
national O
treasure O
and O
an O
Australian O
icon O
, O
Judith B-PER
Durham I-PER
gave O
voice O
to O
a O
new O
strand O
of O
our O
identity O
and O
helped O
blaze O
a O
trail O
for O
a O
new O
generation O
of O
Aussie B-LOC
artists O
, O
” O
wrote O
Australian B-LOC
Prime O
Minister O
Anthony B-PER
Albanese I-PER
on O
Twitter B-ORG
. O
“Her O
kindness O
will O
be O
missed O
by O
many O
, O
the O
anthems O
she O
gave O
to O
our O
nation O
will O
never O
be O
forgotten O
. O
Australian B-LOC
comedian O
and O
actress O
Magda B-PER
Szubanski I-PER
shared O
her O
“deepest O
condolences O
to O
her O
loved O
ones O
” O
on O
Twitter B-ORG
. O
“Her O
beautiful O
, O
crystalline O
voice O
was O
the O
naive O
but O
knowing O
siren O
song O
of O
my O
childhood O
, O
” O
wrote O
Szubanski B-PER
. O
Tanya B-PER
Plibersek I-PER
, O
Australian B-LOC
Minister O
for O
the O
Environment O
and O
Water O
, O
called O
Durham B-PER
“a O
trailblazer O
and O
an O
icon O
in O
Australian B-LOC
music O
” O
on O
Twitter B-ORG
. O
“Her O
songs O
will O
live O
on O
forever O
. O

The O
FBI B-ORG
’s O
search O
of O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
’s O
Mar-a-Lago B-LOC
estate O
on O
Monday O
makes O
one O
thing O
crystal O
clear O
: O
The O
legal O
vise O
is O
tightening O
around O
the O
former O
President O
even O
as O
he O
weighs O
whether O
to O
run O
for O
president O
again O
in O
2024 O
. O
“ O
My O
beautiful O
home O
, O
Mar-A-Lago B-LOC
in O
Palm B-LOC
Beach I-LOC
, O
Florida B-LOC
, O
is O
currently O
under O
siege O
, O
raided O
, O
and O
occupied O
by O
a O
large O
group O
of O
FBI B-ORG
agents O
, O
” O
Trump B-PER
posted O
on O
Truth B-ORG
Social I-ORG
, O
his O
preferred O
social O
network O
, O
on O
Monday O
evening O
. O
He O
added O
that O
“ O
they O
even O
broke O
into O
my O
safe O
. O
Agents O
appear O
to O
be O
focused O
on O
the O
area O
of O
the O
sprawling O
estate O
where O
Trump B-PER
’s O
living O
quarters O
and O
offices O
are O
located O
. O
It O
was O
not O
immediately O
clear O
what O
the O
FBI B-ORG
was O
after O
– O
or O
what O
, O
specifically O
, O
the O
agents O
were O
looking O
for O
. O
Boxes O
of O
items O
were O
taken O
during O
the O
search O
, O
a O
source O
familiar O
with O
the O
investigation O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
We O
do O
know O
that O
federal O
investigators O
issued O
a O
subpoena O
to O
the O
National B-ORG
Archives I-ORG
and O
Records B-ORG
Administration I-ORG
in O
May O
for O
access O
to O
classified O
documents O
that O
were O
taken O
to O
Trump B-PER
’s O
home O
in O
Florida B-LOC
– O
part O
of O
a O
grand O
jury O
investigation O
into O
whether O
Trump B-PER
or O
anyone O
else O
close O
to O
him O
mishandled O
classified O
documents O
that O
he O
took O
with O
him O
after O
leaving O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
last O
January O
. O
Earlier O
this O
year O
, O
15 O
boxes O
of O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
records O
that O
Trump B-PER
had O
brought O
to O
Mar-a-Lago B-LOC
were O
retrieved O
and O
returned O
to O
the O
National B-ORG
Archives I-ORG
. O
Among O
the O
items O
in O
the O
returned O
boxes O
included O
letters O
from O
North B-LOC
Korean I-LOC
dictator O
Kim B-PER
Jong I-PER
Un I-PER
and O
former O
President O
Barack B-PER
Obama I-PER
. O
The O
FBI B-ORG
search O
also O
comes O
on O
the O
same O
day O
that O
The O
New B-ORG
York I-ORG
Times I-ORG
’ O
 Maggie B-PER
Haberman I-PER
revealed O
photos O
of O
torn-up O
notes O
appearing O
to O
bear O
Trump B-PER
’s O
distinctive O
penmanship O
in O
toilets O
– O
one O
of O
which O
was O
in O
the O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
. O
That’s O
consistent O
with O
this O
CNN B-ORG
reporting O
from O
mid-February O
: O
“ O
Three O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
officials O
told O
CNN B-ORG
they O
saw O
Trump B-PER
, O
on O
numerous O
occasions O
, O
manually O
destroy O
papers O
he O
was O
no O
longer O
interested O
in O
or O
had O
finished O
reviewing O
– O
a O
practice O
that O
made O
it O
difficult O
for O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
staff O
secretaries O
to O
preserve O
presidential O
records O
. O
Those O
officials O
said O
the O
former O
President O
sorted O
through O
file O
boxes O
in O
a O
rather O
methodical O
way O
– O
tearing O
up O
newspaper O
clippings O
or O
drafts O
of O
tweets O
that O
he O
had O
rejected O
and O
tossing O
them O
to O
the O
floor O
, O
or O
stacking O
papers O
he O
wished O
to O
hang O
on O
to O
in O
a O
disorderly O
stack O
atop O
his O
desk O
. O
Disposing O
of O
notes O
, O
emails O
and O
other O
forms O
of O
presidential O
communication O
is O
against O
federal O
law O
as O
laid O
out O
in O
the O
Presidential B-MISC
Records I-MISC
Act I-MISC
. O
(Under O
the O
Act O
, O
all O
correspondence O
of O
a O
president O
is O
owned O
, O
ultimately O
, O
by O
the O
public O
) O
The O
FBI B-ORG
’s O
execution O
of O
a O
search O
warrant O
also O
comes O
just O
days O
after O
the O
news O

broke O
that O
lawyers O
for O
Trump B-PER
are O
in O
touch O
with O
the O
Justice B-ORG
Department I-ORG
in O
regards O
to O
its O
ongoing O
investigation O
into O
the O
January B-MISC
6 I-MISC
2021 I-MISC
, O
riot O
at O
the O
US B-LOC
Capitol I-LOC
. O
As O
CNN B-ORG
first O
reported O
: O
“ O
The O
talks O
revolve O
around O
whether O
Trump B-PER
would O
be O
able O
to O
shield O
conversations O
he O
had O
while O
he O
was O
president O
from O
federal O
investigators O
. O
“ O
In O
recent O
weeks O
, O
investigators O
have O
moved O
aggressively O
into O
Trump’s B-PER
orbit O
, O
subpoenaing O
top O
former O
White B-ORG
House I-ORG
officials O
, O
focusing O
on O
efforts O
to O
overturn O
the O
2020 B-MISC
election O
and O
executing O
searches O
of O
lawyers O
who O
sought O
to O
aid O
those O
efforts O
. O
Trump B-PER
, O
CNN B-ORG
has O
also O
reported O
, O
has O
quizzed O
his O
legal O
team O
of O
late O
as O
to O
whether O
he O
might O
be O
indicted O
, O
although O
he O
himself O
is O
skeptical O
it O
will O
come O
to O
that O
. O
(Worth O
noting O
: O
Trump B-PER
is O
not O
a O
lawyer O
) O
The O
series O
of O
developments O
– O
culminating O
with O
the O
high-profile O
search O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
home O
on O
Monday O
– O
reinforce O
a O
fundamental O
fact O
of O
Trump’s B-PER
situation O
: O
He O
is O
far O
more O
likely O
to O
see O
a O
2024 B-MISC
run O
for O
president O
curtailed O
by O
legal O
problems O
than O
political O
ones O
. O
Politically O
, O
Trump B-PER
remains O
the O
800-pound O
gorilla O
in O
the O
Republican B-ORG
field O
. O
Over O
the O
weekend O
, O
he O
convincingly O
won O
a O
straw O
poll O
at O
a O
conservative O
gathering O
in O
Texas B-LOC
. O

And, O
he O
has O
all O
but O
announced O
his O
intention O
to O
run O
again, O
with O
the O
major O
question O
at O
this O
point O
being O
when O
he O
will O
announce O
his O
candidacy O
– O
not O
whether O
he O
will O
do O
so. O
Trump B-PER
posted O
a O
campaign-style O
video O
on O
his O
Truth B-ORG
Social I-ORG
site O
Tuesday O
morning, O
saying O
“the O
best O
is O
yet O
to O
come.” O
Trump’s B-PER
mounting O
legal O
woes O
– O
or O
at O
least O
the O
clear O
sense O
that O
this O
variety O
of O
investigations O
is O
getting O
closer O
and O
closer O
to O
him O
– O
complicate O
all O
of O
that. O
Trump B-PER
under O
legal O
fire O
is O
one O
thing O
for O
Republicans B-ORG
to O
accept. O

Trump O
under O
indictment O
is O
something O
else O
entirely O

We O
are O
, O
of O
course O
, O
not O
there O
yet O
. O
But O
, O
Monday’s O
FBI B-ORG
activity O
suggests O
that O
Trump’s B-PER
legal O
problems O
are O
likely O
to O
get O
worse O
before O
they O
get O
better O
. O
And O
they O
may O
get O
way O
, O
way O
worse O
. O

This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
with O
additional O
information O
. O

In O
Michigan’s B-LOC
jam-packed O
Republican B-ORG
primary O
fight O
for O
governor O
, O
former O
President O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
is O
trying O
to O
tip O
the O
scales O
. O
Just O
days O
before O
the O
Tuesday O
primary O
, O
Trump B-PER
threw O
his O
support O
behind O
Tudor B-PER
Dixon I-PER
, O
a O
conservative O
commentator O
who O
has O
coalesced O
support O
from O
prominent O
Republicans O
in O
the O
state O
, O
even O
as O
she O
beats O
back O
criticism O
that O
she’s O
an O
establishment O
candidate O
who O
isn’t O
“MAGA” O
enough O
to O
inspire O
the O
GOP B-ORG
base O
. O
The O
Mitten B-LOC
State’s I-LOC
prolonged O
, O
often O
bitter O
, O
Republican B-ORG
primary O
saw O
a O
handful O
of O
candidates O
disqualified O
from O
the O
ballot O
, O
while O
another O
– O
still O
in O
the O
race O
– O
was O
arrested O
for O
his O
alleged O
participation O
in O
the O
January O
6 O
, O
2021 O
, O
riot O
. O
Dixon B-PER
is O
up O
against O
a O
handful O
of O
Trumpian O
candidates O
, O
some O
of O
whom O
have O
fully O
embraced O
the O
former O
President’s O
lies O
about O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O

Dixon B-PER
’s O
embrace O
of O
those O
falsehoods O
has O
been O
more O
tepid O
. O
In O
a O
May O
debate O
, O
she O
raised O
her O
hand O
and O
confirmed O
, O
yes O
, O
she O
did O
believe O
Trump B-PER
won O
Michigan B-LOC
– O
a O
state O
he O
lost O
by O
more O
than O
154,000 O
votes O
in O
2020 O
. O
But O
in O
an O
interview O
with O
CNN B-ORG
, O
she O
offered O
a O
more O
muted O
response O
. O

I O
’ve O
talked O
about O
this O
at O
length O
, O
about O
the O
2020 O
election O
, O
” O
Dixon B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
It O
was O
unlike O
any O
election O
we O
had O
ever O
seen O
obviously O
because O
of O
the O
pandemic O
. O
But O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
, O
there O
were O
some O
things O
that O
happened O
in O
Michigan B-LOC
that O
didn’t O
happen O
in O
other O
states O
, O
which O
are O
very O
concerning O
. O
In O
interviews O
with O
CNN B-ORG
, O
Dixon B-PER
’s O
opponents O
quickly O
slammed O
her O
for O
appearing O
to O
water O
down O
her O
views O
on O
the O
2020 O
election O
. O
Garrett B-PER
Soldano I-PER
, O
a O
chiropractor O
vying O
for O
the O
GOP B-ORG
nomination O
, O
panned O
Dixon B-PER
for O
dodging O
the O
2020 O
election O
question O
and O
doubled O
down O
on O
his O
support O
for O
the O
former O
President O
. O
“ O
The O
election O
, O
in O
my O
humble O
opinion O
, O
was O
stolen O
, O
” O
he O
said O
in O
an O
interview O
. O
“ O
I O
’m O
not O
even O
endorsed O
by O
President O
Trump B-PER
, O
and O
I O
still O
have O
his O
back O
. O
Soldano B-PER
then O
turned O
his O
stare O
straight O
down O
the O
lens O
of O
a O
CNN B-ORG
camera O
, O
seemingly O
hoping O
to O
address O
Trump B-PER
directly O
. O
“ O
Even O
though O
, O
sir O
, O
you O
didn’t O
endorse O
me O
, O
you O
’re O
still O
my O
President O
, O
” O
Soldano B-PER
said O
. O
Businessman-turned-candidate O
Kevin B-PER
Rinke I-PER
also O
bashed O
Dixon B-PER
for O
dancing O
around O
election O
falsehoods O
. O
“ O
She O
got O
an O
endorsement O
and O
within O
48 O
hours O
when O
she O
was O
asked O
on O
national O
TV O
if O
the O
election O
was O
stolen O
, O
she O
changed O
her O
mind O
, O
” O
Rinke B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
That O
's O
what O
politicians O
do O
. O
Tudor B-PER
Dixon I-PER
is O
the O
Republican O
version O
of O
Gretchen B-PER
Whitmer I-PER
– O
‘ O
I O
’ll O
say O
anything O
, O
I O
’ll O
do O
anything O
for O
position O
and O
power O
, O
'” O
, O
he O
said O
referring O
to O
the O
state O
’s O
Democratic O
governor O
. O
Rinke B-PER
didn’t O
go O
so O
far O
as O
to O
claim O
the O
election O
was O
stolen O
and O
acknowledged O
that O
Joe B-PER
Biden I-PER
is O
the O
President O
. O

Still, O
he O
said O
he O
believes O
there O
were O
“irregularities” O
in O
2020. O
Meantime, O
Ryan B-PER
Kelley, I-PER
a O
real O
estate O
broker O
in O
the O
race, O
has O
essentially O
turned O
his O
arrest O
for O
allegedly O
participating O
in O
the O
Capitol B-LOC
riot O
into O
a O
campaign O
rallying O
cry. O
“Look O
how O
hard O
these O
people O
are O
trying O
to O
silence O
me,” O
Kelley B-PER
said O
in O
a O
July B-MISC
GOP B-ORG
primary O
debate. O

I O
got O
arrested O
. O
I O
got O
kicked O
off O
Airbnb B-ORG
. O
He O
has O
pleaded O
not O
guilty O
to O
the O
misdemeanor O
charges O
he O
faces O
and O
has O
continued O
to O
falsely O
claim O
Trump B-PER
won O
in O
2020 O
. O
Republican B-ORG
activists O
here O
have O
rallied O
behind O
Trump-loving O
, O
election-denying O
candidates O
. O

At O
an O
endorsement O
convention O
earlier O
this O
year O
, O
Republicans B-ORG
backed O
Kristina B-PER
Karamo I-PER
for O
secretary O
of O
state O
and O
Matthew B-PER
DePerno I-PER
for O
attorney O
general O
, O
paving O
their O
path O
for O
official O
nominations O
later O
this O
year O
. O
If O
they O
win O
in O
November B-MISC
, O
they O
would O
be O
in O
key O
positions O
to O
oversee O
the O
state’s O
elections O
. O

But O
the O
prospect O
of O
having O
Dixon B-PER
atop O
the O
ticket O
has O
rankled O
some O
Trump B-PER
supporters O
, O
particularly O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
her O
less-than-enthusiastic O
embrace O
of O
the O
election O
falsehoods O
fueling O
the O
base O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
she’s O
given O
lip O
service O
to O
President O
Trump B-PER
and O
his O
supporters O
on O
those O
issues O
but O
only O
when O
truly O
pushed O
, O
” O
GOP B-ORG
political O
strategist O
John B-PER
Yob I-PER
said O
in O
an O
interview O
. O
“ O
President O
Trump B-PER
still O
is O
very O
popular O
with O
conservative O
voters O
, O
so O
I O
think O
that O
his O
endorsement O
will O
definitely O
have O
an O
impact O
on O
this O
race O
, O
” O
Yob B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
However O
, O
it O
also O
puts O
things O
in O
a O
bit O
of O
a O
precarious O
situation O
with O
some O
of O
his O
supporters O
being O
left O
dazed O
and O
confused O
because O
they’ve O
been O
behind O
other O
, O
maybe O
more O
MAGA-centric O
, O
candidates O
and O
now O
all O
of O
a O
sudden O
he’s O
endorsed O
the O
establishment O
. O
The O
former O
President’s O
team O
doesn’t O
share O
the O
concern O
that O
Dixon B-PER
may O
not O
be O
as O
vocal O
on O
election O
issues O
, O
said O
a O
person O
close O
to O
Trump B-PER
. O
Dixon B-PER
has O
largely O
shrugged O
off O
the O
criticism O
. O
“ O
I O
think O
that’s O
interesting O
, O
” O
she O
said O
of O
the O
election-related O
barbs O
from O
her O
GOP B-ORG
opponents O
, O
“ O
because O
my O
Democrat B-ORG
opponents O
actually O
have O
a O
whole O
thing O
– O
a O
whole O
list O
of O
reasons O
they O
hate O
me O
because O
of O
the O
election O
, O
right O
? O
I O
guess O
it’s O
just O
a O
campaign O
tactic O
.” O
Dixon B-PER
said O
she O
believed O
she O
could O
get O
a O
boost O
from O
the O
Trump B-PER
endorsement O
but O
declined O
to O
say O
whether O
she O
would O
back O
him O
if O
he O
runs O
again O
for O
president O
in O
2024 O
, O
insisting O
that O
she O
is O
focused O
on O
2022 O
. O
“ O
I O
feel O
honored O
to O
get O
the O
endorsement O
.” O

It O
feels O
like O
we’re O
really O
bringing O
everybody O
in O
the O
Republican B-ORG
Party I-ORG
together,” O
she O
said. O
“So, O
we O
feel O
really O
good O
about O
how O
Tuesday O
is O
going O
to O
end O
up, O
but O
we’re O
still O
fighting. O

Rapper O
Fetty B-PER
Wap I-PER
was O
arrested O
Monday O
after O
he O
allegedly O
threatened O
to O
kill O
someone O
and O
showed O
a O
gun O
during O
a O
FaceTime O
call O
last O
year O
, O
according O
to O
a O
court O
filing O
. O
Fetty B-PER
Wap I-PER
was O
indicted O
and O
arrested O
in O
October O
along O
with O
five O
others O
on O
a O
drug O
trafficking O
conspiracy O
charge O
. O
He O
pleaded O
not O
guilty O
and O
was O
released O
on O
$500,000 O
bond O
as O
he O
awaited O
trial O
, O
and O
one O
of O
the O
conditions O
listed O
in O
the O
release O
order O
stated O
that O
he O
“must O
not O
possess O
a O
firearm O
, O
destructive O
device O
, O
or O
other O
weapon O
.” O
Another O
said O
that O
he O
“must O
not O
violate O
any O
federal O
, O
state O
or O
local O
law O
. O
Prosecutors O
accuse O
Fetty B-PER
Wap I-PER
, O
whose O
legal O
name O
is O
Willie B-PER
Junior I-PER
Maxwell I-PER
II I-PER
, O
of O
violating O
those O
conditions O
during O
a O
December O
11 O
FaceTime O
call O
in O
which O
he O
was O
allegedly O
seen O
holding O
a O
gun O
and O
threatening O
to O
kill O
an O
unnamed O
man O
, O
according O
to O
an O
affidavit O
supporting O
revocation O
filed O
in O
the O
Eastern B-ORG
District I-ORG
Court I-ORG
of O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
. O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
Magistrate O
Judge O
Steven B-PER
Locke I-PER
revoked O
the O
rapper’s O
bond O
following O
his O
Monday O
arrest O
in O
New B-LOC
Jersey I-LOC
, O
according O
to O
John B-PER
Marzulli I-PER
, O
spokesperson O
for O
the O
Eastern B-ORG
District I-ORG
of O
New B-LOC
York I-LOC
. O
In O
a O
video O
recording O
of O
the O
call O
, O
Fetty B-PER
Wap I-PER
allegedly O
pointed O
the O
gun O
toward O
him O
over O
the O
phone O
, O
the O
affidavit O
said O
. O

The O
man O
is O
identified O
as O
John B-PER
Doe I-PER
in O
the O
document O
. O
“ O
The O
defendant O
then O
says O
to O
John B-PER
Doe I-PER
‘Imma O
kill O
you O
and O
everybody O
you O
with O
,’” O
according O
to O
the O
document O
. O
The O
affidavit O
alleges O
that O
the O
rapper O
threatened O
the O
man O
several O
times O
during O
the O
call O
. O
CNN B-ORG
has O
reached O
out O
to O
an O
attorney O
for O
Fetty B-PER
Wap I-PER
for O
comment O
. O
CNN’s B-ORG
Elizabeth B-PER
Wolfe I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

A O
bat O
infestation O
has O
caused O
a O
fire O
station O
in O
Nevada B-LOC
to O
close O
for O
an O
“undetermined O
amount O
of O
time,” O
according O
to O
a O
release O
from O
the O
Truckee B-ORG
Meadows I-ORG
Fire I-ORG
Protection I-ORG
District. O
“Due O
to O
an O
infestation O
of O
bats, O
it O
has O
been O
determined O
that O
the O
station O
is O
a O
health O
and O
safety O
risk O
to O
fire O
crews,” O
the O
release O
said. O
“Bats O
have O
been O
flying O
in O
the O
living O
quarters O
and O
dead O
bats O
have O
been O
found O
in O
the O
apparatus O
bay.” O
Fire O
Station O
30, O
which O
dates O
to O
the O
1950s, O
is O
located O
about O
20 O
miles O
south O
of O
Reno, B-LOC
Nevada, I-LOC
and O
roughly O
10 O
miles O
north O
of O
Carson B-LOC
City. I-LOC
The O
station O
is O
leased O
to O
the O
fire O
protection O
district O
from O
the O
state O
of O
Nevada. B-LOC

First O
responders O
who O
work O
at O
the O
station O
are O
being O
relocated O
to O
a O
nearby O
station O
as O
the O
bat O
infestation O
is O
addressed O
. O
The O
Truckee B-ORG
Meadows I-ORG
Fire I-ORG
Protection I-ORG
District I-ORG
also O
plans O
to O
increase O
its O
coordination O
with O
the O
Carson B-LOC
City I-LOC
Fire B-ORG
Department I-ORG
to O
the O
south O
end O
of O
Washoe B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
. O
“ O
The O
District O
will O
consult O
with O
experts O
to O
determine O
what O
preventative O
and O
remediation O
work O
is O
needed O
to O
eliminate O
the O
bat O
colonies O
and O
associated O
hazards O
, O
” O
the O
release O
said O
. O

This O
isn’t O
the O
first O
time O
that O
the O
fire O
district O
has O
faced O
a O
bat O
problem O
. O
“ O
The O
Fire B-ORG
District I-ORG
attempted O
to O
remediate O
the O
problem O
in O
2015 O
, O
only O
to O
have O
the O
bats O
return O
, O
” O
the O
release O
said O
. O
“ O
Staff O
will O
review O
possible O
options O
including O
contamination O
cleanup O
. O
The O
fire O
district O
also O
notes O
that O
rabies O
is O
a O
concern O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
bats O
, O
along O
with O
other O
diseases O
that O
can O
be O
transmitted O
to O
humans O
. O

An O
attorney O
for O
notorious O
Russian B-LOC
arms O
dealer O
Viktor B-PER
Bout I-PER
said O
Monday O
he O
is O
“confident” O
the O
proposed O
prisoner O
swap O
of O
his O
client O
for O
Americans O
Brittney B-PER
Griner I-PER
and O
Paul B-PER
Whelan I-PER
is O
going O
to O
happen O
. O
“I O
do O
have O
some O
information O
about O
the O
progress O
of O
how O
things O
are O
going O
… O
But O
that O
information O
comes O
from O
the O
Russian B-LOC
side O
as O
opposed O
to O
the O
American B-LOC
side O
, O
Bout’s O
attorney O
Steve B-PER
Zissou I-PER
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
John B-PER
Avlon I-PER
on O
“New B-MISC
Day.” I-MISC
“I’m O
confident O
this O
is O
going O
to O
get O
done O
.” O
Zissou B-PER
continued O
, O
“Look O
, O
it’s O
no O
secret O
they’ve O
been O
wanting O
him O
back O
for O
several O
years O
now O
. O
They’ve O
been O
trying O
to O
get O
him O
back O
for O
decades O
. O
That’s O
not O
something O
they’ve O
ever O
kept O
secret O
. O
The O
US B-ORG
has O
offered O
Bout B-PER
, O
who O
is O
serving O
a O
25-year O
US B-ORG
prison O
sentence O
, O
as O
part O
of O
a O
potential O
deal O
to O
secure O
the O
release O
of O
Griner B-PER
and O
Whelan B-PER
. O
But O
Russian B-LOC
officials O
have O
requested O
that O
Vadim B-PER
Krasikov I-PER
, O
a O
former O
colonel O
from O
the O
country’s O
domestic O
spy O
agency O
, O
be O
included O
in O
the O
US’ O
proposed O
swap O
of O
Bout B-PER
for O
Griner B-PER
and O
Whelan B-PER
, O
multiple O
sources O
familiar O
with O
the O
discussions O
have O
told O
CNN B-ORG
. O
Krasikov B-PER
was O
convicted O
in O
December O
of O
murdering O
a O
former O
Chechen B-LOC
fighter O
, O
Zelimkhan B-PER
“Tornike” O
Khangoshvili I-PER
, O
in O
Berlin’s B-LOC
Kleiner B-LOC
Tiergarten I-LOC
in O
2019 O
and O
sentenced O
to O
life O
in O
prison O
. O

The O
request O
was O
seen O
as O
problematic O
for O
several O
reasons O
, O
the O
sources O
told O
CNN B-ORG
, O
among O
them O
that O
Krasikov B-PER
remains O
in O
German B-LOC
custody O
. O

As O
such O
, O
and O
because O
the O
request O
was O
not O
communicated O
formally O
but O
rather O
through O
a O
FSB B-ORG
backchannel O
, O
the O
US B-LOC
government O
did O
not O
view O
it O
as O
a O
legitimate O
counter O
to O
the O
US’ B-LOC
offer O
which O
was O
first O
revealed O
by O
CNN B-ORG
on O
Wednesday O
. O
National B-ORG
Security I-ORG
Council I-ORG
coordinator O
for O
strategic O
communications O
John B-PER
Kirby I-PER
in O
an O
earlier O
interview O
on O
“New B-MISC
Day” I-MISC
called O
the O
Russian’s B-LOC
request O
a O
“bad O
faith O
attempt” O
and O
said O
the O
country O
should O
accept O
the O
US’ B-LOC
offer O
. O
“This O
so-called O
, O
you O
call O
it O
a O
counteroffer O
, O
we O
would O
call O
it O
a O
bad O
faith O
attempt O
to O
avoid O
what O
is O
a O
serious O
proposal O
already O
on O
the O
table O
. O

And O
oh O
, O
by O
the O
way O
Brianna B-PER
, O
has O
been O
on O
the O
table O
now O
for O
several O
weeks O
, O
” O
Kirby B-PER
told O
CNN’s B-ORG
Brianna B-PER
Keilar I-PER
on O
Monday O
. O
“ O
Holding O
two O
Americans B-MISC
who O
have O
been O
wrongfully O
detained O
hostage O
for O
a O
convicted O
murderer O
in O
a O
third O
country O
is O
just O
– O
we O
don’t O
consider O
that O
a O
serious O
counteroffer O
at O
all O
. O
It O
is O
nothing O
more O
than O
a O
bad O
faith O
attempt O
by O
the O
Russians B-MISC
publicly O
to O
avoid O
what O
is O
a O
serious O
proposal O
, O
one O
that O
we O
are O
not O
making O
detailed O
in O
public O
and O
has O
been O
on O
the O
books O
for O
several O
weeks O
and O
we O
urge O
the O
Russians B-MISC
to O
accept O
it O
.” O
On O
Friday O
US B-ORG
Secretary O
of O
State O
Antony B-PER
Blinken I-PER
spoke O
with O
Russian B-LOC
Foreign O
Minster O
Sergey B-PER
Lavrov I-PER
for O
the O
first O
time O
since O
Russia B-LOC
invaded O
Ukraine B-LOC
earlier O
this O
year O
. O
Blinken B-PER
said O
he O
“ O
pressed O
the O
Kremlin B-LOC
to O
accept O
the O
substantial O
proposal O
that O
we O
put O
forth O
on O
the O
release O
of O
Paul B-PER
Whelan I-PER
and O
Brittney B-PER
Griner I-PER
.” O
At O
a O
press O
conference O
on O
Friday O
he O
declined O
to O
say O
whether O
he O
thought O
Russia B-LOC
was O
more O
or O
less O
likely O
to O
move O
on O
the O
proposal O
following O
the O
conversation O
, O
nor O
would O
he O
describe O
how O
Lavrov B-PER
responded O
. O
The O
Russian B-LOC
Foreign O
Ministry O
said O
in O
a O
statement O
following O
the O
call O
that O
Lavrov B-PER
“ O
strongly O
suggested O
to O
Blinken B-PER
that O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
should O
return O
to O
a O
mode O
of O
“ O
quiet O
diplomacy O
” O
regarding O
a O
possible O
prisoner O
exchange O
“ O
without O
any O
dubious O
media O
leaks O
.” O
Prior O
to O
the O
call O
between O
Blinken B-PER
and O
Lavrov B-PER
, O
US B-ORG
officials O
had O
expressed O
frustration O
at O
Moscow’s B-LOC
lack O
of O
substantive O
response O
to O
the O
proposal O
to O
free O
Whelan B-PER
and O
Griner B-PER
. O
State B-ORG
Department I-ORG
spokesperson O
Ned B-PER
Price I-PER
on O
Thursday O
acknowledged O
“ O
this O
has O
not O
moved O
to O
the O
extent O
we O
would O
like O
.” O
CNN’s B-ORG
Natasha B-PER
Bertrand I-PER
, O
Frederik B-PER
Pleitgen I-PER
and O
Jennifer B-PER
Hansler I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

We O
are O
in O
crisis O
mode O
. O
Those O
are O
the O
words O
of O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Program I-ORG
USA’S B-ORG
Barron B-PER
Segar I-PER
, O
when O
asked O
about O
the O
state O
of O
world O
hunger O
. O
There’s O
a O
sense O
of O
urgency O
and O
a O
sense O
of O
acting O
now O
or O
we’re O
going O
to O
see O
the O
world O
slip O
into O
a O
famine O
and O
we’re O
literally O
going O
to O
see O
millions O
of O
lives O
lost O
. O
Many O
countries O
have O
struggled O
with O
food O
insecurity O
and O
hunger O
problems O
in O
the O
past O
, O
but O
recent O
events O
like O
the O
war O
in O
Ukraine B-LOC
have O
exacerbated O
these O
issues O
. O
The O
numbers O
so O
far O
in O
2022 O
are O
staggering O
. O
The B-ORG
UN I-ORG
estimates O
345 O
million O
people O
around O
the O
world O
are O
facing O
acute O
food O
insecurity O
. O
That’s O
almost O
the O
equivalent O
to O
the O
population O
of O
the B-LOC
United I-LOC
States I-LOC
. O

According O
to O
Marie B-PER
Clarke I-PER
, O
Chief O
of O
Programs O
from O
Women B-ORG
for O
Women I-ORG
International I-ORG
, O
those O
numbers O
are O
a O
25% O
increase O
from O
January O
2022 O
, O
right O
before O
the O
start O
of O
the O
war O
in O
Ukraine B-LOC
. O
“ O
The O
last O
massive O
food O
price O
crisis O
and O
food O
crisis O
globally O
was O
between O
about O
2008 O
and O
2010 O
. O
And O
at O
the O
time O
, O
they O
were O
setting O
a O
goal O
of O
zero O
hunger O
, O
by O
2030 O
. O
We O
were O
making O
a O
lot O
of O
progress O
, O
Clarke B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
What O
we’re O
seeing O
right O
now O
, O
is O
this O
massive O
shift O
in O
the O
other O
direction O
. O
Segar B-PER
from O
the O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Program I-ORG
USA I-ORG
breaks O
down O
how O
parts O
of O
the O
world O
are O
now O
on O
the O
brink O
of O
famine O
in O
what O
he O
calls O
the O
“ O
4 O
C’s O
of O
Crisis O
– O
Conflict B-MISC
, O
Climate B-MISC
, O
Cost B-MISC
and O
Covid B-MISC
. O
Conflict O
The O
war O
in O
Ukraine B-LOC
put O
a O
major O
strain O
on O
the O
world’s O
food O
supply O
as O
both O
Russia B-LOC
and O
Ukraine I-LOC
are O
“ O
breadbaskets O
” O
for O
countries O
in O
the O
Middle B-LOC
East I-LOC
and O
Northern B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
. O

Together O
they O
account O
for O
about O
30% O
of O
the O
world’s O
wheat O
trade O
, O
which O
has O
largely O
been O
shut O
down O
since O
Russia’s B-LOC
attacks O
on O
Ukraine’s B-LOC
port O
cities O
like O
Odesa B-LOC
. O
While O
there O
might O
not O
be O
any O
signs O
of O
the O
war O
ending O
soon O
, O
Russia B-LOC
and O
Ukraine B-LOC
recently O
signed O
a O
deal O
resuming O
grain O
exports O
from O
some O
of O
Ukraine’s B-LOC
Black B-LOC
Sea I-LOC
ports O
. O
The O
first O
shipment O
was O
just O
released O
this O
week O
. O

But O
as O
Segar B-PER
reiterates O
, O
the O
shipments O
need O
to O
go O
out O
quickly O
and O
smoothly O
. O
“ O
We’re O
( O
The O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Program I-ORG
) O
on O
standby O
. O
The O
ships O
are O
ready O
. O

Our O
staff O
is O
ready O

Our O
boots O
on O
the O
ground O
are O
ready O
. O
The O
consequences O
of O
us O
not O
getting O
this O
grain O
out O
swiftly O
are O
dire O
. O
It’s O
not O
just O
the O
conflict O
in B-LOC
Ukraine I-LOC
, O
however O
, O
that’s O
causing O
the O
hunger O
crisis O
to O
grow O
. O
In O
Afghanistan B-LOC
, O
an O
economy O
already O
on O
the O
brink O
, O
the O
Taliban B-ORG
takeover O
prompted O
the O
US B-LOC
and O
other O
countries O
to O
freeze O
an O
estimated O
$7 O
billion O
of O
the O
country’s O
foreign O
reserves O
. O
Many O
in O
Afghanistan B-LOC
now O
rely O
on O
help O
from O
organizations O
like O
the O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Program I-ORG
which O
estimates O
over O
36 O
million O
people O
there O
lack O
sufficient O
food O
. O
That’s O
about O
90% O
of O
the O
population O
. O
Cost O
The O
Ukraine B-LOC
war’s O
economic O
impact O
is O
global O
. O
Marianne B-PER
Kajokaya I-PER
and O
Angelina B-PER
Ajonye I-PER
with O
Women B-ORG
for O
Women I-ORG
International I-ORG
in O
South B-LOC
Sudan I-LOC
have O
seen O
the O
price O
of O
wheat O
rise O
almost O
50% O
since O
the O
invasion O
began O
– O
3,000 O
miles O
away O
. O
Maize O
flour O
, O
a O
staple O
in O
South B-LOC
Sudan I-LOC
, O
has O
tripled O
in O
price O
. O
“ O
The O
market O
has O
been O
changing O
very O
rapidly O
, O
Kajokaya B-PER
said O
.” O

I O
told O
[ O
people O
] O
‘ O
You O
need O
to O
stock O
food O
in O
your O
houses O
.’ O
Kajokaya B-PER
said O
this O
jump O
in O
food O
costs O
forces O
many O
people O
to O
subsist O
on O
just O
one O
meal O
a O
day O
. O
But O
inflation O
is O
also O
hurting O
people O
outside O
the O
market O
. O
“ O
What O
people O
felt O
most O
immediately O
was O
the O
cost O
of O
fuel O
because O
it O
was O
reflected O
in O
transport O
. O
Costs O
of O
fuel O
quadrupled O
and O
transport O
between O
cities O
doubled O
in O
some O
instances O
. O

For O
some O
families O
, O
the O
rising O
cost O
of O
living O
means O
they O
can O
no O
longer O
afford O
to O
send O
their O
children O
to O
school O
and O
in O
some O
cases O
, O
not O
even O
afford O
lifesaving O
treatment O
. O
Kajokaya B-PER
said O
that O
malaria O
treatment O
costs O
about O
$10 O
, O
but O
“ O
for O
somebody O
who O
makes O
less O
than O
$1 O
a O
day O
, O
it O
can O
be O
really O
tough O
. O
“ O
We O
see O
lives O
that O
could O
have O
been O
saved O
, O
just O
perishing O
simply O
because O
people O
can’t O
afford O
to O
buy O
medication O
. O
Climate O
The O
cost O
of O
war O
is O
also O
felt O
in O
countries O
like O
Somalia B-LOC
where O
a O
large O
portion O
of O
wheat O
comes O
from O
Russia B-LOC
and O
Ukraine B-LOC
. O
But O
climate O
change O
is O
another O
key O
factor O
that O
has O
the O
Horn B-LOC
of I-LOC
Africa I-LOC
on O
the O
verge O
of O
famine O
. O

Somalia B-LOC
has O
suffered O
four O
consecutive O
failed O
rainy O
seasons O
and O
there’s O
not O
much O
hope O
that O
the O
upcoming O
rainy O
season O
in O
October O
will O
bring O
relief O
. O
Wafaa B-PER
Saeed I-PER
, O
UNICEF B-ORG
Somalia B-LOC
Representative O
said O
the O
drought O
they O
are O
currently O
experiencing O
is O
unprecedented O
. O
“80% O
of O
the O
country O
is O
either O
in O
extreme O
or O
severe O
drought O
,” O
Saeed B-PER
said O
. O
“I’ve O
spoken O
to O
people O
who O
have O
said O
they O
have O
never O
seen O
a O
drought O
like O
this O
in O
their O
life O
. O
UNICEF B-ORG
estimates O
there O
are O
1.5 O
million O
children O
in O
the O
country O
that O
are O
malnourished O
and O
7 O
million O
people O
that O
are O
acutely O
food O
insecure O
. O
That’s O
about O
half O
the O
country O
. O

People O
have O
nothing O
to O
feed O
on O
. O
Their O
livestock O
has O
died O
. O
They O
have O
no O
jobs O
. O
They O
cannot O
grow O
food O
and O
can’t O
buy O
food O
, O
Saeed B-PER
said O
. O
On O
top O
of O
that O
, O
inflation O
from O
the O
war O
in O
Ukraine B-LOC
has O
caused O
the O
price O
of O
food O
, O
fuel O
and O
water O
to O
increase O
dramatically O
, O
leaving O
many O
desperate O
for O
help O
. O
Saeed B-PER
said O
some O
people O
have O
walked O
nonstop O
for O
days O
on O
end O
in O
search O
of O
help O
. O
With O
the O
effects O
of O
climate O
change O
continuing O
to O
grow O
however O
, O
drought O
is O
“ O
becoming O
the O
norm O
.” O
“ O
It O
is O
not O
going O
to O
go O
away O
, O
Saeed B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
We O
have O
to O
invest O
in O
a O
longer O
term O
response O
to O
build O
the O
resilience O
of O
the O
people O
. O
Aid O
in O
water O
management O
and O
drought O
assistance O
are O
key O
factors O
in O
helping O
people O
“ O
get O
back O
to O
normal O
lives O
” O
and O
be O
able O
to O
provide O
for O
their O
futures O
. O
Covid B-MISC
More O
than O
two O
years O
into O
the O
pandemic O
, O
the O
ripple O
effects O
( O
and O
illness O
) O
are O
still O
reverberating O
around O
the O
world O
. O

It O
has O
touched O
nearly O
every O
part O
of O
daily O
life O
, O
affecting O
not O
only O
health O
and O
healthcare O
but O
also O
shipping O
, O
workforces O
and O
the O
overall O
economy O
. O
“ O
You O
can’t O
farm O
if O
you’re O
sick O
. O
You O
can’t O
process O
food O
if O
you’re O
sick O
. O

You O
can’t O
transport O
food O
if O
you’re O
sick O
. O
The O
big O
shipping O
supply O
chain O
disruptions O
messed O
up O
our O
ability O
to O
get O
access O
to O
food O
, O
” O
Marie B-PER
Clarke I-PER
from O
Women B-ORG
for O
Women I-ORG
International I-ORG
said O
. O
“ O
There O
were O
a O
lot O
of O
markets O
that O
closed O
sometimes O
because O
the O
state O
or O
the O
country O
would O
shut O
the O
market O
down O
because O
of O
a O
Covid O
rise O
or O
surge O
. O
The O
pandemic O
forced O
almost O
100 O
million O
people O
into O
poverty O
according O
to O
some O
estimates O
, O
and O
the O
amount O
of O
people O
going O
hungry O
increased O
150 O
million O
from O
2020 O
to O
2021 O
. O
While O
much O
of O
the O
world O
is O
still O
working O
its O
way O
back O
from O
the O
pandemic O
setbacks O
, O
new O
variants O
of O
Covid O
continue O
to O
disrupt O
everyday O
life O
. O
How O
to O
help O
World B-MISC
hunger I-MISC
is O
a O
big O
problem O
but O
there O
are O
small O
steps O
you O
can O
take O
to O
help O
alleviate O
the O
food O
crisis O
. O
Shop O
for O
and O
eat O
local O
foods O
, O
support O
small O
farmers O
and O
cut O
down O
on O
food O
waste O
. O

There O
are O
also O
many O
organizations O
around O
the O
world O
providing O
food O
and O
assistance O
. O
You O
can O
support O
those O
organizations O
here O
or O
by O
clicking O
on O
the O
button O
below O
. O

A O
pharmacist O
in O
McGregor B-LOC
, O
Minnesota B-LOC
, O
refused O
to O
fill O
a O
woman’s O
morning-after O
pill O
prescription O
because O
it O
violated O
his O
“beliefs,” O
a O
lawsuit O
alleges O
. O
When O
Andrea B-PER
Anderson’s I-PER
first O
contraception O
method O
failed O
in O
January O
2019 O
, O
she O
turned O
to O
ella O
, O
otherwise O
known O
as O
the O
“morning O
after O
pill” O
or O
emergency O
contraception O
, O
to O
prevent O
a O
possible O
pregnancy O
, O
the O
suit O
filed O
in O
Aitkin B-LOC
County I-LOC
, O
Minnesota B-LOC
, O
said O
. O
McGregor B-LOC
, O
Minnesota B-LOC
, O
is O
roughly O
122 O
miles O
north O
of O
Minneapolis B-LOC
. O

Anderson B-PER
got O
a O
prescription O
and O
had O
her O
doctor O
send O
it O
to O
the O
only O
pharmacy O
in O
the O
area O
at O
that O
time O
, O
the O
McGregor B-ORG
Pharmacy I-ORG
, O
according O
to O
the O
court O
document O
. O
But O
when O
she O
got O
to O
the O
pharmacy O
, O
according O
to O
the O
suit O
, O
“ O
the O
pharmacist O
on O
duty O
told O
her O
that O
he O
would O
be O
unable O
to O
fill O
her O
prescription O
because O
of O
his O
‘beliefs O
.’ O
” O
  O
George B-PER
Badeaux I-PER
, O
the O
pharmacist O
, O
told O
Anderson B-PER
that O
due O
to O
“personal O
reasons” O
he O
would O
not O
fill O
her O
prescription O
, O
the O
suit O
said O
. O
Badeaux B-PER
“did O
not O
clarify O
what O
his O
beliefs O
were O
or O
why O
they O
interfered O
with O
his O
ability O
to O
perform O
his O
job O
as O
a O
medical O
professional O
, O
according O
to O
the O
complaint O
. O
The O
pharmacy’s O
owner O
would O
later O
tell O
Anderson B-PER
that O
he O
didn’t O
“agree O
with” O
Badeaux’s O
refusal O
to O
fill O
the O
prescription O
, O
but O
that O
Badeaux B-PER
was O
a O
local O
pastor O
, O
according O
to O
the O
suit O
. O
Attorneys O
for O
Badeaux B-PER
and O
the O
pharmacy O
did O
not O
return O
CNN’s B-ORG
requests O
for O
comment O
this O
week O
. O
After O
trying O
multiple O
pharmacies O
, O
Anderson B-PER
eventually O
found O
one O
that O
would O
fill O
her O
prescription O
more O
than O
50 O
miles O
away O
from O
where O
she O
lived O
, O
as O
a O
snowstorm O
was O
headed O
toward O
central O
Minnesota B-LOC
, O
the O
suit O
said O
. O
She O
“drove O
over O
100 O
miles O
round O
trip O
in O
the O
snowstorm O
in O
order O
to O
fill O
her O
prescription O
. O
While O
the O
drive O
normally O
takes O
over O
two O
hours O
round O
trip O
, O
that O
day O
it O
took O
over O
three O
hours O
in O
light O
of O
the O
storm O
, O
” O
the O
complaint O
said O
. O
The O
complaint O
argues O
that O
Badeaux B-PER
, O
along O
with O
the O
pharmacy O
, O
violated O
Minnesota’s B-LOC
Human B-MISC
Rights I-MISC
Act I-MISC
. O
Anderson B-PER
is O
asking O
for O
punitive O
and O
monetary O
damages O
to O
be O
determined O
by O
a O
jury O
. O

Jury O
selection O
began O
August O
1 O
, O
according O
to O
a O
court O
docket O
. O

After O
the O
US B-ORG
Supreme I-ORG
Court I-ORG
overturned O
Roe B-MISC
v. O
Wade B-MISC
on O
June O
24 O
2022 O
, O
reproductive O
rights O
activists O
across O
the O
country O
have O
questioned O
whether O
contraceptive O
measures O
may O
be O
threatened O
, O
especially O
after O
Justice B-PER
Clarence I-PER
Thomas I-PER
wrote O
that O
a O
ruling O
on O
that O
right O
– O
among O
others O
– O
should O
be O
revisited O
. O
The O
House B-ORG
voted O
228-195 O
on O
July O
21 O
to O
pass O
a O
bill O
that O
would O
guarantee O
access O
to O
contraception O
by O
protecting O
the O
right O
to O
buy O
and O
use O
contraceptives O
without O
government O
restriction O
. O
It O
is O
unclear O
whether O
the O
bill O
can O
pass O
the O
Senate B-ORG
where O
at O
least O
10 O
Republicans B-MISC
are O
needed O
to O
side O
with O
Democrats B-MISC
to O
overcome O
the O
filibuster’s O
60-vote O
threshold O
. O
Correction O
: O
This O
story O
has O
been O
updated O
to O
make O
clear O
the O
defendant O
pharmacy’s O
name O
. O

The O
story O
also O
misspelled O
the O
name O
of O
the O
county O
where O
the O
pharmacy O
is O
located O
. O
It O
is O
in O
Aitkin B-LOC
County I-LOC
. O

بايدن B-PER
عن O
قتل O
4 O
مسلمين O
في O
"عمليات O
مستهدفة":" O
لا O
مكان O
لجرائم O
الكراهية O
في O
أمريكا B-LOC
- O
CNN B-ORG
Arabic I-ORG

China’s B-LOC
threat O
to O
Taiwan B-LOC
is O
“more O
serious O
than O
ever,” O
but O
the O
island O
will O
stand O
firm O
to O
protect O
its O
freedom O
and O
democracy O
– O
including O
by O
welcoming O
those O
who O
support O
it, O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
Foreign O
Minister O
Joseph B-PER
Wu I-PER
told O
CNN B-ORG
in O
an O
interview O
Monday. O
Wu’s B-PER
defiant O
message O
came O
as O
China B-LOC
said O
it O
continued O
military O
drills O
around O
the O
self-governing O
island, O
after O
a O
four-day O
show O
of O
force O
following O
US B-ORG
House O
Speaker O
Nancy B-PER
Pelosi’s I-PER
trip O
to O
Taipei B-LOC
last O
week. O
“China B-LOC
has O
always O
been O
threatening O
Taiwan B-LOC
for O
years O
and O
it’s O
getting O
more O
serious O
in O
the O
last O
few O
years,” O
Wu B-PER
said. O
“Whether O
Speaker O
Pelosi B-PER
visits O
Taiwan B-LOC
or O
not, O
the O
Chinese B-MISC
military O
threat O
against O
Taiwan B-LOC
has O
always O
been O
there O
and O
that O
is O
the O
fact O
that O
we O
need O
to O
deal O
with.” O
Welcoming O
overseas O
friends O
to O
the O
island O
was O
a O
key O
part O
of O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
strategy O
to O
counter O
China’s B-LOC
attempts O
to O
isolate O
it O
from O
the O
international O
community O
– O
regardless O
of O
the O
potential O
backlash O
from O
Beijing, B-LOC
Wu B-PER
said. O
“(China) B-LOC
cannot O
dictate O
to O
Taiwan B-LOC
that O
we O
should O
not O
welcome O
anyone O
who O
likes O
to O
come O
and O
show O
support O
for O
Taiwan,” O
said O
Wu, B-PER
who O
has O
served O
as O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
foreign O
minister O
since O
2018. O
Pelosi’s B-PER
Taiwan B-LOC
trip O
– O
the O
first O
by O
a O
sitting O
House O
Speaker O
to O
the O
island O
in O
25 O
years O
– O
was O
vehemently O
opposed O
by O
China’s B-LOC
ruling O
Communist O
Party, O
which O
views O
Taiwan B-LOC
as O
its O
territory O
despite O
never O
having O
controlled O
it. O
In O
the O
wake O
of O
Pelosi’s B-PER
visit, O
Beijing B-LOC
has O
ramped O
up O
pressure O
on O
Taiwan, B-LOC
including O
via O
economic O
penalties, O
the O
launch O
of O
missiles O
over O
the O
island O
for O
the O
first O
time, O
and O
drills O
that O
Taipei B-LOC
has O
said O
were O
meant O
to O
“simulate” O
an O
attack O
against O
its O
main O
island O
and O
navy. O
Though O
those O
exercises O
were O
originally O
expected O
to O
end O
Sunday, O
drills O
around O
Taiwan B-LOC
continued O
Monday, O
according O
to O
an O
announcement O
from O
China’s B-LOC
military. O
But O
as O
the O
live-fire O
drills O
raised O
global O
fears O
of O
a O
possible O
military O
conflict, O
the O
mood O
in O
Taiwan B-LOC
remained O
calm, O
with O
life O
carrying O
on O
as O
usual O
with O
packed O
restaurants O
and O
crowded O
public O
transport. O
For O
Wu, B-PER
the O
threat O
made O
it O
even O
more O
critical O
that O
Taiwan B-LOC
continue O
to O
build O
its O
international O
relationships O
and O
show O
it O
is O
not O
afraid. O

I O
worry O
that O
China B-LOC
may O
really O
launch O
a O
war O
against O
Taiwan B-LOC
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
“ O
But O
what O
it O
is O
doing O
right O
now O
is O
trying O
to O
scare O
us O
and O
the O
best O
way O
to O
deal O
with O
it O
( O
is O
) O
to O
show O
to O
China B-LOC
that O
we O
are O
not O
scared O
.” O
Pelosi B-PER
in O
Taiwan B-LOC
Though O
her O
trip O
was O
long O
mooted O
and O
much O
discussed O
, O
Taiwanese B-MISC
officials O
only O
received O
short O
notice O
of O
her O
arrival O
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
Since O
her O
travel O
is O
always O
subject O
to O
a O
lot O
of O
considerations O
, O
especially O
security O
considerations O
… O
we O
were O
not O
able O
to O
find O
out O
until O
the O
very O
last O
moment O
when O
she O
firmed O
up O
her O
plan O
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
Taipei B-LOC
knew O
the O
itinerary O
a O
few O
days O
beforehand O
, O
but O
not O
the O
exact O
timing O
of O
her O
arrival O
. O
The O
visit O
from O
the O
speaker O
and O
an O
accompanying O
congressional O
delegation O
included O
meetings O
at O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
legislature O
and O
the O
office O
of O
Taiwanese B-MISC
President O
Tsai B-PER
Ing-wen I-PER
, O
where O
Pelosi B-PER
said O
they O
came O
to O
send O
an O
“ O
unequivocal O
message O
” O
that O
“ O
America B-LOC
stands O
with O
Taiwan B-LOC
.” O
Wu B-PER
said O
his O
most O
memorable O
impression O
of O
the O
trip O
was O
greeting O
Pelosi B-PER
and O
the O
delegation O
at O
the O
airport O
, O
where O
she O
“ O
showed O
her O
charm O
” O
by O
saying O
she’d O
been O
looking O
forward O
to O
her O
visit O
for O
a O
long O
time O
. O
“ O
And O
by O
the O
time O
she O
departed O
, O
she O
not O
only O
said O
goodbye O
to O
me O
, O
but O
also O
said O
goodbye O
to O
the O
ground O
crew O
, O
the O
security O
people O
, O
and O
to O
those O
people O
who O
had O
been O
taking O
care O
of O
the O
airport O
, O
one O
by O
one O
, O
” O
Wu B-PER
said O
. O
When O
asked O
whether O
the O
United B-ORG
States I-ORG
would O
increase O
its O
support O
for O
Taiwan B-LOC
after O
the O
visit O
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
the O
US B-ORG
has O
always O
been O
“ O
highly O
supportive O
” O
of O
Taiwan B-LOC
– O
but O
the O
current O
support O
was O
“ O
unprecedented O
.” O
In O
an O
exclusive O
interview O
with O
CNN B-ORG
last O
October O
, O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
President O
Tsai B-PER
Ing-wen I-PER
confirmed O
some O
US B-ORG
military O
trainers O
were O
in O
Taiwan B-LOC
– O
the O
first O
time O
a O
Taiwanese B-MISC
leader O
had O
admitted O
to O
their O
presence O
since O
Washington B-LOC
and O
Taipei B-LOC
severed O
diplomatic O
ties O
in O
1979 O
. O
But O
perceptions O
of O
American B-MISC
support O
sparked O
Beijing’s B-LOC
ire O
against O
the O
speaker’s O
visit O
, O
with O
China’s B-LOC
foreign O
ministry O
issuing O
a O
statement O
on O
the O
heels O
of O
Pelosi’s B-PER
arrival O
Tuesday O
evening O
saying O
her O
trip O
would O
have O
a O
“ O
severe O
impact O
on O
the O
political O
foundation O
of O
China-US B-MISC
relations O
, O
” O
and O
“ O
gravely O
undermines O
peace O
and O
stability O
across O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
.” O
Beijing B-LOC
announced O
the O
large-scale O
military O
exercises O
in O
what O
it O
said O
were O
six O
zones O
around O
the O
island O
of O
Taiwan B-LOC
swiftly O
after O
Pelosi’s B-PER
arrival O
, O
in O
response O
to O
what O
it O
viewed O
as O
an O
infringement O
of O
China’s B-LOC
“ O
sovereignty O
and O
territorial O
integrity O
.” O
While O
the O
US B-ORG
and O
many O
of O
its O
allies O
have O
decried O
the O
drills O
, O
China B-LOC
defended O
its O
actions O
as O
“ O
legitimate O

and O
justified O
,” O
saying O
it O
was O
the O
US B-ORG
, O
not O
China B-LOC
, O
who O
was O
“ O
the O
biggest O
saboteur O
and O
destabilizer O
of O
peace O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
, O
where O
China B-LOC
claims O
“ O
sovereign O
rights O
and O
jurisdiction O
. O
‘Wrecking’ O
the O
status O
quo O
Taiwan B-LOC
and O
China B-LOC
have O
been O
governed O
separately O
since O
the O
end O
of O
a O
civil O
war O
more O
than O
seven O
decades O
ago O
, O
in O
which O
the O
defeated O
Nationalists B-PER
fled O
to O
Taipei B-LOC
. O
Taiwan B-LOC
transitioned O
from O
authoritarian O
rule O
to O
a O
democracy O
in O
the O
1990s O
, O
and O
is O
now O
ranked O
one O
of O
the O
freest O
jurisdictions O
in O
Asia B-LOC
by O
Freedom B-ORG
House I-ORG
, O
a O
US-based O
non-profit O
organization O
. O

In O
recent O
years O
, O
as O
his O
power O
has O
grown O
, O
Chinese B-MISC
leader O
Xi B-PER
Jinping I-PER
has O
made O
clear O
his O
ambitions O
to O
“reunify” O
with O
the O
island O
– O
by O
force O
if O
necessary O
. O
Wu B-PER
accused O
China B-LOC
of O
trying O
to O
change O
the O
status O
quo O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
, O
including O
by O
conducting O
military O
exercises O
in O
recent O
days O
across O
the O
median O
line O
– O
the O
halfway O
point O
between O
the O
island O
and O
mainland O
China B-LOC
that O
has O
previously O
been O
an O
informal O
but O
largely O
respected O
border O
of O
control O
between O
Beijing B-LOC
and O
Taipei B-LOC
. O
Dozens O
of O
Chinese B-MISC
warplanes O
crossed O
the O
median O
line O
between O
Thursday O
and O
Sunday O
, O
according O
to O
accounts O
from O
Taiwan’s B-LOC
Defense B-ORG
Ministry I-ORG
. O
While O
the O
informal O
median O
line O
has O
largely O
preserved O
peace O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
for O
decades O
, O
China B-LOC
now O
openly O
denies O
its O
existence O
. O
“This O
kind O
of O
behavior O
is O
wrecking O
the O
status O
quo O
, O
and O
it’s O
wrecking O
peace O
and O
stability O
in O
this O
region O
and O
it O
should O
not O
be O
accepted O
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
, O
adding O
that O
China B-LOC
had O
sought O
to O
declare O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
as O
its O
internal O
waters O
for O
“some O
time” O
before O
Pelosi’s B-PER
visit O
. O
That O
had O
implications O
beyond O
Taiwan B-LOC
as O
China B-LOC
seeks O
to O
expand O
its O
influence O
across O
the O
Western B-MISC
Pacific I-MISC
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
. O

But O
he O
added O
that O
he O
remained O
optimistic O
about O
the O
future O

Democracy O
is O
going O
to O
prevail O
, O
he O
said O
. O
“ O
If O
you O
look O
at O
authoritarianism O
, O
it’s O
not O
resilient O
. O
” O

It O
may O
appear O
strong O
, O
and O
it O
may O
appear O
to O
be O
expanding O
. O

But O
it’s O
not O
resilient O
and O
at O
some O
point O
is O
going O
to O
break O
.” O
When O
asked O
if O
the O
situation O
could O
be O
called O
a O
crisis O
, O
Wu B-PER
said O
that O
was O
ultimately O
up O
to O
Beijing B-LOC
. O
“ O
It O
depends O
on O
the O
will O
of O
the O
Chinese B-MISC
leaders O
to O
see O
whether O
they O
want O
to O
pursue O
the O
relations O
with O
Taiwan B-LOC
… O
in O
a O
peaceful O
and O
stable O
manner O
. O
” O
Wu B-PER
said O
he O
doesn’t O
know O
whether O
Chinese B-MISC
leaders O
“ O
have O
made O
up O
their O
mind O
” O
to O
use O
force O
to O
take O
Taiwan B-LOC
, O
but O
Taiwanese B-MISC
officials O
were O
“ O
looking O
at O
several O
different O
scenarios O
, O
” O
in O
particular O
due O
to O
concerns O
that O
Beijing B-LOC
could O
seek O
to O
divert O
attention O
from O
domestic O
problems O
by O
creating O
a O
crisis O
in O
the O
Taiwan B-LOC
Strait I-LOC
. O
“ O
The O
important O
thing O
for O
us O
is O
that O
we O
need O
to O
be O
prepared O
, O
” O
Wu B-PER
said O
. O

We O
want O
to O
defend O
the O
freedom O
and O
democracy O
that O
we O
enjoy O
over O
here O
. O
Nobody O
can O
take O
that O
away O
from O
us O
. O

Alyssa B-PER
Alhadeff I-PER
would O
be O
in O
her O
second O
year O
of O
college O
if O
she O
hadn’t O
been O
murdered O
in O
a O
2018 O
mass O
shooting O
at O
her O
Parkland B-LOC
, O
Florida B-LOC
, O
high O
school O
– O
and O
her O
father O
would O
be O
looking O
forward O
to O
watching O
her O
achieve O
her O
dreams O
. O
“ O
Soon O
she’d O
go O
on O
to O
be O
a O
professional O
soccer O
player O
. O
She’d O
get O
her O
law O
degree O
, O
and O
maybe O
become O
one O
of O
the O
most O
successful O
business O
negotiation O
lawyers O
the O
world O
would O
see O
, O
” O
Ilan B-PER
Alhadeff I-PER
told O
a O
Broward B-LOC
County I-LOC
courtroom O
Tuesday O
, O
testifying O
in O
the O
death O
penalty O
trial O
of O
his O
daughter’s O
killer O
. O
“ O
She O
was O
supposed O
to O
get O
married O
, O
and O
I O
was O
going O
to O
have O
my O
father-daughter O
dance O
, O
” O
he O
said O
, O
his O
voice O
breaking O
. O

She O
would O
have O
had O
a O
beautiful O
family O
, O
four O
kids O
, O
live O
in O
a O
gorgeous O
house O
– O
a O
beach O
house O
on O
the O
side O
. O

All O
those O
plans O
came O
to O
an O
end O
with O
Alyssa’s O
murder O
,” O
he O
said O
. O
Families O
of O
the O
17 O
people O
killed O
in O
the O
Parkland B-LOC
school O
shooting O
continued O
taking O
the O
stand O
Tuesday O
, O
offering O
victim O
impact O
statements O
to O
illustrate O
the O
toll O
the O
murders O
have O
taken O
as O
a O
jury O
decides O
whether O
to O
sentence O
the O
shooter O
, O
Nikolas B-PER
Cruz I-PER
, O
to O
death O
. O
The O
hearing O
was O
emotional O
, O
as O
parents O
of O
some O
of O
the O
14 O
students O
killed O
described O
not O
only O
who O
their O
children O
were O
, O
but O
who O
they O
will O
never O
get O
to O
become O
– O
a O
catalog O
of O
things O
left O
undone O
and O
unsaid O
. O
Cruz B-PER
, O
now O
23 O
, O
pleaded O
guilty O
in O
October O
to O
17 O
counts O
of O
murder O
and O
17 O
counts O
of O
attempted O
murder O
, O
and O
this O
phase O
of O
his O
criminal O
trial O
aims O
to O
determine O
his O
sentence O
: O
Prosecutors O
are O
seeking O
the O
death O
penalty O
, O
while O
Cruz’s O
defense O
attorneys O
are O
asking O
the O
jury O
for O
a O
sentence O
of O
life O
in O
prison O
without O
the O
possibility O
of O
parole O
. O
To O
recommend O
a O
death O
sentence O
, O
jurors O
must O
be O
unanimous O
. O
If O
they O
do O
so O
, O
the O
judge O
could O
choose O
to O
follow O
the O
recommendation O
or O
sentence O
Cruz B-PER
to O
life O
instead O
. O
To O
make O
their O
decision O
, O
jurors O
will O
hear O
prosecutors O
and O
defense O
attorneys O
argue O
aggravating O
factors O
and O
mitigating O
circumstances O
– O
reasons O
Cruz B-PER
should O
or O
should O
not O
be O
executed O
. O
Victim B-MISC
impact I-MISC
statements I-MISC
add O
another O
layer O
, O
giving O
the O
families O
and O
friends O
of O
the O
victims O
their O
own O
day O
in O
court O
, O
though O
the O
judge O
told O
the O
jury O
the O
statements O
are O
not O
meant O
to O
be O
weighed O
as O
aggravating O
factors O
. O
“ O
We O
were O
a O
family O
unit O
of O
five O
always O
trying O
to O
fit O
into O
a O
world O
set O
up O
for O
even O
numbers O
, O
said O
Tom B-PER
Hoyer I-PER
, O
whose O
15-year-old O
son O
Luke B-PER
– O
the O
youngest O
of O
three O
– O
was O
killed O
. O
“ O
Two- O
four- O
six-seat O
tables O
in O
a O
restaurant O
. O

Two- O
four- O
six-ticket O
packages O
to O
events O
. O
Things O
like O
that O
.” O
But O
the O
Hoyers B-PER
are O
no O
longer O
a O
family O
of O
five O
, O
and O
“never O
again O
will O
the O
world O
feel O
right O
, O
now O
that O
we’re O
a O
family O
of O
four O
, O
” O
Hoyer B-PER
said O
. O
“When O
Luke B-PER
died O
something O
went O
missing O
in O
me O
, O
” O
he O
said O
. O
“And O
I’ll O
never O
, O
never O
get O
over O
that O
feeling O
. O
‘I O
will O
never O
get O
over O
it O
’ O
Nicholas B-PER
Dworet I-PER
, O
captain O
of O
the O
high O
school’s O
swim O
team O
, O
had O
just O
received O
a O
scholarship O
to O
the B-ORG
University I-ORG
of I-ORG
Indianapolis I-ORG
at O
the O
time O
he O
was O
killed O
, O
his O
mother O
, O
Annika B-PER
Dworet I-PER
, O
testified O
Tuesday O
. O
He O
wanted O
to O
study O
finance O
and O
move O
to O
Boston B-LOC
with O
his O
girlfriend O
. O

“ O
Nick B-PER
had O
big O
goals O
– O
bigger O
than O
most O
of O
us O
dare O
to O
dream O
of O
,” O
she O
said O
. O
“ O

Next O
to O
his O
bed O
, O
he’d O
taped O
a O
note O
which O
read O
, O
“ O
I O
want O
to O
become O
a O
Swedish B-MISC
Olympian I-MISC
and O
go O
to O
Tokyo B-LOC
2020 O
to O
compete O
for O
my O
country O
. O
I O
will O
give O
all O
I O
have O
in O
my O
body O
and O
my O
mind O
to O
achieve O
the O
goals O
I O
have O
set O
. O
“ O
Now O
, O
Annika B-PER
Dworet I-PER
said O
, O
“ O
we O
will O
never O
know O
if O
he O
would O
have O
reached O
his O
goal O
to O
go O
to O
the O
Olympics B-MISC
. O
” O
  O
Jennifer B-PER
Guttenberg I-PER
, O
mother O
of O
14-year-old O
Jaime B-PER
, O
told O
the O
court O
watching O
her O
daughter’s O
friends O
and O
classmates O
grow O
up O
and O
achieve O
things O
Jaime B-PER
never O
will O
is O
“ O
excruciatingly O
difficult O
.” O
Family O
get-togethers O
and O
holidays O
are O
hard O
, O
too O
, O
with O
one O
less O
seat O
at O
the O
table O
and O
no O
Jaime B-PER
to O
keep O
“ O
everyone O
upbeat O
and O
laughing O
.” O
“ O
There O
is O
togetherness O
, O
but O
there O
is O
no O
celebrating O
,” O
Guttenberg B-PER
said O
. O
“ O
There O
is O
a O
deafening O
silence O
amongst O
everyone O
, O
as O
they O
don’t O
want O
to O
bring O
up O
Jaime’s O
name O
to O
cause O
pain O
, O
but O
don’t O
want O
to O
forget O
her O
, O
either O
.” O
The O
last O
four O
years O
have O
been O
no O
less O
painful O
for O
Linda B-PER
Beigel I-PER
Schulman I-PER
, O
who O
told O
the O
court O
Monday O
it O
had O
been O
1,630 O
days O
since O
she O
spoke O
to O
her O
son O
Scott B-PER
Beigel I-PER
, O
a O
geography O
teacher O
killed O
as O
he O
ushered O
students O
to O
safety O
in O
his O
classroom O
. O
“ O
I O
will O
never O
get O
over O
it O
. O

I O
will O
never O
get O
past O
it O
,” O
she O
said O
Monday O
. O
“ O
My O
life O
will O
never O
, O
ever O
be O
the O
same O
. O
‘Our O
lives O
have O
been O
shattered O
’ O
Cruz B-PER
had O
no O
visible O
reaction O
Monday O
to O
any O
of O
the O
victim O
impact O
statements O
, O
though O
one O
of O
his O
defense O
attorneys O
was O
seen O
wiping O
away O
a O
tear O
, O
as O
were O
at O
least O
two O
members O
of O
the O
jury O
. O
“ O
It’s O
been O
four O
years O
and O
four O
months O
since O
he O
was O
taken O
from O
us O
, O
his O
friends O
and O
his O
family O
, O
Patricia B-PER
Oliver I-PER
said O
of O
her O
son O
, O
who O
was O
17 O
when O
he O
was O
killed O
. O
“ O
We O
miss O
him O
more O
than O
words O
can O
say O
and O
love O
him O
dearly O
, O
she O
said O
, O
adding O
, O
“Our O
lives O
have O
been O
shattered O
and O
changed O
forever O
. O
” O
Joaquin’s B-PER
sister O
, O
Andrea B-PER
Ghersi I-PER
, O
said O
her O
6-foot-1 O
baby O
brother O
was O
“energetic O
, O
vibrant O
, O
loud O
, O
confident O
, O
strong O
, O
empathetic O
, O
understanding O
, O
smart O
, O
passionate O
, O
outgoing O
, O
playful O
, O
loving O
, O
competitive O
, O
rebellious O
, O
funny O
, O
loyal O
and O
constantly O
spoke O
up O
when O
he O
felt O
something O
was O
not O
just O
. O
Victoria B-PER
Gonzalez I-PER
also O
took O
the O
stand O
Tuesday O
. O
The O
day O
of O
the O
shooting O
, O
she O
became O
Joaquin’s B-PER
girlfriend O
, O
Gonzalez B-PER
told O
the O
court O
, O
but O
they O
already O
referred O
to O
each O
other O
as O
“always O
soul O
mates O
, O
and O
she O
described O
him O
as O
“magic O
personified O
, O
love O
personified O
.” O
His O
name O
, O
she O
said O
, O
is O
“etched O
into O
the O
depth O
of O
my O
soul O
. O
Gena B-PER
Hoyer I-PER
, O
mother O
of O
Luke B-PER
Hoyer I-PER
, O
said O
her O
15-year-old O
son’s O
room O
remains O
the O
same O
. O
His O
glasses O
and O
charger O
are O
still O
on O
the O
nightstand O
and O
his O
clothes O
go O
untouched O
, O
she O
testified O
. O

She O
becomes O
physically O
ill O
when O
she O
moves O
anything O
in O
the O
room O
, O
she O
said O
. O
Meadow B-PER
Pollack I-PER
’s O
mother O
, O
Shara B-PER
Kaplan I-PER
, O
told O
the O
jurors O
to O
articulate O
how O
her O
daughter O
’s O
death O
affected O
her O
she O
would O
have O
to O
rip O
out O
her O
heart O
and O
show O
them O
it O
’s O
been O
shattered O
in O
a O
million O
pieces O
. O
“ O
(Meadow O
’s O
death) O
has O
destroyed O
my O
life O
and O
my O
capability O
of O
ever O
living O
a O
productive O
existence O
, O
” O
she O
said O
of O
her O
daughter O
. O
“ O
I O
am O
heartbroken O
that O
I O
won’t O
be O
able O
to O
watch O
her O
become O
the O
amazing O
young O
woman O
she O
was O
turning O
into O
. O
Alaina B-PER
’s O
sister O
Meghan B-PER
echoed O
the O
sentiment O
, O
telling O
the O
court O
, O
“ O
I O
would O
have O
loved O
to O
see O
her O
grow O
up O
. O

She O
would O
have O
been O
a O
blessing O
to O
the O
world O
.” O
CNN’s B-ORG
Carlos B-PER
Suarez I-PER
, O
Kevin B-PER
Conlon I-PER
and O
Denise B-PER
Royal I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O

Democrats’ B-MISC
push O
to O
advance O
their O
energy O
and O
health O
care O
bill O
is O
likely O
headed O
for O
a O
procedural O
speed O
bump O
known O
in O
Washington B-LOC
as O
a O
“vote-a-rama.” O
The O
time-consuming O
and O
stamina-challenging O
process O
is O
among O
the O
final O
obstacles O
for O
Democrats, B-MISC
along O
with O
the O
Senate B-ORG
parliamentarian’s O
review O
of O
the O
package. O
Politically, O
a O
vote-a-rama O
gives O
Republicans B-ORG
a O
chance O
to O
sow O
discord O
and O
create O
distractions O
as O
they O
force O
Democrats B-MISC
to O
vote O
on O
controversial O
issues. O
But, O
once O
it’s O
over, O
Democrats B-MISC
have O
the O
opportunity O
to O
advance O
their O
package O
on O
a O
straight O
party-line O
vote O
that O
would O
not O
be O
subject O
to O
the O
filibuster’s O
60-vote O
threshold. O
Here’s O
what O
you O
need O
to O
know: O
What O
is O
a O
vote-a-rama? O
Usually O
in O
the O
legislative O
process, O
lawmakers O
can O
use O
a O
series O
of O
procedural O
maneuvers O
to O
avoid O
voting O
on O
amendments. O
But O
in O
a O
budget O
reconciliation O
process O
– O
which O
Democrats B-MISC
are O
using O
to O
advance O
their O
bill O
– O
you O
can’t O
do O
that. O
Lawmakers O
cannot O
hold O
a O
final O
vote O
on O
a O
reconciliation O
bill O
until O
all O
the O
amendments O
have O
been O
“disposed O
of,” O
or O
in O
simpler O
terms, O
“voted O
on.” O
The O
practice O
involves O
votes O
on O
a O
series O
of O
amendments O
that O
can O
– O
and O
usually O
do O
– O
stretch O
for O
hours. O
How O
do O
lawmakers O
use O
the O
process? O

The O
party O
in O
charge O
typically O
wants O
to O
move O
this O
vote-a-rama O
along O
as O
quickly O
as O
possible O
with O
as O
few O
votes O
as O
possible O
. O
The O
minority O
party O
takes O
the O
opportunity O
to O
force O
votes O
on O
all O
kinds O
of O
measures O
they O
don’t O
typically O
have O
the O
power O
to O
put O
on O
the O
floor O
. O
How O
long O
does O
each O
vote O
take O
? O

Usually O
, O
lawmakers O
agree O
to O
a O
process O
that O
looks O
a O
lot O
like O
this O
. O
Each O
amendment O
takes O
about O
15 O
minutes O
or O
so O
to O
get O
through O
. O
The O
process O
moves O
quickly O
by O
Senate B-ORG
standards O
, O
which O
is O
why O
it O
is O
so O
important O
for O
members O
to O
basically O
stay O
in O
or O
close O
by O
the O
chamber O
for O
the O
entire O
marathon O
event O
. O

What’s O
in O
the O
bill O
? O

The O
bill O
contains O
a O
number O
of O
Democrats’ O
goals O
, O
including O
some O
provisions O
that O
party O
leaders O
have O
worked O
toward O
for O
years O
: O
Still O
, O
this O
isn’t O
Build O
Back O
Better O
2.0 O
. O
The O
package O
is O
less O
than O
half O
the O
size O
of O
Biden’s B-PER
original O
social O
safety O
net O
plan O
, O
and O
a O
number O
of O
key O
Democratic O
priorities O
are O
likely O
to O
be O
left O
out O
. O
CNN’s B-ORG
Tami B-PER
Luhby I-PER
and O
Katie B-PER
Lobosco I-PER
contributed O
to O
this O
report O
. O
